<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'
      xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'
      xml:base='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/ongoing.atom'
      xml:lang='en-us'>
 <title>ongoing by Tim Bray</title>
 <link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/</id>
 <link href='./' />
 <link rel='self' href='' />
 <link rel='replies'       thr:count='101'       href='/home/tbray.org/www/html/ongoing/comments.atom' />
 <logo>rsslogo.jpg</logo>
 <icon>/favicon.ico</icon>
 <updated>2010-06-22T07:22:02-07:00</updated>
 <author><name>Tim Bray</name></author>
 <subtitle>ongoing fragmented essay by Tim Bray</subtitle>
 <rights>All content written by Tim Bray and photos by Tim Bray Copyright Tim Bray, some rights reserved, see /ongoing/misc/Copyright</rights>
 <generator uri='/misc/Colophon'>Generated from XML source code using Perl, Expat, Emacs, Mysql, Ruby, Java, and ImageMagick.  Industrial-strength technology, baby.</generator>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/20/'>
 <title>Unfinished, With Clouds</title>
 <link href='Unfinished' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='2'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Unfinished#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/20/Unfinished</id>
 <published>2010-06-20T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-20T20:50:59-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Vancouver' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Vancouver' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>What happened was, we went to a party at Shane and Ally&#x2019;s place on East First Ave at a mixed residential-commercial development with a common rooftop garden.  We barbecued up there, sharing the space amicably with a couple of other parties.  The view was compelling and the clouds were interesting.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>What happened was, we went to a party at Shane and Ally’s place on East First Ave at a mixed
residential-commercial development with a common rooftop garden.  We barbecued
up there, sharing the space amicably with a couple of other parties.  The view
was compelling and the clouds were interesting.</p>
<p>This is looking West from more or less
<a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=366+east+1st+ave,+vancouver+bc&amp;sll=49.268043,-123.096925&amp;sspn=0.003731,0.009023&amp;g=Richmond,+Greater+Vancouver+Regional+District,+British+Columbia,+Canada&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=&amp;hnear=366+1+Ave+E,+Vancouver,+Greater+Vancouver+Regional+District,+British+Columbia+V5T+1A7,+Canada&amp;ll=49.269149,-123.10421&amp;spn=0.119403,0.288734&amp;t=h&amp;z=12">here</a>.</p>
<img src="PS089492.png" alt="Clouds, looking west from central Vancouver" />
<p>Notice that in the foreground there’s quite a bit of low-rise low-rent
industrial land; every city needs to earn its living and to have cheap
neighborhoods, but the density doesn’t feel right.</p>
<p>Doug Coupland (I believe it was in
<a href="http://www.coupland.com/2009/02/28/template-book-3/">City of
Glass</a>) said “In 100 years, Paris will still be Paris and New York will
still be New York.  What will Vancouver be?”  He had a point, and the point is
that Vancouver is profoundly unfinished; we’re making it up as we go
along. Let me underline the point by turning the camera northeast.</p>
<img src="PS089497.png" alt="Vacant space in central Vancouver" />
<p>In one of these vacant spaces (not shown here) there was some sort of
squatter thing happening, with a nice semi-modern Greyhound-style bus
apparently parked permanently with lawn chairs, sort of a one-inhabitant trailer park.</p>
<p>Bear in mind that this is all within spitting distance of some of the most
expensive neighborhoods in one of the world’s most expensive real-state
markets; bubble-icious say some.</p>
<p>But then the clouds kept pulling the front of the camera back to the
west.</p>
<img src="PS089499.png" alt="Looking west at sunset from central Vancouver" />
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/20/'>
 <title>Day Ten</title>
 <link href='World-Cup-Day-10' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='4'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='World-Cup-Day-10#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/20/World-Cup-Day-10</id>
 <published>2010-06-20T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-20T14:25:06-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports/Soccer/World Cup 2010' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Soccer' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='World Cup 2010' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Well, my job and my life have interfered heavily with your authoritative Web Geek&#x2019;s <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020'>World Cup 2010</a> coverage.  And&#xa0;&#x2014;&#xa0;let&#x2019;s get this out of the way&#xa0;&#x2014;&#xa0;my predictions as to which matches were going to be fun and how the groups would play out have been almost entirely wrong.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Well, my job and my life have interfered heavily with your authoritative
Web Geek’s <a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020">World Cup
2010</a> coverage.  And — let’s get this out of the way — my predictions as to
which matches were going to be fun and how the groups would play out have been
almost entirely wrong.</p>
<p>In fact, the only games I watched end-to-end were Argentina-South Korea on
Day Seven, and Brazil-Côte d'Ivoire just now, until I switched off at Brazil’s
third; too depressing for this
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Côte_d%27Ivoire_national_football_team">Elephants</a>
fan.  So rather than games, just some impressions and notes as we approach
two-thirds of the way through the round-robin.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Disappointed</h2>
<p>In the quality of play in general.  With the notable exception of Argentina
I haven’t seen any team really show seriously hot stuff for more than a few
minutes of a match against a first-rank opponent.</p>
<p>Just now, I caught a bit of Brazil-Côte d'Ivoire post-game and the
commentator remarked on having seen ten or fifteen minutes of “real Brazilian
football.”  No.  Your <em>real</em> game is the one you play for most of the
match, innit?</p>
<p>In particular, I’m shocked by the big-name teams apparently concluding they don’t
need their “A” game against non-marquee opponents; as in Spain against
Switzerland or Germany against Serbia.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Disappointed</h2>
<p>In the refereeing.  It seems like every game I watch has
egregiously-botched calls, sendings-off that are travesties, flagrant
hand-balls in the penalty zone missed, innocent tacklers punished and guilty
divers rewarded.  I assume they send the best, so we’re watching either a run
of bad luck or a profession in bad shape.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Disappointed</h2>
<p>In the ethics of the players.  This is the <em>fucking World Cup</em>, what’s with
the grabbing and clutching and above all the diving?  I eventually gave up
watching the Tour de France when I realized I had no respect for any of the
chemically-enhanced performers; I’d hate to walk away from soccer, but this is
starting to get seriously up my nose.  I say give all the referee’s assistants
the power to issue an instant red card for diving, with a presumption of guilt.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>Disappointed</h2>
<p>In African soccer.  The traditional story is that the African teams run at
opponents and terrify defenders and then lose when it matters because they
don’t have the defensive precision. This year’s been like that only without
much attack, either.  Next time, right?</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>Impressed</h2>
<p>By the play of the Latin-American teams.  Yes, every other commentator has
highlighted this too, but good heavens.  The odds of the Cup staying in the
Northern Hemisphere seem increasingly long.  Even Mexico and Paraguay have
looked stronger than supposed powers like France and Italy.  Which is fine by
me; European soccer, even when it’s played well (as by Germany, this time
around) is boring.</p>
<h2 id='p-7'>Impressed</h2>
<p>By Argentina.  The clear standouts in the round-robin play.  Also, they
play with a little more courage and less diving than the World-Cup norm.</p>
<p>But here’s the thing; the round-robin results become instantly meaningless
when it ends.  Teams which have disappointed so far can get through and
suddenly come alive.  Despite the dominance of the New World teams in general
and Argentina in particular, it’s perfectly possible that one of the old-guard
Eurobores will grind their way through to the Cup.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/17/'>
 <title>Maureen Forrester, 1930&#x2014;2010</title>
 <link href='Maureen-Forrester' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Maureen-Forrester#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/17/Maureen-Forrester</id>
 <published>2010-06-17T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-17T06:28:53-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Music' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Music' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Eulogies' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Eulogies' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I have a teeny little bit of personal history with this opera icon; sad to see that <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maureen_Forrester'>Ms Forrester</a> has left us.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I have a teeny little bit of personal history with this opera icon; sad to see
that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maureen_Forrester">Ms
Forrester</a> has left us.</p> 
<p>This would have been some thirty years ago, when as a college student I was
earning rent money by stage-managing any and every sort of musical event, one
of which was a set of master classes given by the diva.</p>
<p>For those who haven’t been to a master class, it’s essentially a public
music lesson. The students (young professionals on that occasion) perform
little bits and pieces; the Star 
critiques and praises and makes them retake and rethink and rework. Good
fun — she was a natural teacher and obviously enjoyed offering <i>faux</i>-intimate
“just between me and all of you” asides to the audience; I sure learned a lot about opera
singing.</p>
<p>Anyhow, here’s what sticks in my memory.  I’d put in a few hours of hard
work setting up the room and polishing the piano and so on; then the Leading
Lady swept in.  She arrived in a cloud of perfume and pastel taffeta, retainers
either side, laughing hugely, her smile framed by a tower of golden hair 
and a generous helping of creamy bosom.  Introductions all around, 
then she asked “And which way to the little girls’ room?”</p>
<p>I didn’t have the nerve to say it, but I was thinking she was about as far
from a “little girl” as it’s possible for a female person to be; it was a
thrill to be in her presence.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/15/'>
 <title>Day Five</title>
 <link href='World-Cup-Day-5' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='6'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='World-Cup-Day-5#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/15/World-Cup-Day-5</id>
 <published>2010-06-15T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-15T23:23:56-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports/Soccer/World Cup 2010' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Soccer' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='World Cup 2010' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>We&#x2019;re now approaching the end of the first third of the round-robin in this geek-blog <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020'>World Cup 2010</a> coverage. Long way to go yet.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>We’re now approaching the end of the first third of the round-robin in this geek-blog
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020">World Cup 2010</a>
coverage.
Long way to go yet.</p>
<p>I didn’t get up at 4AM to watch New Zealand-Slovakia, although I am the
husband of a New Zealander and the father of two more.  Oh well.  And I might
divert a bit of attention from work for an interesting game but I decided that
Brazil-DPRK wouldn’t be one of those; I gather I was wrong.  I have a certain
sick fascination with North Korea to the extent of feeling physical pain in
my gut when I read about what its poor people have to live through. And watching
them play a football match, or otherwise pretend to be normal in the context of a normal
human activity, well it just seems wrong.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Ivory Coast 0 Portugal 0</h2>
<p>OK, I’m a fan now, of the team from the country that would prefer to be
known as Côte d'Ivoire.  They pretty well made mincemeat of the Portuguese
midfield; if Drogba had been able to play 90 minutes I can’t see them not
having won.</p>
<p>There’s all this noise about Ronaldo’s hotness; but today Gervinho was the
more impressive attacker.  No, he’s not an import, his real name is
Gervais Yao Kouassi and Gervinho’s a nickname he got from a Brazilian coach.  If
Drogba can get back on form that just might be the best one-two attacking
punch in the tournament.</p>
<p>As for the Portuguese, feaugh.  I have an attitude problem
caused by their despicable clutching and diving and whining in the 2006
tournament, and I will say they didn’t seem quite as loathsome this time
around.  I literally crowed with glee when the no-bullshit referee gave Ronaldo
and his dance partner yellow cards right at the start of the game; I think the ref
may have done his colleagues in the rest of the tournament a big favor
there.</p>
<p>It’s a pity — that big early shot of Ronaldo’s was like a force of nature
unleashed.  The guy’s got so much talent and so little class.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Tomorrow</h2>
<p>The interesting game, since Group H is a complete yawner which will deliver
Spain and some cannon fodder to the round of 16, is South Africa-Uruguay of
course, since Group A is so wide-open.  Pity it’s in the middle of the work-day.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/15/'>
 <title>Day Four</title>
 <link href='World-Cup-Day-4' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='0'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='World-Cup-Day-4#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/15/World-Cup-Day-4</id>
 <published>2010-06-15T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-15T08:13:27-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports/Soccer/World Cup 2010' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Soccer' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='World Cup 2010' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>We&#x2019;re now four days into the unique insights on <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020'>World Cup 2010</a> only available from those with a good basis in Web and Mobile technology.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>We’re now four days into the unique insights on
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020">World Cup 2010</a> only
available from those with a good basis in Web and Mobile
technology.</p>
<p>I didn’t watch Netherlands-Denmark nor will I watch any further games that
require me to get up at 4AM; there are limits to fandom.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Japan 1 Cameroon 0</h2>
<p>I wanted to be a Cameroon fan on the principle that fluid attacking soccer
in the African style is something to be encouraged.  But I was left 
cold; even the mighty Eto’o seemed a little lead-footed.  Unless Cameroon
has a reservoir of so-far-unrevealed brilliance, I don’t see them making it
out of the group.</p>
<p>As for Japan, their goal was well-earned, their conditioning obviously
better than the opposition’s, and their defence well-schooled.  Not terribly
exciting to watch aside from Matsui’s runs up the side, but I’ll be
unsurprised if they move on.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Italy 1 Paraguay 1</h2>
<p>I sort-of watched this in on my computer via the excellent 
<a href="http://cbcsports.ca">cbcsports.ca</a> feed, but work was intense and
held most of my attention.  On the occasions where I did tune in for a few
minutes, I saw the Italian attack running aground in the rain on the sharp-edged rocks of the
Paraguayan defense.  Even though I’m generally negative about defensive
soccer, it was quite a show.</p>
<p>And the Paraguayan goal, which I did happen to see, was a lightning strike,
perfectly staged and entirely impossible to parry. It wasn’t a defensive
lapse, Alcaraz just out-worked and out-jumped the Italian defenders.
One or two of those per game, plus strong defense, is plenty enough to get not
just out of Group F but well into the serious part of the tournament.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/13/'>
 <title>Day Three</title>
 <link href='World-Cup-Day-3' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='4'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='World-Cup-Day-3#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/13/World-Cup-Day-3</id>
 <published>2010-06-13T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-13T13:37:14-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports/Soccer/World Cup 2010' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Soccer' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='World Cup 2010' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Thus endeth the first weekend of a geek blogger&#x2019;s deathless  <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020'>World Cup 2010</a> prose. For other coverage from non-specialists, much more amusing than mine, check out <a href='http://nplusonemag.com/world-cup-preview'>n+1 magazine&#x2019;s World Cup Preview</a>.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Thus endeth the first weekend of a geek blogger’s deathless 
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020">World Cup 2010</a>
prose.
For other coverage from non-specialists, much more amusing than mine, check
out
<a href="http://nplusonemag.com/world-cup-preview">n+1 magazine’s World Cup Preview</a>.</p>
<p>I didn’t get up at 4AM to watch Algeria-Slovenia but I guess I’m happy because I’ve
<a href="/ongoing/What/The%20World/Places/Slovenia/">been to
Slovenia</a> but not Algeria.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Sebia 0 Ghana 1</h2>
<p>I really couldn’t figure this game out. The Ghanaians totally sliced up the
Serbian mid-field, time and again, quality moves all over the place, then
failed to penetrate the penalty area.  The Serbians looked clumsy and 
unpolished but actually had, on balance, more scoring chances.  That handball?
More clumsiness.  I suppose Ghana deserved the win.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Germany 4 Australia 0</h2>
<p>Just a few minutes into the match, I tweeted “The Germans are scary
good. Ouf” and, well, yeah.  The Aussie defence didn’t seem that weak, which
speaks volumes, probably unnecessary, to Germany’s lethal combination of
precision passing and individual excellence up front.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the Aussie attackers did seem pretty hapless, which
suggests a more capable opponent could give Germany real trouble at the back.
It looks on balance like they and the Ghanaians should waltz out of Group D
without breathing too hard.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/12/'>
 <title>Day Two</title>
 <link href='World-Cup-Day-2' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='4'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='World-Cup-Day-2#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-Day-2</id>
 <published>2010-06-12T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-13T07:43:59-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports/Soccer/World Cup 2010' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Soccer' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='World Cup 2010' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Being the second outing in the bloggification of <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020'>World Cup 2010</a>.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Being the second outing in the bloggification of
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020">World Cup 2010</a>.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Korea 2 Greece 0</h2>
<p>The first comprehensive pounding of this year’s tournament.  The Koreans
apparently recognized fairly early on that the Greeks were having a rotten
day and decided to go into all-pressure-all-the-time mode, and then it was
over.  It’d take real courage for them to try the same approach next time,
which happens to be Argentina, but I’d sure like to watch it.</p>
<p>I think just maybe the Koreans are underrated; among other things, I find
it hard to believe the Greeks are as bad as they looked today. To be fair,
Greece’s team have historically been World Cup chokers, but still.</p>
<p>In particular, the commentators on my TV channel put both Korean
goals down to defensive lapses, which just isn’t true. In particular that
second goal by Park Ji-Sung, who’s a real force at Man United let’s not
forget, may have started with a clumsy give-away, but that was at mid-field
and then he blasted through two defencemen and made the keeper look bad; that
was a class effort.</p>
<p>Nobody seemed to notice that while Greece didn’t bring much pressure to
bear on Korean keeper Jung Sung-Ryong, he handled some nasty high balls coming
right out of the sun without any apparent effort; seems a cool cat.
I’m hoping the Koreans surprise some of the big
names and I’m afraid the Greeks are out of their depth.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Argentina 1 Nigera 0</h2>
<p>Obviously, the boys in blue and white are among the favorites, and this
game offered evidence both for and against that ranking.  On the “for” side is
Messi, who is the real deal.  I’m pleased that with he and Ribéry,
two of the tournament’s biggest-name attackers like to take the ball straight at,
as opposed to around, the defense.  Messi, I suspect he’s the single person on
the planet that a defender least likes to see incoming with momentum.</p>
<p>Also in the “for” side is the remarkable Argentinean discipline and
precision; they routinely pull off these jaw-dropping passing sequences that
happen so fast you have to reconstruct it your mind later.  Truly hot
stuff.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the margin was only 1-0, and Nigeria looked 
pathetic to me: sloppy, poorly conditioned, and just not that hungry.  With
the obvious exception of Vincent Enyeama, who put on as good a
goalkeeping display as I think I’ve ever seen.  But that’s a lousy excuse; a
properly-set-up goal in soccer is one that leaves the keeper no chance, and
Argentine could only manage one of those in 90 minutes.  I think some of their
players not named Messi are going to have to up their game a couple of notches
if they’re going to get anywhere.</p>
<p>But jeepers, those hell-for-leather charges by Messi sure are fun to
watch.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>England 1 USA 1</h2>
<p>(I only watched the last third).</p>
<p>What a terrible disappointment for the English. You can’t ride a shaky
keeper very far in the World Cup, and you also can’t go far if you finish 
your scoring chances with a shot straight at the other keeper’s
chest.  People were praising US keeper Tim Howard to the skies, and yeah, he
stopped Rooney cold three times in the part of the game I saw, but none of
those shots actually made him worry about anything but rebound control.</p>
<p>England may have more to offer than we saw today; they’d better or they’re
in for a short run.  The USA are a lovable team and may just make it out of
the first round, but nobody’s expecting any more than that I think.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/12/'>
 <title>Day One</title>
 <link href='World-Cup-Day-1' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='2'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='World-Cup-Day-1#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-Day-1</id>
 <published>2010-06-12T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-12T06:03:03-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports/Soccer/World Cup 2010' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Soccer' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='World Cup 2010' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Welcome to the <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020'>ongoing World Cup 2010 blogathon</a>.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Welcome to the
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020">ongoing World Cup 2010
blogathon</a>.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Mexico 1 South Africa 1</h2>
<p>It’s a pity the Bafanas couldn’t have won.  Their opening-segment
nerves were forgivable, and their recovery admirable.
Tshabalala’s goal was pure beauty, the kind of thing that
makes soccer worth watching.</p>
<p>I also was impressed by keeper Itumeleng Khune’s quickness and coolness
under fire; he covered for some appalling South African defensive
lapses.</p>
<p>Except for one; on the equalizer there were <em>three</em> Mexican
attackers lined up behind the defense, no South African anywhere near.  What
sets the elite European teams apart is, among other things, that they simply
don’t make that class of mistake.</p>
<p>As for the Mexican game, it felt very European to me: cautious,
orchestrated, focused on at all costs avoiding mistakes.  I don’t think they
have enough attack to get very much further in this tournament, once they’re
up against world-class defense.  But we’ll see.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Uruguay 0 France 0</h2>
<p>I came away from this one liking the French, and remembering that four
years ago they also started slow; slower, if memory serves, than this
pretty-good outing.</p>
<p>Let’s be honest: I also like watching France because, unlike so many of the
other teams, they don’t look like a bunch of TV stars, but like some guys you might
meet in an ordinary bar somewhere.  And Ribéry’s monumental scarfaced
homeliness is remarkably appealing; makes me smile almost every time he crosses the screen.</p>
<p>Speaking of Ribéry, you have to love his relentless runs, given the
slightest opportunity, straight at the defense.
None actually got through against Uruguay, and maybe none
will in this tournament, but they may stress out a few of those defenses to
the point of opening up other attacking lanes.</p>
<p>France is going to have to play better to get very far into this
tournament, but it’s easy to believe they have it in them.</p>
<p>As for Uruguay, after the match I found a blank spot where my opinion of
the team ought to have been. I don’t think my attention wandered that much,
but I just couldn’t bring anything memorable to mind, aside from keeper
Fernando Muslera’s remarkable save against Gourcoff’s nasty corner-bound free
kick.</p>
<p>Being colorful or memorable is not necessarily required for success in the
World Cup tournament; but surely we can ask for a little more than we saw on
Day One.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/12/'>
 <title>2010 World Cup</title>
 <link href='World-Cup-2020' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='6'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='World-Cup-2020#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/12/World-Cup-2020</id>
 <published>2010-06-12T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-12T05:01:23-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports/Soccer/World Cup 2010' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Soccer' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='World Cup 2010' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>What happened was, four years ago in June we <a href='/ongoing/When/200x/2006/06/11/Now-We-Are-Four'>had a baby daughter</a> and I ended up <a href='/ongoing/What/Sports/Soccer/'>watching the World Cup</a>.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>What happened was, four years ago in June we
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2006/06/11/Now-We-Are-Four">had a baby
daughter</a> and I ended up
<a href="/ongoing/What/Sports/Soccer/">watching the World Cup</a>.</p>
<p>I’m not particularly a soccer fan but I found that I enjoyed the show immensely.
I’m not a sportswriter but after I started blogging the matches more or
less accidentally in a newborn-parent haze, that was fun too, and I got tons
of email (that was before there were comments here).</p>
<p>I don’t have parental leave this time, so I probably won’t see as much
of the show, but lots of the matches are very early Pacific time... and then
there’s BitTorrent.  So if you’re oblivious to sports in general or soccer in
particular, I apologize in advance for the coverage that is about to
occur.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Why I Like It</h2>
<p>The sense of occasion, and the widespread joy it brings to so
many around the world.  Something that causes this much intense shared feeling
just can’t be a bad thing.  On balance, I’d say the World Cup is one of the
good things about being a member of <i>Homo sapiens</i>.</p>
<p>Yesterday, before the opening match, listening to the remarkable howl of the
vuvuzelas, halfway between a beehive and a Formula One race, all the smiles
and color and excitement; whose heart could avoid lifting?  I felt (pardon the
cliché) at one with the world.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>My Prejudices</h2>
<p>This year, I go in without a favorite, not really backing anyone.  And I
didn’t manage to catch any of the playdowns, so I’m pretty well in <i>tabula
rasa</i> mode as regards all the teams.  But I’m not without prejudices:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>I like underdogs.</p></li>
<li><p>I like attacking soccer; I think the key to the game is finding space and
running into it and playing the ball forward.</p></li>
<li><p>I like African soccer; the firewagon attack of the good Cameroon and Côte
d'Ivoire teams has provided my favorite international-soccer moments.
Eventually one of these teams is going to build a world-class defense and cut
through the Europe elite, with its fussy caution-first approach, like a
hot knife through butter</p></li>
<li><p>I like Mexico, because they’re from our group, the one that Canada almost
never makes it through into the finals.</p></li>
<li><p>I dislike, of all things, diving.  The #1 thing FIFA could do to improve
the game would be to attack it, and here’s how: Since experience shows that
the referees on the field can’t reliably detect it, but that it’s obvious on
TV, for big matches there ought to be a couple of extra officials watching
video streams, on the radio with the chief referee; and a policy of an instant
yellow card for every dive.</p></li>
</ul>
<h2 id='p-3'>How To Watch It</h2>
<p>I mean, in the case where you can’t sit down in a comfy chair in front of a
nice TV.  There are a variety of feeds here and there around the Net; perhaps
my commenters will fill the details.</p>
<p>Here in Canada,
<a href="http://cbcsports.ca/">cbcsports.ca</a> has a nice setup that 
includes several alternate-camera feeds.</p>
<p>And, in what I consider a triumph, I demonstrated that, given a good WiFi
Signal, my Nexus One, running an Android 2.2 prerelease, with the Flash plug-in installed
(but set to “On Demand” rather than “Auto Start”), I could watch the
cbcsports.ca live feed; a bit of lag and jag but quite usable.</p>
<p>Here’s hoping for surprises.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/10/'>
 <title>Disclosure re Twitter</title>
 <link href='Twitter-Disclosure' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='9'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Twitter-Disclosure#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/10/Twitter-Disclosure</id>
 <published>2010-06-10T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-10T10:31:52-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>A while ago, I made a small investment in a Vancouver company called
Smallthought Systems, which has now been
<a href="http://blog.twitter.com/2010/06/more-than-dabbling.html">acquired by
Twitter</a>.  Thus, I am now the owner of a small number of Twitter shares,
and may fairly be suspected of bias when discussing that company.  I continue
to admire and use Twitter, and also continue to think that it’s a bug when an
apparently-fundamental medium for human communications is the product of a
single company.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/09/'>
 <title>Early-Summer Evening</title>
 <link href='Lightroom-Porch' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Lightroom-Porch#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/09/Lightroom-Porch</id>
 <published>2010-06-09T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-09T19:19:57-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>The idea was, since I just upgraded to Lightroom 3, that I&#x2019;d import whatever was on the cameras, beautify it, and report back on the big new release.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>The idea was, since I just upgraded to Lightroom 3, that I’d import
whatever was on the cameras, beautify it, and report back on the big new
release.</p>
<p>Except for something went wrong; the most interesting pictures were all
taken in a six-minute span out on the porch after dinner, and
for some reason the big Pentax was in JPG not RAW mode, which
drastically reduces Lightroom’s scope.  It’s actually not that easy to switch
the camera over; I suspect one of my children of fiddling with it while I
wasn’t looking.</p>
<p>Having said all that, Pentax ships a pretty damn good JPEG engine in those
cameras; so
consider the following as a photo-essay on a bright early-summer back-porch
evening. I’ll be back to discuss the subtleties of Lightroom 3 once I have
more challenging raw material.</p>
<img src="PS089479.png" alt="Flowers and large arthropod" />
<img src="PS089480.png" alt="Flowers and large arthropod" />
<img src="PS089487.png" alt="Cat (note tongue at work)" />
<img src="PS089490.png" alt="Dogwood" />
<p>That last shot is a dogwood,
the replacement for our recently-deceased pear tree, now in June somewhat past
its prime but still pretty nice to look at as the sun coasts sideways and
down, but mostly sideways at 50°N latitude.</p>

</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/07/'>
 <title>Dots Per Inch</title>
 <link href='DPI' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='19'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='DPI#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/07/DPI</id>
 <published>2010-06-07T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-07T20:19:19-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Mobile' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Mobile' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Presentation' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Presentation' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I thought maybe the most interesting single thing about the new iPhone 4 was its display, not so much the 960 vertical dots but the 326DPI, in the cleverly-named <a href='http://www.apple.com/iphone/features/retina-display.html'>Retina Display</a>. Which leads me to wonder, how much does this matter?</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I thought maybe the most interesting single thing about the new iPhone 4
was its display, not so much the 960 vertical dots but the 326DPI, in the
cleverly-named
<a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/features/retina-display.html">Retina
Display</a>. Which leads me to wonder, how much does this matter?</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>300</h2>
<p>If you care about this subject, I recommend a quick trip to Wikipedia’s
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_displays_by_pixel_density">List
of displays by pixel density</a>.  In the keynote, Steve claimed that there
was some sort of a threshold around 300DPI having to do with the resolving
capabilities of the human retina (thus the name).</p>
<p>Indeed, three hundred is an interesting number; the first wave of
personal-computer printers which produced results that actually looked really
good started at 300DPI.  Right now, per Wikipedia, there are exactly three
devices in the world whose displays exceed it; along with the iPhone, the
Toshiba G900 and the Sony/Ericsson Experia X1, both WinMo phones.</p>
<p>Also I can testify that my Nexus One, at 250DPI or so, is astoundingly
sharp; the first thing in years that’s made me want to tune up the typography
on my blog.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Take Me Higher</h2>
<p>At the same time, I’m not sure about the importance of that 300DPI elbow.
It’s sure not there on paper; today’s commercial laser printers commonly run
at 1200 or 2400DPI.  And high-end commercial pre-press products go way higher;
the devices in the 
<a href="http://www.heidelberg.com/pe/www/en/content/products/prepress/prosetter/prosetter_family">Heidelberg Prosetter</a>
family range up to 3386DPI.</p>
<p>Given the nature of the Android ecosystem, I think we can be pretty sure
that if it turns out that Apple bet right and the extra resolution is a good
selling point, we’ll be in an amusing arms race around DPI PDQ.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Do We Even Need It?</h2>
<p>I hope so, because I sure love the look of these things, but I’m not 100%
convinced.  I’m typing this on a generic Dell 30" 2560x1600 display
offering a pathetic 101DPI, and for the stuff I do all day, it makes me very
happy; I’d have a hard time sacrificing any of that real-estate (4,096,000 pixels!)
for higher density.</p>
<p>For serious photo-work I use a 25"
<a href="http://www.necdisplay.com/products/product/?product=1713e080-c8e3-4aab-9447-73dacb301b84">NEC
2690</a> that I bought because it was
<a href="http://blog.duncandavidson.com/2008/03/nec-2690wuxi-first-impressions.html">good
enough for James Duncan Davidson</a>, and everything looks immensely better there
than it does on the big Dell or my 113DPI MacBook, but that’s not because of
the 98DPI, it’s because of the wonderful color.</p>
<p>I suspect that unless you’re preparing high-quality print work, there’s no
appreciable benefit for a photographer, and perhaps some downside, in an ultra-high-res
display.</p>
<p>Some other relatively low-res devices that seem beautiful to me: the iPad
at 132DPI, and my nice 42" 1080p TV at home, at a laughable 52DPI.</p>
<p>I gotta say though that those high
densities are a joyful experience on hand-held devices; is it as
simple as the fact that you hold them closer to your face?  Is there a
placebo effect at work?</p>
<h2 id='p-5'>Economics</h2>
<p>Do bear in mind that all these extra dots are not free. I’m fairly ignorant
about the manufacturing trade-offs, i.e. how much extra it’s costing Apple to put
614,400 dots on the iPhone 4, as opposed to the the 3GS’s 153,600.</p>
<p>I tend to worry more about the software costs; you have to manipulate 4
times as many pixels every time you double the DPI, and while we’ve learned a
lot of tricks over the years, and increasingly push the work down into display
controllers, the computing cost is very far from zero.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>Typography</h2>
<p>Anyhow, the best way to make a good looking page on the screen,
particularly now that browsers are getting smarter and more polished with
their font-handling, is with
<a href="http://blog.romeda.org/2010/06/beautiful-lines.html">good typography</a>.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/05/'>
 <title>Windy</title>
 <link href='Wind-Mobile' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='4'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Wind-Mobile#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/05/Wind-Mobile</id>
 <published>2010-06-05T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-06T13:27:24-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Canada' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Canada' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Android' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Android' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business/Mobile' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Mobile' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Canada has long been a telephone oligopoly: <a href='http://www.rogers.com/'>Rogers</a>, <a href='http://telus.com/'>Telus</a>, and <a href='http://bell.ca/'>Bell Canada</a>; Canadians generally feel that prices are high and service only so-so. Now we&#x2019;ve got a new mobile player, <a href='http://www.windmobile.ca/'>Wind Mobile</a>. I signed up as soon as they got to Vancouver, at least in part for reasons of ideology; competition is a good thing.  So far, Wind looks like a good thing too.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Canada has long been a telephone oligopoly:
<a href="http://www.rogers.com/">Rogers</a>,
<a href="http://telus.com/">Telus</a>, and
<a href="http://bell.ca/">Bell Canada</a>; Canadians generally feel that prices
are high and service only so-so.
Now we’ve got a new mobile player, <a href="http://www.windmobile.ca/">Wind
Mobile</a>. I signed up as soon as they got to Vancouver, at least in part for
reasons of ideology; competition is a good thing.  So far, Wind looks like a
good thing too.</p>
<p>Mobile network operators make it tough to compare prices, but Wind claims to be
quite a bit cheaper.  I’ve been paying Rogers through the nose because I got a
package with unlimited US roaming, and some add-ons to (somewhat) reduce the
data-roaming pain.</p>
<p>It turns out I can get a corporate SIM card from Google to ease the
in-the-US pain; and then Wind sells unlimited calls <em>to</em> the US for
$10/month.  This is going to create some multiple-phone-numbers pain, but
presumably Google Voice will make that go away before too long assuming it
crosses the US border.</p>
<p>So far, the Wind coverage around Vancouver isn’t as good as
Rogers’ — specifically, only just reaches my house — but it’s usable.</p>
<p>Here’s an amusing thing; while I was down at the Wind office in Yaletown, I
was recognized by two people who know me from Twitter;
<a href="http://flavors.me/nredmond">Niamh Redmond</a> AKA
<a href="http://twitter.com/nredmond">@nredmond</a> and
<a href="http://www.figuiere.net/hub/blog/">Hubert Figuière</a> AKA 
<a href="http://twitter.com/hfiguiere">@hfiguiere</a>.  This kind of thing is
increasingly common; oddly, I hardly ever encounter <span class='o'>ongoing</span>
readers, although the numbers suggest there are way more of ’em.</p>
<p>Here’s another funny thing; while I was at the Wind office signing up,
two others there had Nexus Ones.  Another reason that Wind is interesting to
some people is that Nexus Ones come in two flavors, “A”, which works with
AT&amp;T in the US and Rogers in Canada, and “T”, which works with the
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Wireless_Services">AWS</a>
spectrum; T-Mobile in the US, lots of carriers in Europe and Asia, and now
Wind in Canada.  So if you’ve got a “T” model and want 3G coverage, Wind is
your only choice.</p>
<p>Anyhow, if there are nasty surprises I’ll report back; otherwise the
likeliest outcome is that I will (with some glee) cancel my Rogers service in
the near future.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/03/'>
 <title>Mom&#x2019;s Birthday</title>
 <link href='Jean-Bray-turns-Eighty' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='1'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Jean-Bray-turns-Eighty#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/03/Jean-Bray-turns-Eighty</id>
 <published>2010-06-03T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-03T23:58:59-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Family' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Family' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>The weekend of May 24th, my extended family gathered in Calgary from points East and West across Canada to celebrate my Mom&#x2019;s eightieth birthday.  Herewith  storytelling and pictures.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>The weekend of May 24th, my extended family gathered in Calgary from points East
and West across Canada to celebrate my Mom’s eightieth birthday.  Herewith 
storytelling and pictures.</p>
<p>My Mom is the youngest of six children of Bob and Clara Scott, both Alberta
schoolteachers; she left the profession to be a mother and he went on to
become a Provincial Inspector of Schools; there’s still an R.J. Scott School
somewhere in Edmonton.</p>
<p>The oldest boy was Allen, who died in the very late stages of World War II;
the oldest girl was Beryl, who died a few years ago. Next was Patricia, who’s
not in good enough health to have made it to Calgary.</p>
<p>That leaves Don Scott, professor emeritus of Chemical Engineering at the U
of Waterloo, Beth White, now resident in Calgary, and my mother.</p>
<img src="PS089433.png" alt="Jean Bray, Beth White, Don Scott" />
<div class="caption"><p>Jean Bray, Beth White, Don Scott.  Combined age 251
years; don’t they look great?</p></div>
<p>In Bob and Clara’s generation there was a double marriage between two
brothers and two sisters, so there are all sorts of double cousins; and then
their children were fertile; I have many first cousins and
once you get past that the acquaintance gets hazy. My daughter is the youngest
of Bob and Clara’s great-grandchildren; there’s a spread of over forty years
in that generation.  Most of us remain in the western half of Canada, but
there has been leakage east and south.</p>
<p>My brother Rob hosted; we had 18 souls
there for the actual party-with-cake bit.  Rob, with some help from my other
brother Don and me and his kids, hustled up enough barbecued kebabs and salad and hummus and
tzaziki and corn-on-the-cob and, oh I forget, that nobody went away
hungry.  Damn tasty if I say so myself.</p>
<p>Below are my brothers Don and Rob.  Those who know what I may look like may
detect a pattern.</p>
<img src="PS089400.png" alt="Don Bray" />
<img src="PS089405.png" alt="Rob Bray" />
<p>We lacked enough organization and determination to bake a cake, so they were
store-bought; but let me say that the
<a href="http://www.calgarycoop.com/">Calgary Co-op</a> has the best selection
of cakes I’ve ever seen in a life that has taken me to some famous baking
spots around the world.</p>
<p>I wanted to put eighty candles on it but they wouldn’t let me; anyhow,
there were quite a few, and the rendition of “Happy Birthday” was rousing.
Mom, who plays in a woodwind quartet, blew them out with sufficient force that
the people downwind had to dodge icing fragments.</p>
<p>There was lots of wine, and after dinner politics broke out.  We are a
<em>talkative</em> family, an <em>articulate</em> family, a family whose
current-events discussions have been known to make those who married into it dive for
cover.  While the perfidy and general wrongness of Harper’s Tories was
generally agreed to, there were other points where consensus was not evident.</p>
<p>We’ve taken a resolution to do this again any time one of Bob and Clara’s
kids has a birthday with a “0” in it.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/01/'>
 <title>Starting To Be Wrong</title>
 <link href='Fixed-Format-Electronic-Publishing' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='20'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Fixed-Format-Electronic-Publishing#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/01/Fixed-Format-Electronic-Publishing</id>
 <published>2010-06-01T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-03T21:26:30-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Publishing' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Publishing' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Mobile' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Mobile' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Web' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Web' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Everybody knows that designing for the Web is not like designing for print: The shape is fluid not fixed, the font selection is limited, and there aren&#x2019;t enough dots-per-inch to do proper typography anyhow; the effect is that you have to give up fine control over layout.  Which was true until 2010.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Everybody knows that designing for the Web is not like designing for
print: The
shape is fluid not fixed, the font selection is limited, and there aren’t
enough dots-per-inch to do proper typography anyhow; the effect is that you
have to give up fine control over layout.  Which was true until 2010.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>The Transition</h2>
<p>It hits me especially hard because I’ve always been interested
in typography and design (I didn’t say I was <em>good</em> at
it, just interested), and I come out of the publishing-technology business.  I remember
the sustained howls of anguish from design professionals when
the Web came along and everyone wanted to use it and suddenly many of the
things they they thought they knew became wrong.</p>
<p>The Web obviously didn’t remove the need for visual excellence; it just
made the designer’s life harder by subtracting standard tools.
The user could reshape the window or enlarge the type or suddenly be using a
computer with a really small or really big screen.  The dots-per-inch plunged
from 600-and-up to 100-and-down.</p>
<p>In exchange for all that visual polish we gave up, we got a
dynamic content-addressable world-wide multimedia-rich hypertext; most people
found the trade fair enough.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>That Wired App</h2>
<p>It’s what shoved me into this epiphany that I suppose everyone else had
sometime last year.  The app’s 500M+ in size and, everyone says, 
enthralling.  The way it works is explained by Layton Duncan in
<a href="http://laytonduncan.tumblr.com/post/640355763/bundle-diving-in-the-wired-ipad-app">Bundle
Diving in The WIRED iPad app</a>; the page formats are just graphics, with
overlays for interaction.  They’re designed down to the pixel level; 
pre-Web page-layout techniques in action.</p>
<p>I’ve seen this movie before; in the early days of the Web, a few 
transplanted designers threw up their hands in frustration at its
impoverished visual vocabulary and did more or less as WIRED has; composed 
in a page-layout program, exported as a graphic, and pushed that onto the
Web.  Which was considered evidence that they Just Didn’t Get It.</p>
<p>And at the moment, there are indeed peeved born-and-bred Web
designers explaining why WIRED Just Doesn’t Get It: check out Joe
Clark’s
<a href="http://blog.fawny.org/2010/06/02/wired-app/">Smart designer exports
dumb pictures of text</a> and Jon Gilkison’s
<a href="http://interfacelab.com/is-this-really-the-future-of-magazines-or-why-didnt-they-just-use-html-5/">Is This Really The Future of Magazines or Why Didn’t They Just Use HTML 5?</a>
</p>
<p>Well, yeah.  As
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eric_Gill">Eric Gill</a> wrote, “A
letter is a thing, not a picture of a thing.”  At some level, what WIRED has
given us is a travesty.</p>
<h2 id='p-5'>Oh, Wait</h2>
<p>At another, it’s a rational response to the new environment found on mobile
Internet devices.  They typically don’t use resizeable windows; you work within the
constraints of a specific fixed rectangle.  They have densities that
are now approaching the 300dpi where print starts; if
Wikipedia’s
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_displays_by_pixel_density">List
of displays by pixel density</a> is accurate, the next iPhone will exceed it.
I can certainly testify that my Nexus One is the highest-resolution electronic
display device I’ve ever owned; it makes conventional monitors (and the 132dpi
iPad) look dingy.</p>
<p>Granted, vertical scrolling in the browser style is still common, but on the
iPad in particular, a page-flip metaphor has replaced scrolling in many
applications.
If you abandon scrolling, you immediately open the door to multi-column
layouts, which
<a href="http://informationarchitects.jp/wired-on-ipad-just-like-a-paper-tiger/">are controversial</a> but, in the right circumstances, highly
effective.</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>What’d you say I’d get?</h2>
<p>I am reminded of an acronym that had fallen into disuse: WYSIWYG for What
You See Is What You Get.  It was the rallying cry of the first
electronic-publishing systems, the ones that made Steve and the Woz their
first few boatloads of money.  It was always a complete lie, because what you
could display on a screen was never remotely comparable to the experience of
the same layout on real paper with a factor-of-ten-higher pixel density.  But
it was useful.</p>
<p>In the early days of the Web, some of the authoring software claimed to
offer “WYSIWYG Web Publishing” which was an even bigger lie and not even a
useful one; still, I remember Adobe getting a standing ovation at the first
public demonstration of
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_PageMill">PageMill</a> in 1994, when they
dragged-and-dropped a GIF in the authoring system and then refreshed Netscape
and it was just where they’d put it.  In that version of that browser on that
computer on that day, anyhow.</p>
<p>But, I dunno... the people who pulled that WIRED app together, What They
Saw was What We Got.  There has to be a better way to achieve the effect.  But
the fact remains that a lot of what we think we know about Web design is 
starting to be wrong.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/06/01/'>
 <title>Compatibility and Fragmentation</title>
 <link href='Compatibility' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Compatibility#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/06/01/Compatibility</id>
 <published>2010-06-01T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-06-01T11:07:55-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Android' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Android' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Over on the Android Developers&#x2019; Blog, we just published <a href='http://android-developers.blogspot.com/2010/05/on-android-compatibility.html'>On Android Compatibility</a> by Dan Morrill, who manages both the Open-Source and Compatibility work here.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Over on the Android Developers’ Blog, we just published
<a href="http://android-developers.blogspot.com/2010/05/on-android-compatibility.html">On
Android Compatibility</a> by Dan Morrill, who manages both the Open-Source and
Compatibility work here.</p>
<p>It’s like this: The source code is the technology.  The Compatibility
Definition Document is the policy.  The Compatibility Test Suite is the OEM
tool.  And the Android Market is the enforcement mechanism.</p>
<p>I think it’s an important piece, because there’s
been a lot of talk around these issues and, as far as I know, nobody had ever
written up, for anyone except the OEMs, exactly what the Android policy and
mechanisms are.  My feeling is that anyone who wants to hold forth on these
subjects really ought to invest some time reading this, as well as the
documents it links to.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2010/05/30/'>
 <title>Corporations and Emotions</title>
 <link href='Feelings-About-Companies' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='25'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Feelings-About-Companies#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/05/30/Feelings-About-Companies</id>
 <published>2010-05-30T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2010-05-30T23:59:47-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Is meaningful or useful to have emotional reactions to business organizations?  Right now there&#x2019;s a lot of that going around; the atmosphere swirling around my employer and That Fruit Company a short commute away in Silicon Valley grows steamy.  Which pales compared to the global outpouring of fear and loathing directed at a certain English oil corporation. I&#x2019;m going to argue (after some personal digressions) that hating on BP is perhaps actively harmful.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Is meaningful or useful to have emotional reactions to business
organizations?  Right now there’s a lot of that going around;
the atmosphere swirling around my employer and That Fruit Company a
short commute away in Silicon Valley grows steamy.  Which pales
compared to the global outpouring of fear and loathing directed at a certain
English oil corporation. I’m going to argue (after some personal digressions) that
hating on BP is perhaps actively harmful.</p>
<h2 id='p-7'>Personal Digression</h2>
<p>Recently I
<a href="http://twitter.com/timbray/status/14950012279">tweeted</a> (and I
apologize for the coarse language): “Unlike apparently everyone, I’m not
pissed at BP. You gonna live on fossil fuel, shit gonna happen. BP drew the
short straw.”  Which didn’t seem to me that radical a thing to say.  It’s far
from established that BP is significantly worse (or better) in its practices
than the rest of the industry.  Seems to me that it’s not one oil company
that’s befouling our species’ only nest, it’s our systemic addiction to cheap
energy and aversion of our eyes from what that does to us.</p>
<p>I can see perfectly well that others might not agree with me, seeing BP as
a unique malefactor worthy of unique punishment; for example, a 
<a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Boycott-BP/119101198107726">large
number gathering on Facebook</a>.  So I wasn’t surprised at getting lots of pushback.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Angry at Google</h2>
<p>I was a little surprised at
<a href="http://twitter.com/counternotions/status/15062361881">this</a>, which
opens with “Google mouthpiece Tim Bray...”  A couple of clicks reminded me
that I was reading someone who hides behind the (albeit stylish) alias
<a href="http://counternotions.com/contact/">Kontra</a> and who has previously
<a href="http://counternotions.com/2010/05/17/curation/">hated on me</a> with
considerable glee.</p>
<p>While everyone knows that there’s a lot of perfectly-reasonable
worry about Google’s pervasiveness and reach, the company itself seems too
inchoate and chaotic to hold any particular single feeling about for any length of
time. But Kontra genuinely loathes Google right down to the ground. (I can
testify with some force that at Google there is a notable lack of 
conspiratorial intent to Do Bad Things With All That Data, but then you might
choose to discount that testimony because of the logo on my paycheck.)</p>
<p>Having said all
that, I think Kontra is something of an anomaly.  I wish he’d decloak though;
anonymous polemics leave a very sour taste.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>What About Apple?</h2>
<p>Hating (or loving) them seems
about as equally unreasonable.  I’ve been vocal about my loathing for their
app-store regime but they’re my favorite computer manufacturer, and
the iPhone is a terrific product; challenging fun to compete against.  
Apple marketing irritates me but
then so does 90%-plus of <em>all</em> marketing.  I have emotional reactions
to certain of their design values (positive to the general design of the OS X interface,
negative to the shiny-black-and-silver
color scheme of recent MacBooks) but design values <em>should</em> provoke
those.  Apple as a whole? I look into my soul and honestly can’t scare up
much in the way of feelings, positive or negative.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>It Happened To Me</h2>
<p>For some number of years I loathed Microsoft, but
then on the other hand I’d been the target of a direct attack during which
that company sincerely tried to ruin my career, and my wife’s because of her
relationship to me.  So that was an unusual situation no matter how you look
at it.  These days Microsoft is irrelevant to anything I care about.</p>
<p>And at the end of the day I can’t see really getting emotional about
commercial organizations.  That
<a href="http://www.google.com/corporate/tenthings.html">Our Philosophy</a> stuff
does lend me some comfort here at Google, but my passions, positive and negative, center on
people and projects, not the commercial organizations that house them.</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>Back to BP</h2>
<p>Hating the company has the potential to distract from a larger problem, the
immense number of <em>other</em> 
poorly-regulated oil platforms in the Gulf; is it 
<a href="http://scienceblogs.com/pharyngula/2010/05/a_constructive_suggestion_for.php">4,000
or only 1,500</a>?</p>
<p>And it’s bigger than that; both the current spill and the whole Gulf problem,
the more I look at them, seem like
symptoms of a deeper disease.  You have to treat a disease’s symptoms or they
might kill you, but suing BP into oblivion (a good idea if there’s
a decent legal case) isn’t going to reduce the big-picture damage contingent
on our addiction to unrealistically-priced fossil fuels.</p>
<p>And hating the company, or any company, will just reduce the quality of
your life.</p>
</div></content></entry>

</feed>
