<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- RSS generated by OPML Editor v0.73 on Thu, 24 Jun 2010 01:19:06 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:scripting2="http://scripting2.com/namespace.html">
	<channel>
		<title>Scripting News</title>
		<link>http://scripting.com/</link>
		<description>Dave Winer&apos;s weblog, started in April 1997, bootstrapped the blogging revolution. </description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>Copyright 2010 Scripting News, Inc.</copyright>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 01:19:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<generator>OPML Editor v0.73</generator>
		<managingEditor>scriptingnews1mail@gmail.com</managingEditor>
		<webMaster>scriptingnews1mail@gmail.com</webMaster>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.org" port="5337" path="/rsscloud/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<ttl>15</ttl>
		<item>
			<title>What good is the realtime web...</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/whatGoodIsTheRealtimeWeb.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/whatGoodIsTheRealtimeWeb.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/whatGoodIsTheRealtimeWeb.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/23/applestore.jpg&quot; width=&quot;145&quot; height=&quot;78&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named applestore.jpg&quot;&gt;If you can&apos;t get a realtime readout on the line at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/retail/west14thstreet/?cid=WWW-NAUS-GoogMaps-Retail-211&amp;cp=GoogMaps&quot;&gt;14th Street&lt;/a&gt; Apple Store?&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I mean if I get up at 3AM and there&apos;s a party down there, I might actually take a hike. If it&apos;s just crazy drunks screaming at and about nothing, I&apos;ll just sleep in. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I mean come on people, it&apos;s 2010! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 01:11:42 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/whatGoodIsTheRealtimeWeb.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Time-Warner DOCSIS 3 in NYC?</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/timewarnerDocsis3InNyc.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/timewarnerDocsis3InNyc.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/timewarnerDocsis3InNyc.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dslreports.com/shownews/Time-Warner-Cable-Finally-Launches-DOCSIS-30-104626&quot;&gt;According to DSL Reports&lt;/a&gt;, Time-Warner is offering DOCSIS 3 in NYC for $99.95 per month.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m sure I don&apos;t know what DOCSIS is, but I do know this much -- it&apos;s faster than what I have. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&quot;According to Time Warner Cable, they&apos;re now offering a 50 Mbps downstream and 5 Mbps upstream for $99.95 per month.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;That&apos;s the deal I want. Now, I&apos;ve been to the TWC website, and I can upgrade to &quot;Turbo&quot; for $9.95 more per month. But I&apos;m only paying $34.95 per month now, so it seems that can&apos;t be the faster DOCSIS 3. There is no technical information on the site. And I definitely don&apos;t want to get on the phone with one of their fast-talking bull-shitting hucksters. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I also want to order cable TV with the minimal package I need to get HBO. I&apos;m sure their hucksters can&apos;t handle that either. I want an online form I can order it from.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Any pointers would be much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;PS: My mom is getting 23.5 Mbps down and 15.5 Mbps up from Verizon FIOS in Queens.&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 00:54:36 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/timewarnerDocsis3InNyc.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Edit This Page works in Scripting2</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/howEditThisPageWillWorkInS.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/howEditThisPageWillWorkInS.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/howEditThisPageWillWorkInS.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/23/touchdown.gif&quot; width=&quot;59&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named touchdown.gif&quot;&gt;This is more geeky tech stuff, and might interest about a dozen people, so if you don&apos;t understand -- no problem. It won&apos;t be on the final exam. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/1999/05/24/editThisPage.html&quot;&gt;Edit This Page&lt;/a&gt; was the central feature in Manila, the blogging tool we shipped at UserLand in 1999. For me, a blogging tool without it isn&apos;t much of a blogging tool. But it&apos;s not easy to implement. C&apos;est la vie. Neither was Undo, but the Mac required it, and it&apos;s one of the reasons people like the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;The premise was that every story in the system would have an ETP button that, when clicked, would open the story in an editor, so you can make the change, hit Save, and get on with it. Content management systems of the day didn&apos;t have that feature. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Anyway -- Scripting2 will have that feature as well. I&apos;m getting started implementing it, so if you look at the HTML source for &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/howEditThisPageWillWorkInS.html&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;, you&apos;ll see a &amp;lt;script&gt; element that links back to the local server, 127.0.0.1. If you don&apos;t have a server running there, hopefully your browser just ignores it. That&apos;s one of the reasons I&apos;m writing this post, to see if that assumption is true. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;On my machine, the HTML the script returns is a form with an Edit button, that, when clicked, loads the source of the page into an editor where I can change it, save it and move on. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Update: 6:21PM Eastern -- it works! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 19:53:53 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/howEditThisPageWillWorkInS.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Improving paragraph-level permalinks</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/improvingParagraphlevelPer.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/improvingParagraphlevelPer.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/improvingParagraphlevelPer.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m back in NY, after returning from Calif where I sold my house. Now it&apos;s time to get back to my real job -- writing a new blogging tool called Scripting2.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;To get the ball rolling, I&apos;m going to make paragraph-level permalinks work a little beter.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;In their first incarnation, implemented a few years ago, a pargraph would get a unique name derived from its timestamp which was converted into a number to make the name. So if this paragraph was created at 12:28:08 PM today its name would be &quot;p934826408.&apos; It works, but it&apos;s pretty unsightly. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;In the next iteration the names were a bit nicer. As it was rendering the story it would bump a counter each time it moved to a new paragraph. So the names would be p1, p2, etc. The only problem is if I added a paragraph in the middle, all the numbers would move down and links might point to the wrong place, which defeats the purpose of having the permalinks.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;So now I&apos;m doing it a better way that has less distracting names than the original approach, but won&apos;t break if paragraphs are added in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;When I create a new paragraph I give it a serial number. So the first paragraph in a story might get serial number 249, and the second would be 250, and so on. The corresponding names would be p249 and p250. Later if I add a paragraph between them, it could be 284. The numbers would appear to be out of sequence if you looked closely, but they would remain unique. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;In fact this post was written using the new system. If you&apos;re reading this on the web and not in a feed reader, try hovering over the purple pound signs at the end of each paragraph. A paragraph was added in the middle. See if you can find it!&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;BTW, the serial numbers are reflected in the OPML that&apos;s linked into the HTML rendering and the RSS feed, so if you&apos;re writing an alternate viewer for my posts, you can use the serial numbers in generating your paragraph-level permalinks.&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 16:35:48 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/improvingParagraphlevelPer.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to start over with Google Voice?</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/howToStartOverWithGoogleVo.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/howToStartOverWithGoogleVo.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/howToStartOverWithGoogleVo.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/23/obama.jpg&quot; width=&quot;145&quot; height=&quot;101&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named obama.jpg&quot;&gt;Yesterday Google &lt;a href=&quot;http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2010/06/google-voice-for-everyone.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/voice#inbox&quot;&gt;Google Voice&lt;/a&gt; is open to everyone. That&apos;s great! I&apos;d love to use it. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;But when I set it up initially, about a year ago, I didn&apos;t understand how it works, and I made a mess of it. I was just trying stuff out, like I often do with online apps, thinking it would be easy to start over once I understood how it worked. Apparently not so with Google Voice. Unless I was missing something.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve tried to ask the question through other means, but haven&apos;t gotten an answer. So I thought, as a last resort, I&apos;d ask you guys if you have a clue how I might nuke my account and create a new one. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Update: Apparently there is a way to &lt;a href=&quot;http://spreadsheets.google.com/viewform?formkey=cjlWRDFTWERkZEIxUzVjSmNsN0ExU1E6MA&quot;&gt;request&lt;/a&gt; that a Google Voice number be transferred to a different Google account.&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 12:05:13 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/23/howToStartOverWithGoogleVo.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why I don&apos;t do interviews</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/whyIDontDoInterviews.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/whyIDontDoInterviews.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/whyIDontDoInterviews.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/22/typewriter.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named typewriter.jpg&quot;&gt;I mentioned in an off-hand &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/gettingBackToNewYork.html#p5&quot;&gt;way&lt;/a&gt; that I don&apos;t do interviews. I thought I had written a piece that explains why, but I couldn&apos;t find it. Now I&apos;ll have one to point to if the question comes up again.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;First, I did press interviews for many years before deciding not to do them. I was never happy with the process, but considered them a necessity, mostly because I was either a company executive or product promoter, or both. By accepting their terms, my name would get more exposure, I would become more famous, and presumably more credible. Since my name was attached to a product, and it was attached to a business model, being interviewed was a way to make money, in theory.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;However, there was a negative side -- they rarely carried my point of view accurately. My quotes almost always made it appear as if I believed things I didn&apos;t. Sometimes I was portrayed as believing &lt;i&gt;the opposite&lt;/i&gt; of what I believed. So while I might have been furthering my financial cause, I was often hurting the cause of truth. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Then in 2002, something changed -- I left my company, and since then, have been involved on a consulting basis, from time to time, with other people&apos;s products. But, mostly, the financial incentive was gone. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Another thing happened a few years before that -- I started blogging, and thus had a way to get my name and ideas out there, without going through the press. And when I write, my words can express exactly what I believe, and when they don&apos;t, I can run a follow-up. I didn&apos;t realize it at first, but the success of my blog made it unnecessary for me to accept the problems with doing press interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/22/mwom.gif&quot; width=&quot;138&quot; height=&quot;193&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named mwom.gif&quot;&gt;Futher, I don&apos;t accept the theory of press interviews. Why should I give an exclusive to one reporter at the expense of all others? And why should I favor professionals over amateurs, over other bloggers? Why can&apos;t they read what I write on my blog, and choose soundbites from that material? They can, of course. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Some of them don&apos;t like this, they think that in an interview they can catch people in lies. I&apos;ve had them actually say this to me. In all the years I had been cooperating with reporters, not one has caught me in a lie, nor would they be likely to, if I was deceiving them. Mostly they are unprepared for the interview, often they&apos;re not even listening (or so it seems). They certainly don&apos;t know the subject well enough to catch a liar. They explain themselves as they were heroes, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hrc.utexas.edu/exhibitions/web/woodstein/&quot;&gt;Woodward or Bernstein&lt;/a&gt; chasing Watergate. I think it&apos;s ludicrous. I think they are incapable of getting original stories, and mostly rewrite press releases, and never take chances with the favor of companies they need access to, therefore the stories mostly come out the same. There isn&apos;t very much courage or depth in today&apos;s press. I might do interviews again if I got the idea that a reporter was doing something worthwhile with their franchise. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;In the press there&apos;s a presumption that they&apos;re honest and you&apos;re not. I guess this, when I finally fully understood it, was what got me to stop helping them. I think even when I was in the role of a company exec, I was more honest than most of the reporters I tried to work with. There&apos;s certainly no cause to treat me, by default, as if I was &lt;i&gt;dis&lt;/i&gt;honest. Even a small fry like me doesn&apos;t have to cooperate these days. Maybe that&apos;s the fundamental contradiction of journalism today.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;It got comical at times, especially since I had absolutely no business interest in the things I was talking about. For me the light came on when I was being grilled by a reporter, asked the same question over and over, while talking about the gadgets used at a friends&apos; wedding. I kept trying to say I was doing everyone a favor by talking with the reporter, I had nothing to gain by the interview. To prove it, I asked not to be quoted in the piece.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I was starting to feel like it was unnecessary and pointless, and had mostly stopped doing interviews. When I made an exception, I would get burned. So I stopped making exceptions. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;These days, my policy re interviews is: 1. I don&apos;t do them. 2. If you want to tell me what you&apos;re interested in, I might write a blog post if I have something to say. You can quote the post freely, of course -- it&apos;s on the record and for attribution. 3. I might be willing to talk with you, but it will always be for background only. You can&apos;t quote anything I say. It&apos;ll be two equals having a discussion, not one person interviewing the other.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I made a different offer to Brendan Greeley of the Economist, a former colleague of mine at Berkman Center. I suggested he come on the weekly Rebooting the News &lt;a href=&quot;http://rebootnews.com/2010/06/21/rebooting-the-news-56/&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; with myself and Jay Rosen. Most reporters wouldn&apos;t do this, not wanting to tip off their competitors. I never understood this, since they all write the same stories anyway. Rarely is there anything worth keeping secret, at least from my naive point of view. Brendan accepted, and he more or less got the interview he sought. It&apos;s a good show! And since it&apos;s all out there, we all win. No chance of me being misquoted. Of course when his story runs that&apos;s a whole other thing. We talk about that in the podcast. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Also, I&apos;m always willing to do live radio. It has none of the disadvantages of a private interview. And if I want to I can turn it around and make it a discussion, as we did in yesterday&apos;s podcast. &lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 19:29:31 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/whyIDontDoInterviews.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Should I be at the Apple store at 7AM on Thursday?</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/shouldIBeAtTheAppleStoreAt.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/shouldIBeAtTheAppleStoreAt.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/shouldIBeAtTheAppleStoreAt.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/22/iphone4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;145&quot; height=&quot;273&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named iphone4.jpg&quot;&gt;It&apos;s a long story but I&apos;m one of the people who has an iPhone 4 reserved at the local Apple store. This time the people who opted for home delivery are getting theirs a day early. Last time around, with the iPad, I opted for home delivery and got it a few hours after the people who waited in line. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;But this time I have to get in line. The question is should I be a total fanboy and be there at 6AM, lined up for the 7AM opening? Do I really have the fortitude and patience to wait in line, or should I show up at a reasonable hour, say 10AM or 11AM and wait in the line then. It&apos;s summer so it&apos;ll be much hotter later in the day. But maybe the line will be shorter? Maybe there won&apos;t be a line? &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Questions. Questions. Of course I&apos;d like to be among the first to have the phone, but that&apos;s not possible since the home folk are going to have it a day earlier than me. &lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 13:23:33 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/shouldIBeAtTheAppleStoreAt.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>How naming will work with Twitter Annotations</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/howNamingWillWorkWithTwitt.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/howNamingWillWorkWithTwitt.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/howNamingWillWorkWithTwitt.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/22/skittles.gif&quot; width=&quot;121&quot; height=&quot;187&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named skittles.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/twitter-api-announce/browse_thread/thread/fa5da2608865453?hl=en&amp;pli=1&quot;&gt;Annotations&lt;/a&gt; is a feature coming soon for Twitter that allows developers to attach arbitrary bits of metadata to tweets. I&apos;ve written about this idea several times, most recently on April 9. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/04/09/howTwitterCanKillTheTwitte.html&quot;&gt;How Twitter can kill the Twitter-killers&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;If I want to write an app for dogs who tweet, let me add a &apos;field&apos; to a tweet called isDog, a boolean, that tells me that the author of the tweet is a dog. That way the dog food company who has a Twitter presence can learn that the tweet is from a dog, from the guy who&apos;s developing a special Twitter client just for dogs, even though Twitter itself has no knowledge of the special needs of dogs. We can also add a field for breed and age (in dog years of course). Coat type. Toy preference. A link to his or her owner. Are there children in the household?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Almost as soon as it was announced, before any developers had actually used it, a concern was raised. How will the names be arrived at? And what happens if two developers use different names for the same idea? Based on this, they question the value of the entire architecture. How could it possibly work?&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;There is an answer to the question. We know how it will work because this is far from the first time the question has come up. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;The answer is this: Developers &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; choose different names for the same idea. However, if the idea is important enough, and if an entity with a lot of users (and therefore a lot of tweets) gets involved, people will gravitate to the name that entity chooses. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;This is one of the advantages of a corporate platform like Twitter. There is by default an entity with a lot of users -- Twitter. They basically have &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; the users. So the names they use will by default become the standard names. This is a very good thing, and no amount of FUD from bigger companies should stop them from exercising their eminent domain.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Further, in my April post, I suggested that &quot;all the elements of the core namespace&quot; be &quot;reserved for Twitter. If you want to extend it, create a namespace and have a party.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/22/scoop.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;155&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named scoop.gif&quot;&gt;Now, it&apos;s reasonable to assume that Twitter won&apos;t want to get involved in every possible use of Annotations. In that case the chaos of the market and a sense of urgency will fill in. This happened in RSS, where there was a similar situation. Some developers even renamed ideas that were in the core namespace! Yes, it&apos;s a mess. But it worked anyway. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;If there are two or three names for the same idea, guess what an enterprising developer does -- he or she supports all of them. In these cases &lt;a href=&quot;http://essaysfromexodus.scripting.com/postelsLaw&quot;&gt;Postel&apos;s Law&lt;/a&gt; advises: &quot;Be liberal in what you accept and conservative in what you send.&quot; That&apos;s how long we&apos;ve been having this re-invention problem, it goes all the way back to the founding of the Internet. Hey it probably goes back to biblical or even caveman days. The desire to take credit for other people&apos;s accomplishments is something that&apos;s been in our species for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I suspect the people who are casting stones at Twitter Annotations either don&apos;t have the experience to know that these things work themselves out if the incentives are strong enough, or have another agenda, like limiting the growth of the Twitter platform. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I suggest not worrying about it. If it turns into a problem, it will be because we found at least a few valuable applications for Twitter Annotations. In other words, it&apos;s a &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; problem to have. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 11:16:02 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/22/howNamingWillWorkWithTwitt.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>An epiphany about Twitter</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/21/anEpiphanyAboutTwitter.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/21/anEpiphanyAboutTwitter.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/21/anEpiphanyAboutTwitter.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/21/vacuum.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;246&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named vacuum.jpg&quot;&gt;Just in time for &lt;a href=&quot;http://rebootnews.com/&quot;&gt;Rebooting the News&lt;/a&gt; that&apos;s about to start in a half hour. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Twitter is down, again. It&apos;s become a regular experience, again, lately. Each time it happens, some link doesn&apos;t get transmitted to my followers, but more important to me, it doesn&apos;t get into my link system. So now I have to worry about whether I&apos;ll remember to go back and read it later. And I won&apos;t be able to see how many people clicked on it, to get a rough idea of how interesting it is to people. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Arrrgh, I think to myself, if only the fishstinkin Twitter client guys would get a little bit of courage and implement an &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/howAnEbsForTwitterCouldWor.html&quot;&gt;EBS for Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Then I realized something, and this is the epiphany. Geez, maybe it isn&apos;t up to the client guys, maybe it&apos;s up to the users!&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Imagine if you had a shit ISP that couldn&apos;t keep your website on the air. How long would you put up with it? Should it make a difference that Twitter is free? Is that really what it&apos;s about? I leak huge amounts of money just living my daily life. No, it&apos;s not about the money. And yes, after a while, enough is enough, it&apos;s time to do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;So that&apos;s the epiphany -- we don&apos;t have to wait for anyone, I can solve it, as a user. I can put my short status messages somewhere else, and let them find their way to Twitter, when it&apos;s up.&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 15:38:11 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/21/anEpiphanyAboutTwitter.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Kick back Google</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/kickBackGoogle.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/kickBackGoogle.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/kickBackGoogle.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2010/06/20/twitter-annotations-are-coming-what-do-they-mean-for-twitter-and-the-web/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+OmMalik+%28GigaOM%29&quot;&gt;Twitter Annotations are coming&lt;/a&gt; and Google can&apos;t get their act together to compete so they try to spoil the party. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Look Twitter is a small company that struggles. They&apos;re trying to ship an ambitious, potentially revolutionary feature called Annotations. They don&apos;t have to do it. There are probably people inside the company that wonder why they are. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;If you work for Google, you work for a much bigger, much richer company. If you want to take cheap shots at Twitter, at least have the good grace to quit your job and do it from the sidelines. When you do it from inside The Machine you make it look very bad. You make it look like you can&apos;t compete in the market so you try to spoil it for those who are trying. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Being-nasty-for-the-sake-of-being-nasty. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Grrr. &lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 16:38:34 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/kickBackGoogle.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>A fatherless Father&apos;s Day</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/aFatherlessFathersDay.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/aFatherlessFathersDay.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/aFatherlessFathersDay.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;This is my first fatherless Father&apos;s Day.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s doubly weird because my father&apos;s birthday was last week. The first birthday since his birth that he missed.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I sold my house a couple of days before Father&apos;s Day. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;A fatherless Father&apos;s Day isn&apos;t entirely a bad thing. It could also be Freedom Day. Because no matter how much you swore you&apos;d never live for your father, and no matter how much he swore he wouldn&apos;t make you live for him, it happened anyway. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Giving up on the paternal judgment is like giving up smoking in some ways. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Oh, btw, I just realized June 14 was my anniversary. Eight years. I completely missed it. Sign of a truly reformed smoker.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;But in my first year as a non-smoker, when my thought process came to a vexing problem, it would snap to: Oh I&apos;ll just smoke a cigarette, and I&apos;d move on to the next step. I&apos;d probably grab a cigarette at that point, for good luck.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I can&apos;t tell you how many times, on accomplishing something, no matter how small, my mind would snap to: Call Dad. Tell him about it. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s like losing an uncle only worse. When my uncle died, I felt like I lost an arm. It was that big a deal. Part of my support system was gone. But with a father, it&apos;s a leg. Sometimes it&apos;s both legs. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;But as you get used to it, the snap-to fades. And what replaces it is freedom. Not entirely bad, as I said earlier. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;My father told me about it when his father died. It was then he told me not to wait for him to pass to take my leave of his judgment. Didn&apos;t matter. Couldn&apos;t do it. Didn&apos;t.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks have been irritating. Messages from Amazon, every damned day reminding me to buy him a gift. What are you going to do. Forget it and move on. &lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 19:34:51 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/aFatherlessFathersDay.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Getting back to New York</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/gettingBackToNewYork.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/gettingBackToNewYork.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/gettingBackToNewYork.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/scriptingnews/4716333340/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/20/sold.jpg&quot; width=&quot;115&quot; height=&quot;137&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named sold.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&apos;m writing this at &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=sfo&amp;sll=40.733373,-74.004711&amp;sspn=0.007171,0.013797&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=&amp;hnear=San+Francisco+Intl,+San+Francisco,+San+Mateo,+California+94128&amp;z=13&quot;&gt;SFO&lt;/a&gt;, waiting for a flight to NY, where I resume my life without the tether back to California. The house is sold, the money is in the bank. I already have a life in New York. Knock wood, it should all be smooth from here, even though it was rough this week in Berkeley. These kinds of transitions always are. Gotta remember that next time I&apos;m thinking it would be fun to buy a big beautiful house. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m starting to map out the next moves with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting2.com/&quot;&gt;Scripting2&lt;/a&gt; software. I have to add the ability to preview a post and to delete a post. After that I&apos;ll be ready to start my second site. Once all the kinks are worked out at that level, I&apos;ll invite one or two people to try it out, the same way I did with Manila in 1999. My first three users of that software, aside from other people at UserLand, were Dan Gillmor, Jamis at Buck&apos;s Woodside and my Jamaican uncle. There weren&apos;t many bloggers back then to try out new blogging software. We more or less had to create them. It will be different now.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;A couple of other things I want to do with Scripting2: 1. The ability to create documents that are not hooked into the chronology of the blog. 2. A single place to find all change notes for all the various software projects I&apos;m doing. Right now it&apos;s pretty scattered. With Scripting2 as a foundation, I&apos;m within striking distance of a unified, outline-based change notes tool. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I also want to integrate the &lt;a href=&quot;http://howto.opml.org/dave/editorOpmlOrg/instantOutlineTool.html&quot;&gt;Instant Outliner&lt;/a&gt; with the Scripting2 editing tool. I think it&apos;s time to break the connection with Friendfeed, as much as I like their API. I&apos;ll probably use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rsscloud.org/cloudpipe.html&quot;&gt;Cloudpipe protocol&lt;/a&gt; I created for rssCloud. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;We&apos;re going to have a guest again this week on &lt;a href=&quot;http://rebootnews.com/&quot;&gt;Rebooting The News&lt;/a&gt;. This time it will be &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/brendanhgreeley&quot;&gt;Brendan Greeley&lt;/a&gt; who writes for the Economist. He&apos;s doing a piece about where blogging is at, and is almost ready to submit it for publication. He wanted to get my perspective, I don&apos;t do interviews, so I suggested he come on the show, and he accepted. So he gets to discuss this with Jay too! Win-win-win.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;As always it will be carried live on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogtalkradio.com/rebooting-the-news/2010/06/21/rebooting-the-news-56&quot;&gt;BlogTalkRadio&lt;/a&gt; and available as an MP3 from &lt;a href=&quot;http://rebootnews.com/&quot;&gt;rebootnews.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I know Brendan from Berkman days. He worked with Chris Lydon on his Radio OpenSource podcast. Should be fun&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 18:05:45 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/20/gettingBackToNewYork.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pear Salad</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/19/burgerAtTrex.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/19/burgerAtTrex.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/19/burgerAtTrex.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/scriptingnews/4716319276/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/19/pearSalad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named pearSalad.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 03:57:59 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/19/burgerAtTrex.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Burger at T-Rex</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/19/burgerAtTrex.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/19/burgerAtTrex.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/19/burgerAtTrex.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/scriptingnews/4716111580/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/19/burger.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named burger.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 03:50:04 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/19/burgerAtTrex.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why Angry Birds is so much fun</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/18/whyAngryBirdsIsSoMuchFun.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/18/whyAngryBirdsIsSoMuchFun.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/18/whyAngryBirdsIsSoMuchFun.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/18/pigs.gif&quot; width=&quot;145&quot; height=&quot;153&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named pigs.gif&quot;&gt;On a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://rebootnews.com/&quot;&gt;RBTN&lt;/a&gt; podcast I asked Jay if he remembered how, when the iPad first came out, we said we&apos;d have to see what its killer app is. Well I think we now know. It&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/angry-birds/id343200656?mt=8&quot;&gt;Angry Birds&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;;-&gt;&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;You could hum the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/geekdad/2010/03/iphone-review-angry-birds-make-great-projectiles/&quot;&gt;Angry Birds&lt;/a&gt; theme song in the subway and &lt;i&gt;someone&lt;/i&gt; would look up and smile at you. It&apos;s become that popular.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;The game is very simple. The pigs stole the birds&apos; eggs. The birds are angry. The pigs build forts. The birds jump into a sling shot where you aim them at the fort. When a bird or a bit of debris hits a pig, he explodes. Your mission is to kill all the pigs. And the pigs don&apos;t seem to mind. They&apos;re happy, snorting and grinning, all the way up to their moment of death. That&apos;s the gist of the game, though it has a few little subtleties. No spoilers. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve been trying to figure out why such a dumb game is so much fun.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I know it sounds mean, but it&apos;s probably the same kind of pleasure you get from breaking up your little sister&apos;s doll tea party. Or your brother&apos;s sand castle at the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I guess it&apos;s not really mean because it&apos;s just a video game on a hand-held device.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Another thought hit me. When the elaborate pig forts topple it kind of looks like the Twin Towers coming down on 9/11. And the birds, well they&apos;re a lot like a suicide bombers. Well, actually they are &lt;i&gt;totally&lt;/i&gt; like suicide bombers. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;They&apos;re so damned angry at the pigs that they don&apos;t mind killing themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Of course when you see how smug the pigs are, you get angry at them too. But in a nice way! &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 15:48:07 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/18/whyAngryBirdsIsSoMuchFun.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Yvonne and the fish-head guy</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/17/yvonneAndTheFishheadGuy.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/17/yvonneAndTheFishheadGuy.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/17/yvonneAndTheFishheadGuy.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/scriptingnews/4709979968/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/17/fishHeadYvonne.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named fishHeadYvonne.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 23:25:49 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/17/yvonneAndTheFishheadGuy.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>My last trip to Calif as a Californian</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/17/myLastTripToCalifAsACalifo.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/17/myLastTripToCalifAsACalifo.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/17/myLastTripToCalifAsACalifo.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/17/california.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;81&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named california.gif&quot;&gt;I&apos;m writing this from Berkeley. I&apos;m here to sell my house and cut my last ties to the Golden State, and this time it feels like it&apos;s for good. I say &quot;feels like,&quot; because I did this once before, in 2003. Sold my house in Woodside, and drove cross-country to Cambridge. After that, I tried living in Florida, Seattle and got started looking at apartments in NY before giving up. I found myself in Berkeley and tired of being unrooted. So I rented an apartment, and one thing led to another -- I was house-shopping and found a place I loved.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;It was 2006, the peak of the real estate market. It&apos;s hard to imagine now, but back then real estate was thought to be a foolproof investment. I was making tons of money in the stock market. I had a feeling that I would just increase my earnings by owning prime Calif real estate. And it is a lovely old designer home in a fantastic spot.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Soon after buying the house, everything went to hell. I&apos;m sure you know the story. Mortgage crisis, banking crisis, world financial meltdown. The house, while still lovely, had spoiled as an investment. But don&apos;t cry for me, net-net I&apos;m way ahead because I got scared early and sat out the worst of the stock market &quot;bath of blood.&quot; (I just watched &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lord_of_War&quot;&gt;Lord of War&lt;/a&gt;, that&apos;s its running joke.) And it was a very nice place to live.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Then last year my father got really sick, again, and this time &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com/stories/2009/10/03/fathersDay.html&quot;&gt;he died&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;That&apos;s a time when you get to look at everything about your life, you can&apos;t hide from yourself, like we so often do. When I looked inside, one of the things I found was a regret that I hadn&apos;t been closer to him in his last years. But there was a deeper regret. I found that I&apos;m a New Yorker, and I was living in the wrong place for a New Yorker.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lord_of_War&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/17/lord.jpg&quot; width=&quot;145&quot; height=&quot;205&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named lord.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I had been traveling there a lot in 2009, so I decided to rent an apartment, and try living bi-coastal for a year. I got a visiting fellowship with my friend Jay Rosen at NYU, to give me an official reason to be there. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;By March, I decided that I wanted to be there permanently. Not on a bi-coastal basis. So I put the house on the market, drove my car cross-country. And got to work at being a full-time Noo Yawka.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Since then, I&apos;ve discovered some simple truths, but important ones.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve always, as an adult, lived in a place where I was a transplant, and other people were natives. In NY, I am a native. I actually live in the place where I come from. There are small cues. Like the smell of the ocean at sunrise, and how it reminds me of waking up in my grandmother&apos;s house in Rockaway. No two oceans smell alike, I guess. This one smells like home. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I can tell how New York has changed!&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;When I grew up here, everyone wanted to leave. Brooklyn was a complete disaster. The streets and subways weren&apos;t safe. The Bronx was burning down. There were riots. Then the city went bankrupt.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Things are so dramatically better in NY now, it&apos;s hard for the newbies to realize it.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;And the people who come to NY from the other parts of the country -- they are amazing. At least the ones I&apos;m meeting. It seems if you have something you want to do, it&apos;s the place you go. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;And from a creative and business standpoint, I am in exactly the right place at the right time. Sure there may be a lot of value in social networks, and California is where that&apos;s being pioneered. But for me, it&apos;s about publishing and media. I believe in leveling the playing field and opening the doors. I don&apos;t think of this as democratization, or citizen journalism -- I agree with Nick Denton that there are people who will use the new techniques much more powerfully than others. But it should allow more information to flow faster to the people who want it. And in doing so, create new economies. And of course in doing &lt;i&gt;that,&lt;/i&gt; make new wealth. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;In other words, people who think NY should aspire to be another Silicon Valley, are completely missing the opportunity. And people who leave NY to find fame and fortune in Silicon Valley may find it, but they won&apos;t find what I&apos;ve been looking for. I gave it 30-plus years. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&apos;m writing this from Berkeley. Right now I still own property here, but soon (knock wood) I won&apos;t. When I get on the plane for NY, this time, I will truly be going home. Can&apos;t wait. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 13:37:21 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/17/myLastTripToCalifAsACalifo.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>2010 Knight News Challenge Winners</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/2010KnightNewsChallengeWin.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/2010KnightNewsChallengeWin.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/2010KnightNewsChallengeWin.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;CityTracking. $400K. Eric Rodenbeck, Stamen Design, San Francisco, CA&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;The Cartoonist. $378K. Ian Bogost and Michael Mateas. Atlanta, GA.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Local Wiki. $350K. Philip Neustrom and Mike Ivanov. San Francisco, CA&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;WindyCitizen&apos;s Real Time Ads. $250K. Brad Flora, WindyCitizen.com. Chicago, IL.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;GoMap Riga. $250K. Marcis Rubenis and Kristofs Blaus, GoMap Riga. Riga, Latvia.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Order in the Court 2.0. $250K. John Davidow, WBUR. Boston, Mass.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Front Porch Forum. $220K. Michael Wood-Lewis, Front Porch Forum. Burlington, VT.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;One-Eight. $202K. Teru Kuwayama. Chicago, Ill.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Stroome. $200K. Nonny de la Pe&#150;a and Tom Grasty, Stroome. Los Angeles, CA&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;CitySeed. $90K. Retha Hill and Cody Shotwell, Arizona State University. Phoenix, AZ.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;PRX StoryMarket. $75K. Jake Shapiro, PRX. Boston, MA.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Tilemapping. $74K. Eric Gundersen, Development Seed. Washington, DC&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:06:12 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/2010KnightNewsChallengeWin.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bootstrapping a federated Twitwork with annotations?</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/bootstrappingAFederatedTwi.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/bootstrappingAFederatedTwi.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/bootstrappingAFederatedTwi.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/04/24/chairs.gif&quot; width=&quot;170&quot; height=&quot;145&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named chairs.gif&quot;&gt;Just had an idea that with the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://engineering.twitter.com/2010/05/annotations-hackfest.html&quot;&gt;annotations&lt;/a&gt; feature coming soon in Twitter, we might have the means to bootstrap an &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/howAnEbsForTwitterCouldWor.html&quot;&gt;Emergency Broadcast System&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Imagine if every tweet included info about where to find that users&apos; status messages if Twitter is down. It could simply be the URL of a feed. Unless Twitter went down it would just be stored by your client. But if Twitter should go offline, at least you know how to find out what&apos;s going on with at least some of your associates.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;The point is that with annotations we have the ability to create new ad hoc flows of information, and can possibly use it to make Twitter more reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s like having a place to meet your friends after a ballgame, or part of being prepared for an earthquake (I just landed in SF). You arrange for a meeting place if the normal lines of communication go down. You use the normal lines to transmit the place you will be found in cast the line goes down. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I guess it&apos;s something like DNS, where you always specify two servers and two hosts. If everything is working you only need one. But the network is designed to work even if everything isn&apos;t working.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Of course it&apos;s this line of reasoning that led me to the conclusion that Twitter should just run off DNS, and Twitter should be the Verisign of this network. But that&apos;s another story. &lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 17:34:02 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/bootstrappingAFederatedTwi.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>How I do the Hand-drawn Posts</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/howIDoTheHanddrawnPosts.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/howIDoTheHanddrawnPosts.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/howIDoTheHanddrawnPosts.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;From time to time people ask how I do the hand-drawn posts. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/scriptingnews/4705845700/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/16/howIDoTheHandDrawnPosts.gif&quot; width=&quot;449&quot; height=&quot;363&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;  alt=&quot;A picture named howIDoTheHandDrawnPosts.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why I do them:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;1. They&apos;re fun.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;2. I like to draw.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;3. It&apos;s a neat way to use a scanner.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;4. It&apos;s super low-tech.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;5. They&apos;re eye-catching.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;6. People like them.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;7. They work.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why do both lists have seven items?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;1. Seven is the perfect number of items for a list.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;2. Just kidding. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Dave&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 08:26:32 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/16/howIDoTheHanddrawnPosts.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>How an EBS for Twitter could work</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/howAnEbsForTwitterCouldWor.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/howAnEbsForTwitterCouldWor.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/howAnEbsForTwitterCouldWor.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;An &lt;i&gt;Emergency Broadcast System for Twitter&lt;/i&gt; might look like this.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/scriptingnews/4704357433/sizes/l/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/15/ebsForTwitter.gif&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named ebsForTwitter.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;When everything is working at Twitter, all the clients communicate through Twitter. A client is an app like Tweetdeck, UberTwitter, Seesmic, Brizzly, Tweedroid, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;However, when Twitter is down, each client sends your tweets to a &quot;safe place&quot; and the clients your friends use hear about your status updates from there.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s still a lot of disruption, but some messages get through. Over time the EBS will get better, as we learn better how to make the best of a Twitter outage.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Reality: We still need to communicate even when Twitter is down.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Bottom-line: The client vendors are key.&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 00:59:08 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/howAnEbsForTwitterCouldWor.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>A bug in the OPML validator?</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/aBugInTheOpmlValidator.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/aBugInTheOpmlValidator.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/aBugInTheOpmlValidator.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/14/rssToTheLeftOfMeOpmlToTheR.html#comment-56818466&quot;&gt;Chris Janton&lt;/a&gt; pointed out that some of my OPML isn&apos;t properly handled by another OPML-processing application, and that my own &lt;a href=&quot;http://validator.opml.org/&quot;&gt;validator&lt;/a&gt; rejects it as invalid. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s an &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/youCanReserveAnIphoneAtAnA.opml&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt; of a file that&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://validator.opml.org/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fscripting.com%2Fstories%2F2010%2F06%2F15%2FyouCanReserveAnIphoneAtAnA.opml&quot;&gt;rejected&lt;/a&gt; as invalid. It says: &quot;The type attribute on an &amp;lt;outline&gt; element should be a known type.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opml.org/spec2#extendingOpml&quot;&gt;OPML 2.0 spec&lt;/a&gt; says this is okay. &quot;OPML can also be extended by the addition of new values for the type attribute.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/15/bigfly.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;101&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named bigfly.gif&quot;&gt;The reason it is this way is that the OPML Editor, the app that OPML is the file format for, has an extension mechanism that allows this. When I give an &amp;lt;outline&gt; element a type attribute with a value of foo, when the user double-clicks on that element, the editor looks for a nodetype definition called foo. If it has a method for handling a double-click, it gets control, does its thing, and returns, overriding the default functionality. It&apos;s essential to the way the editor works that the type attribute be allowed to have unforseen values.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;So it&apos;s clearly a bug that the OPML Validator rejects these OPML docs.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Not sure what the OPML-processing app should do, I&apos;d have to know more about what the concern is. But the spec clearly allows what we&apos;re doing with Scripting2&apos;s OPML.&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 19:03:20 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/aBugInTheOpmlValidator.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>You *can* reserve an iPhone 4 at an Apple Store</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/youCanReserveAnIphoneAtAnA.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/youCanReserveAnIphoneAtAnA.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/youCanReserveAnIphoneAtAnA.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/15/iphone4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;145&quot; height=&quot;273&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named iphone4.jpg&quot;&gt;Like almost everyone else, I have been unable to get through to the Apple Store on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.apple.com/us&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt;. I had the time today so I got on the subway and headed uptown to the Apple Store on &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?oe=utf-8&amp;client=firefox-a&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;q=apple+store+fifth+ave&amp;fb=1&amp;gl=us&amp;hq=apple+store+fifth+ave&amp;hnear=Midtown,+New+York,+NY&amp;cid=0,0,4277159875397643590&amp;ei=2qAXTNLxCsSBlAeg2oi0Cw&amp;ved=0CBoQnwIwAA&amp;ll=40.764974,-73.973029&amp;spn=0.007752,0.013797&amp;z=16&amp;iwloc=A&quot;&gt;5th Ave&lt;/a&gt;, thinking I could order it there, in person.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;At first, the salespeople said I had to do it the same way I&apos;d do it from home. I said that doesn&apos;t work. They shrugged it off. I was getting ready to leave, but on the way out I asked another sales person, and really pressed, and he said he could reserve one for me to pick up on the 24th. Sheez, why didn&apos;t you say that in the first place? Never mind. I did it, and now presumably I&apos;ll get one on the 24th like all the other Apple-addicts who can&apos;t wait to get their hands on the latest and greatest.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get this out there, in case you&apos;re near an Apple Store, you might want to go down there, and tell them you &lt;i&gt;know&lt;/i&gt; you can reserve one for pickup on the 24th. Tell them Dave toldja. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 15:44:38 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/youCanReserveAnIphoneAtAnA.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>May the source be with you! :-)</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/mayTheSourceBeWithYou.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/mayTheSourceBeWithYou.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/mayTheSourceBeWithYou.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;Just as a program has source code, so does the writing on this blog. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s always been this way, but I&apos;ve accepted the limits of other blogging tools, and the limits of RSS, and not exposed the richer writing environment behind scripting.com. That is changing, gradually, with the new software. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;The small initial changes have caused some consternation. Some people are concerned that they&apos;re not getting all the content in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feeds. Some people feel the plus sign is too small, and others don&apos;t want to click on it, they think it should be expanded by default.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;So here are some responses to these concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I want to include all the content in the feeds, and with a change I made last night, I now am. I&apos;m just not providing it in the old &quot;flat&quot; way. There&apos;s a link to the source code behind the HTML rendering. The source has all the text. Of course there aren&apos;t any apps that read this format, yet. It&apos;s always that way. When I first came out with the predecessor to RSS, no one read it. But eventually someone did, and then a lot of people, etc etc. That may not happen here, but then again, it might. Don&apos;t count it out. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/15/nyer.gif&quot; width=&quot;125&quot; height=&quot;177&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named nyer.gif&quot;&gt;There are actually now &lt;i&gt;two ways&lt;/i&gt; to get the source behind the HTML rendering: 1. You can get it from a link element in the HTML. This would be useful for a bookmarklet that wanted to try alternate rendering of the text, as Readability does, for example. 2. It&apos;s in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/rss.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; for scripting.com. Each item links to the source in a new element called &amp;lt;scripting2:source&gt;. This would be used by a news reader app like Google Reader, if they wanted to do something special with content coming from advanced blogs like Scripting News. Do I believe that eventually the other blogging tools will offer this? Yes, in fact, I do. Do I think Google will support it now? No, as long as it&apos;s just my blog, they won&apos;t support it (probably). But when others do it, they hopefully &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; decide to support it, and help us add some cool features to the web. I would, of course, like to see them do that. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I also made a small change to the rendering of the site. There&apos;s now a small XML icon below the blogroll, in the right margin of every page. It links to the OPML for the blogroll. I expect there will be some interesting things doen with that. There are features already implemented in the blogroll that aren&apos;t yet visible in the UI. I think the blogroll will eventually bust out of the right margin and become something itneresting on its own. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;There have been some excellent suggestions about the sub-text feature: 1. Make the icon larger. (Will do.) 2. Move the icon so it&apos;s at the right and bottom. (Makes sense, but isn&apos;t the way outliners work. I&apos;m going to stick with the current placement for now.) 3. Make it so clicking in the text makes it expand. (Good idea, but doesn&apos;t that break selection? What if you want to copy a bit of text from the post?)&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Finally, I&apos;m really glad this discussion is taking place here now. I wanted to draw intelligent thoughtful technical people back to Scripting News, to participate in what I hope will be a bootstrap of some new technology. Keep discussing, share your ideas, even if you don&apos;t like what I&apos;m doing. There&apos;s more to come. Sometimes the first few chapters of a story don&apos;t make you happy, then you see where the plot is going, and it starts to make sense. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 12:59:03 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/15/mayTheSourceBeWithYou.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>RSS to the left of me, OPML to the right</title>
			<link>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/14/rssToTheLeftOfMeOpmlToTheR.html</link>
			<guid>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/14/rssToTheLeftOfMeOpmlToTheR.html</guid>
			<comments>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/14/rssToTheLeftOfMeOpmlToTheR.html#disqus_thread</comments>
			<description>
								&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.scripting.com/archiveScriptingCom/2010/06/14/joker.gif&quot; width=&quot;145&quot; height=&quot;226&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; hspace=&quot;15&quot; vspace=&quot;5&quot; alt=&quot;A picture named joker.gif&quot;&gt;Jay wrote a blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://journalism.nyu.edu/pubzone/weblogs/pressthink/2010/06/14/ideology_press.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; this evening whose title is a lyric from an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuck_in_the_Middle_With_You&quot;&gt;old&lt;/a&gt; Stealer&apos;s Wheel &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8StG4fFWHqg&quot;&gt;song&lt;/a&gt;. Got me humming and it eventually became the title of this post. &lt;i&gt;&quot;Only steal from the best!&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m getting a lot of inquiries about sub-text in Scripting2. People still seem to love it, but they want to know how it will work with RSS apps like NetNewsWire, River2 and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?q=define:omnibus&quot;&gt;omnibus&lt;/a&gt; Google Reader. (I first wrote ominous, for its sheer dominance, but then thought they probably don&apos;t &lt;i&gt;feel&lt;/i&gt; dominant, just like they&apos;re carrying all kinds of passengers.) I don&apos;t have the source code to the other apps, and River2 is not a full-text affair (I strip markup and cut the text off at 250 characters, based on its design as a skimmer rather than a reader). But we should get on the road to making it &lt;i&gt;possible&lt;/i&gt; for reader apps to do something nice with the collapsed sub-text.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;So, today I did two things that should help, but probably aren&apos;t the last word in publishing the material that backs up a Scripting2 post. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;1. There&apos;s now a &amp;lt;link&gt; element at the top of each &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/14/rssToTheLeftOfMeOpmlToTheR.html&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; that points to the OPML source for the story. View Source in the browser to see it.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;2. There&apos;s a link to the OPML source in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/rss.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;. It&apos;s in a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting2.com/namespace.html&quot;&gt;namespace&lt;/a&gt; called scripting2.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;These are probably not the last word in linkage to the full source behind my blog posts, and if there&apos;s little or no uptake, I&apos;m not guaranteeing I&apos;ll support them for perpetuity. If you use them -- please let me know, preferably in a public comment or post, so others can see. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;PS: For good measure, there&apos;s also a link to the blogroll in the HTML source, per a request from the illustrious Matt Terenzio. &quot;;-&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

				</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 01:30:39 GMT</pubDate>
			<scripting2:source>http://scripting.com/stories/2010/06/14/rssToTheLeftOfMeOpmlToTheR.opml</scripting2:source>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
