<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">
    <title>Repairing the Healthcare System</title>
    
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/" />
    <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:weblog-352923</id>
    <updated>2010-06-22T18:41:12-07:00</updated>
    
    <generator uri="http://www.typepad.com/">TypePad</generator>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem" /><feedburner:info uri="repairingthehealthcaresystem" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>RepairingTheHealthcareSystem</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><entry>
        <title>President Obama And The Sustainable Growth (SGR) Formula For Medicare Reimbursement</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/T4HxpXJl1Mo/president-obama-and-the-sustainable-growth-sgr-formula-for-medicare-reimbursement.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/president-obama-and-the-sustainable-growth-sgr-formula-for-medicare-reimbursement.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133f19f29e3970b</id>
        <published>2010-06-22T18:41:12-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-06-22T18:41:12-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE President Obama promised the AMA he would fix the defective Medicare Sustainable Growth Rate formula for calculating Medicare reimbursement to physicians. As a result of that promise the AMA supported President Obama’s healthcare reform bill. The AMA...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicare" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/">
&lt;div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;President Obama promised the AMA he would fix the defective Medicare Sustainable Growth Rate formula for calculating Medicare reimbursement to physicians. As a result of that promise the AMA supported President Obama’s healthcare reform bill.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The AMA made a big mistake supporting President Obama’s healthcare reform bill. It was as if the AMA did not evaluate the bill’s obvious unintended consequences for both patients and physicians.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The AMA lost support from not only 85% of physicians that are not members of the AMA but also from the 15% of physicians that are members.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The SGR formula makes no sense. Medicare has reduced physician reimbursement to physicians as physicians’ expenses have increased. A 21.2% decrease in reimbursement will result in physicians losing money seeing Medicare patients. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e20133f19f24f0970b-pi"&gt;&lt;img title="clip_image002" style="border-top-width: 0px; display: inline; border-left-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; border-right-width: 0px" height="185" alt="clip_image002" src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e20133f19f25b3970b-pi" width="244" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;It is stupid to lose money seeing patients. President Obama’s unintended consequence will be physicians will stop seeing Medicare patients. Physicians cannot make up the loss by increasing the volume of patients seen. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Most physicians are decreasing expenses by installing electronic medical records. The available EMRs are not fully functional. The capital expenditure is too high for most physicians. They cannot afford an electronic medical record even with President Obama’s subsidy. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;A New York Times article explains the conventional wisdoms. However, there is little proof that the conventional wisdom is correct. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/06/06/opinion/06sun1.html?emc=tnt&amp;amp;tntemail1=y"&gt;There will likely be no real solution until the American health care system moves away from unfettered fee-for-service payments&lt;/a&gt; that encourage doctors to perform unnecessary and costly tests and procedures and pays them instead for better management of a patient’s care over time.” &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;My interpretation is physicians should get paid a salary by the government as the single party payer. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The media ignores the fact that most physicians do not get paid for the unnecessary and costly procedures.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Hospital systems and national laboratories do the tests and receive the reimbursement. The majority of physicians are single practitioners. Family Physicians and Internists cannot afford the equipment necessary to do testing in office. It is against the law for physicians to bill for testing done outside their office. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Physicians might order multiple tests that could be considered unnecessary by some. They order these tests as part of the defense against malpractice suits. Malpractice reform has been totally ignored by President Obama’s healthcare reform bill. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Until there is significant malpractice reform defensive medicine and the resulting “unnecessary testing” will not disappear. The use of appropriate data can alert the government and the healthcare insurance industry when a physician abuses the system. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The excuse of over testing does not warrant a reduction in reimbursement to Family Physicians and Internists. Doctors cannot afford to see Medicare and Medicaid patients at a loss. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;It is obvious that there will be a physician shortage, long waiting periods to see a physician and rationing of care. I will discuss the complexity of the issue in detail shortly.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Family physicians and internists only have time and intellectual property to sell. The Medicare fee schedule recognizes prevention. However, Medicare does not reimburse for prevention, telephone calls or emails. President Obama talks a good game but has done nothing to correct SGR. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The “sustainable growth rate” (SGR) formula was enacted in 1997. Policy wonks concluded it was a way to restrain Medicare spending. I do not think the Policy wonks intended the consequences. The SGR set annual limits for the total amount of money to be paid in the traditional Medicare program. It also included allowances for inflation in the cost of operating a medical practice, for growth in the elderly population, and even a little extra money to pay for increases in the volume and complexity of services performed. It sounded reasonable. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The blue represents physicians’ increased in billings. The red represent application of the SGR formula. In 2007- 2009 Congress waived application of the SGR. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013484c6d2c9970c-pi"&gt;&lt;img title="clip_image004" style="border-top-width: 0px; display: inline; border-left-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; border-right-width: 0px" height="181" alt="clip_image004" src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013484c6d382970c-pi" width="244" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/06/06/opinion/06sun1.html?emc=tnt&amp;amp;tntemail1=y"&gt;The fatal flaw in the formula was&lt;/a&gt; that it had no way to limit the array of services doctors provided or distinguish between valuable and needless treatments.” &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If doctors in the aggregate billings drove Medicare expenditures above the limit set by SGR, the SGR formula called for fees in the following year to be reduced.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“ &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/06/06/opinion/06sun1.html?emc=tnt&amp;amp;tntemail1=y"&gt;That aggregate punishment was not enough to persuade individual doctors to change behavior&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Off course it would not change behavior. The threat of a malpractice trumps a punitive monetary penalty. It is not wise to create a punitive environment for any workers. It encourages bad behavior. Why can’t the government find the specific individuals it claims abuse the system and deal with them? The SGR is defective and needs changing. It needs to be changed along with the rules in the malpractice system.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Congress has waived the SGR formula since 2007 after physicians screamed for help. Congress did not suspend the proposed cuts. The accumulation of the yearly suspended cuts resulted in the 21.2% reduction in reimbursement this year. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2009/02/more-medicaid-is-this-what-we-want-for-our-healthcare-system-part-2.html"&gt;I said physicians would stop seeing Medicare patients at a loss.&lt;/a&gt; This would hurt seniors’ access to medical care. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama ignored the call for help until June 12&lt;sup&gt;th. &lt;/sup&gt;He has had one and one half years to proclaim his support for eliminating the faulty SGR formula. He used the 21.2% reduction to calculate the deficit reduction effect of his healthcare reform bill.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Republicans are screaming that President Obama is spending money like a drunken sailor. Republicans decided to put their foot down. SGR was the wrong issue to put their foot down on. &lt;a href="https://md.sermo.com/medical/ticket/details?id=52423"&gt;President Obama placed the blame on the Republicans in his weekly radio address.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“&lt;a href="www.whitehouse.org"&gt;This year, a majority of Congress is willing to prevent a pay cut of 21% -- a pay cut that would undoubtedly force some doctors to stop seeing Medicare patients altogether. But this time, some Senate Republicans&lt;/a&gt; may even block a vote on this issue. After years of voting to defer these cuts, the other party is now willing to walk away from the needs of our doctors and our seniors.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama knew Democrats did not have the votes to eliminate the SGR formula when President Obama made his grandstanding radio announcement. The suspension of SGR failed to pass. Physicians are now going to see a 21.2% reduction in Medicare reimbursement. The AMA’s deal with President Obama did not work. It was never going to work. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The American public should be getting tired of President Obama’s games. Barney Frank and John Kerry summed up the strategy that had been developed by the Democrats long ago. No one listened. Listen again. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;div class="wlWriterEditableSmartContent" id="scid:5737277B-5D6D-4f48-ABFC-DD9C333F4C5D:d793e2eb-a281-4da2-9662-69b3c1ca317f" style="padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-left: 0px; float: none; padding-bottom: 0px; margin: 0px; padding-top: 0px"&gt;&lt;div id="55ab5bc9-40c6-455c-9f58-5ed93dec14e6" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline;"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f3BS4C9el98&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;" target="_new"&gt;&lt;img src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013484c6d489970c-pi" style="border-style: none" galleryimg="no" onload="var downlevelDiv = document.getElementById('55ab5bc9-40c6-455c-9f58-5ed93dec14e6'); downlevelDiv.innerHTML = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;object width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;param name=\&amp;quot;movie\&amp;quot; value=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/f3BS4C9el98&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/param&amp;gt;&amp;lt;embed src=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/f3BS4C9el98&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash\&amp;quot; width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/embed&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/object&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/div&amp;gt;&amp;quot;;" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;div class="wlWriterEditableSmartContent" id="scid:5737277B-5D6D-4f48-ABFC-DD9C333F4C5D:7a43bffc-734c-4bf0-8dd3-a7cecb8639b7" style="padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-left: 0px; float: none; padding-bottom: 0px; margin: 0px; padding-top: 0px"&gt;&lt;div id="32d9a2dc-6e4f-48fd-85aa-644690663594" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline;"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-522hcm3woA&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;" target="_new"&gt;&lt;img src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e20133f19f2985970b-pi" style="border-style: none" galleryimg="no" onload="var downlevelDiv = document.getElementById('32d9a2dc-6e4f-48fd-85aa-644690663594'); downlevelDiv.innerHTML = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;object width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;param name=\&amp;quot;movie\&amp;quot; value=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/-522hcm3woA&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/param&amp;gt;&amp;lt;embed src=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/-522hcm3woA&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash\&amp;quot; width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/embed&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/object&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/div&amp;gt;&amp;quot;;" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Now President Obama doesn’t need congressional approval to get a single party payer system. He will do it by administrative regulation.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I do not think President Obama has thought out the unintended consequences. The burden to the American public will be huge . &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="OLE_LINK1"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/T4HxpXJl1Mo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/president-obama-and-the-sustainable-growth-sgr-formula-for-medicare-reimbursement.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>If You Like Your Insurance You Can Keep It. Period! President Barack Obama</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/-fDmNCPJQUA/if-you-like-your-insurance-you-can-keep-it-period-president-barack-obama.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/if-you-like-your-insurance-you-can-keep-it-period-president-barack-obama.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133f1839fab970b</id>
        <published>2010-06-20T08:38:02-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-06-20T08:38:02-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE Here we go again. On Friday June 11, 2010 at 4.30 pm internal administration documents were leaked. The documents reveal that up to 51% of employers may have to relinquish their current health care coverage because of...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/">
&lt;div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Here we go again. On Friday June 11, 2010 at 4.30 pm internal administration documents were leaked. The documents reveal that up to 51% of employers may have to relinquish their current health care coverage because of ObamaCare. President Obama promised us that if we like our insurance we can keep. (See 3.46 minutes of the following You Tube.}&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;div class="wlWriterEditableSmartContent" id="scid:5737277B-5D6D-4f48-ABFC-DD9C333F4C5D:6f54efd8-f557-4052-a711-90b02cb3b63e" style="padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-left: 0px; float: none; padding-bottom: 0px; margin: 0px; padding-top: 0px"&gt;&lt;div id="be448aa3-2556-4619-a88c-69afd2c7b094" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline;"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=83FvLjsUOJg&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;" target="_new"&gt;&lt;img src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e20133f1839f9f970b-pi" style="border-style: none" galleryimg="no" onload="var downlevelDiv = document.getElementById('be448aa3-2556-4619-a88c-69afd2c7b094'); downlevelDiv.innerHTML = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;object width=\&amp;quot;456\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;380\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;param name=\&amp;quot;movie\&amp;quot; value=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/83FvLjsUOJg&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/param&amp;gt;&amp;lt;embed src=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/83FvLjsUOJg&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash\&amp;quot; width=\&amp;quot;456\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;380\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/embed&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/object&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/div&amp;gt;&amp;quot;;" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2008/04/now-we-are-talk.html"&gt;This is getting to be a habit with this administration.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Late in the afternoon on Fridays is a convenient time to leak information. No one will notice the information. The leaks’ impact will be old news by Monday morning. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The administration claims it did not know how it leaked. It is only a draft of the regulations created by Kathleen Sebalius Secretary of HHS. President Obama’s healthcare bill gives her the authority to write the regulations. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.investors.com/NewsAndAnalysis/Article/537208/201006111932/Keep-Your-Health-Plan-Under-Overhaul-Probably-Not-Govt-Analysis-Concludes.aspx"&gt;“The &amp;quot;midrange estimate is that 66% of small employer plans and 45% of large employer plans will relinquish&lt;/a&gt; their grandfathered status by the end of 2013,&amp;quot; according to the document.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;In the worst-case scenario, 69% of employers — 80% of smaller firms — would lose that status, exposing them to far more provisions under the new health law.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The report was part of a joint project of the Departments of Health and Human Services, Labor and the IRS. The final report will be 118 pages. The report examined the effects ObamaCare's regulations will have on existing, or &amp;quot;grandfathered,&amp;quot; employer-based health care plans.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama pledged it would have no effect on the healthcare insurance you have now. He did not say anything about modifications to present plans.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.investors.com/NewsAndAnalysis/PhotoPopup.aspx?path=WEB2c0614_full.jpg&amp;amp;docId=537208&amp;amp;caption="&gt;&lt;img title="clip_image002" style="border-right: 0px; border-top: 0px; display: inline; border-left: 0px; border-bottom: 0px" height="167" alt="clip_image002" src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013484ab76b8970c-pi" width="272" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.investors.com/NewsAndAnalysis/PhotoPopup.aspx?path=WEB2c0614_full.jpg&amp;amp;docId=537208&amp;amp;caption="&gt;View Enlarged Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This is another trick play by President Obama. The Republicans have been caught flatfooted once again. The healthcare reform bill allows President Obama and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to interpret broad provisions in the bill any way they want. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The President has said that a single party payer system works in other countries. It can work in America. His goal is to work his way toward a single party payer. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;People have accused President Obama of wanting to eliminate private insurance. He said “we can keep our insurance if we like our present insurance.”&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;It turns out with these new regulations that we cannot keep our healthcare insurance plan if our employers modify the provisions in our plan. Americans will be forced to buy healthcare insurance from President Obama’s health insurance exchanges. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The health insurance exchange is supposed to provide affordable healthcare insurance. The healthcare insurance will be purchased with after-tax dollars. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The problem is cost controls will be regulated by the government. The program will fail to control costs just it has failed to control cost and improve service in Massachusetts. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama has also said if something does not work we will adjust the system. Here comes the Public Option. However, the government and the states cannot afford to pay for healthcare insurance.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.investors.com/NewsAndAnalysis/Article/537208/201006111932/Keep-Your-Health-Plan-Under-Overhaul-Probably-Not-Govt-Analysis-Concludes.aspx"&gt;What are the conditions that eliminate your retaining your present healthcare insurance?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;* The plan eliminates benefits related to diagnosis or treatment of a particular condition.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;* The plan increases the percentage of a cost-sharing requirement (such as co-insurance) above the level at which it was on March 23, 2010.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;* The plan increases the fixed amount of cost sharing such as deductibles or out-of-pocket limits by a total percentage measured from March 23, 2010, that is more than the sum of medical inflation plus 15 percentage points.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;* The plan increases co-payments as a total percentage measured from March 23, 2010, that is more than the sum of medical inflation plus 15 percentage points or medical inflation plus $5.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;* The employer’s share of the premium decreases more than 5 percentage points below what the share was on March 23, 2010.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The regulations are a done deal. Employers modify healthcare insurance plans every year. It is cheaper to pay a $2,000 per employee penalty than $15,000 a year per employee healthcare insurance premium.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“&lt;i&gt;A White House official said, “This is a draft document, and we will be releasing the final regulation when it is complete. The president made a promise to the American people that if they liked their health care plan, they can keep it. The regulation, when finalized, will uphold that promise.&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Promise-President-Obama-Year-One/dp/1439101191/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1277047508&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Jonathan Alter in his book “The Promise” which is about President Obama’s first year in office quotes him on healthcare&lt;/a&gt;. “&lt;i&gt;President Obama said to a group of Single Party Payer advocates that “they had to deal with the world as it is and not wanted it to be.” &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama is dealing with the world as he is working his way toward how he wants it to be. A government controlled world. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The next step is a single party payer.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Consumers will not have freedom of choice or free access to care. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/-fDmNCPJQUA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/if-you-like-your-insurance-you-can-keep-it-period-president-barack-obama.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Private Healthcare Insurance System Is Broken</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/kMME_10KhWs/the-private-healthcare-insurance-system-is-broken.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/the-private-healthcare-insurance-system-is-broken.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20134846fb2c4970c</id>
        <published>2010-06-16T06:14:10-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-06-16T06:14:10-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE During our father son weekend Brad introduced me to Ian Sigalow. Ian is a 31 year old principle in the venture capital firm Greycroft LLC. He received his BS in Economics from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> </p>  <p>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/father-son-weekend.html">During our father son weekend</a> <a href="http://www.feld.com">Brad</a> introduced me to <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/ian-sigalow">Ian Sigalow.</a> Ian is a 31 year old principle in the venture capital firm Greycroft LLC. He received his BS in Economics from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and an MBA from Columbia University Graduate School of Business. He is a smart fellow.</p>  <p>Ian felt comfortable with the healthcare insurance policy his firm provided him before he got sick. <a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/father-son-weekend.html">At the Lindzonpollosa</a> he told me his horrible story. He has permitted me to repeat it. There are several important points to illustrate the dysfunction of the healthcare system. </p>  <p>There is also a lesson here for President Obama. Government is supposed to be by the people for the people. Government should make the rules that are be fair to consumers of healthcare.</p>  <p>I<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ian-sigalow/the-health-insurance-trap_b_310147.html">an published his story in the Huffington Post</a>. I hope I will give his story a little more publicity.</p>  <p>Ian had never been sick until he was diagnosed with Seminoma at age 29. Seminoma is a type of testicular cancer that affects one percent of males. It is the most common type of cancer among men aged 20 to 35. It is often cured by surgery alone, but advanced disease requires the addition of radiation therapy or chemotherapy. His seminoma had spread to his lymph nodes. He needed to have chemotherapy for a cure. </p>  <p><em>“My insurance provider was </em><a href="https://www.oxhp.com/Member/MemberPortal/"><em>Oxford Healthcare</em></a><em>, a subsidiary of UnitedHealth, the largest private health insurer in the United States.” </em></p>  <p><em>“When it comes to testicular cancer, the Centers of Excellence are Indiana University, which treated Lance Armstrong, and Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSK) in New York.”</em></p>  <p>Sloan-Kettering was not in his Oxford healthcare insurance plan’s network. He couldn’t switch to an upgraded plan because he works for a small business. </p>  <p><em>“Oxford’s better plans are reserved for large employers. I was willing to pay any amount to get in-network access but there were no options. However, I learned that Oxford offers an "in-network exception", where in-network privileges are granted to out-of-network hospitals based on doctor referral. I was told that if three Oxford oncologists referred me to Memorial Sloan Kettering, an in-network exception would be granted.”</em></p>  <p>Oxford supplied him with a list of 300 doctors to call. Many were not in practice anymore and most were not oncologists. This was the situation despite Oxford’s claim to be user friendly. </p>  <p>Ian found ten oncologists in the Oxford network. They all recommended Sloan Kettering based on the advanced stage of his disease. Oxford then reneged on its offer to grant an in-network exception.</p>  <p><em>“Oxford was going to call another set of doctors to see if they could find someone in-network to treat me. I asked the woman from Oxford why I was told to make the calls if Oxford was planning on doing it themselves. Her response was, <b>"We were hoping you wouldn't bother."</b></em></p>  <p>Oxford called a few days later. It was on a Friday afternoon. The representative told him she found three physicians who were willing to meet with him. He was advised by his oncologist that rapid initiation of treatment was important. He had scheduled himself for treatment the following Monday morning at Sloan Kettering. Oxford’s representative knew all this before she called him. </p>  <p>"<em>We cannot tell you not to go to Memorial Sloan Kettering, and we cannot tell you to delay treatment. However, we found three doctors in New York who agreed to meet with you. It will require a new consultation..." and more delay in treatment.</em></p>  <p>The first lesson is of private healthcare insurance abuse in order to save money. This happens countless times a day. Unless you are the victim you would not be aware of the restrictions of access to care. </p>  <p>The state and federal government must paying attention to the consumer abuse. Consumer abuse has been ignored for 20 years. A simple regulation fining Oxford or rescinding its license to sell insurance in the state where the abuse took place would be an effective deterrent to the industry’s restricting access to care. In order to get Oxford's full coverage he would have had to delay his treatment and pay an additional deductible to see three other physicians in consultation to grant permission for an in network exception. </p>  <p><em>“I made the decision to go out-of-network.” </em></p>  <p>After being treated at Sloan Kettering Ian called the three additional doctors Oxford had recommended. They all agreed he made the right decision to go to Sloan Kettering. He also found out from a former Oxford executive that patients with out-of-network benefits are almost never granted an in-network exception. All Oxford was doing was stalling and trying to impose its will on him.</p>  <p>Ian tried to quantify, in advance, the costs of out-of-network as opposed to in-network. It was impossible. Hospital systems do not publish their fees no matter how hard a patient tries he cannot get them.</p>  <p>This defect presents another opportunity for President Obama to Repair the Healthcare System. All that would have to be done is to require hospital systems to publish their fees in order to get certified to treat patients. Instead, President Obama is creating bureaucratic agencies to fix prices. </p>  <p>Ian obtained Oxford’s reimbursement rates for procedures and drugs. He figured his out of pocket expenses would be between $5,000 and $7,000. He was prepared to pay that fee based on his in network benefits. </p>  <p>His final out of pocket expenses bill were $35,000. Hospital systems have multiple negotiated prices. <b>The multiple fees are one of the travesties of the healthcare system.</b> If you are out of network you are responsible for the inflated retail price.</p>  <p>If a hospital system will accept five hundred dollars for a service from a healthcare insurance industry an individual patient out of network should not be responsible for a fifteen hundred dollar retail price for the same treatment and services. There is a total lack of transparency of negotiated prices.</p>  <p>All President Obama would have to do would be to require publication of negotiated prices Transparency would immediately empower consumers. </p>  <p><em>“What surprises many people is that the largest part of the bill was not doctor's fees -- those were only $3,000.”</em></p>  <p>Physicians do not know what hospital systems charge. Hospital systems have lobbied the government to restrict physicians from delivering the chemotherapy in their clinics because the in hospital profit margin is so large. </p>  <p>Why is the government always using physicians as a scapegoat? Physicians are the scapegoat because they are the weakest stakeholder in America’s political system. We lack effective representation. </p>  <p>Ian used the example of drug costs.</p>  <p><em>“One example of how this adds up: I was prescribed three shots of Neulasta, which is a white blood cell booster. At </em><a href="http://drugstore.com"><em>drugstore.com</em></a><em>, a single shot of Neulasta costs $3,500. At Memorial Sloan Kettering, it was $5,600. Oxford's usual and customary reimbursement was $2,600. I didn't have a choice. I was left with $9,000 out of pocket for three shots.”</em></p>  <p>How was the cost of $3,500 at <a href="http://www.drugstore.com">www.drugstore.com</a> calculated? How much did it cost to produce the drug? How do you price R&amp;D for the drug? Why should Sloan Kettering charge $5,600 a shot? Why would a hospital accept $2,600 from Oxford?</p>  <p>There is nothing in President Obama’s healthcare reform bill that deals with this problem. The solution is easy. Develop rules of transparency to price various services and treatments which include all the negotiated prices. </p>  <p>President Obama has chosen to impose prices through price controls and not rules to negotiate prices. </p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/03/a-tale-of-two-states.html">Price controls never work.</a> </p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p>  <p><b /></p>  <p><a name="fb_share"><b /></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/kMME_10KhWs" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/the-private-healthcare-insurance-system-is-broken.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>War On Obesity: Part 16</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/U6rfAmhYDM0/war-on-obesity-part-16.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/war-on-obesity-part-16.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133f0e82001970b</id>
        <published>2010-06-13T05:38:05-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-06-13T05:38:05-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP, MACE The public’s perception is that obesity cannot be cured. In my opinion this is wrong. I received two comments from readers after publishing War on Obesity: Part 15 The first; Dr. Feld Don’t you know that...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="War on Obesity" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP, MACE</p>  <p>The public’s perception is that obesity cannot be cured. In my opinion this is wrong.</p>  <p>I received two comments from readers after publishing <a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/war-on-obesity-part-15.html">War on Obesity: Part 15</a></p>  <p>The first;</p>  <p><i>Dr. Feld</i></p>  <p><i>Don’t you know that Obesity is a genetic disease? No matter what you do people cannot lose weight. If they lose the weight they will gain it back. A genetic disease cannot be cured. </i></p>  <p><i /></p>  <p><i>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus is also a genetic disease. </i></p>  <p><i>Sincerely</i></p>  <p>All obesity is not genetic. There are many diseases, situations that can lead to overeating. The majority of the obesity is due to environment factors.</p>  <p>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus is genetic. At least 25% of Hispanic and Black people have a genetic abnormality making them less sensitive to insulin. (Insulin resistance). Insulin resistance increases as weight increases. </p>  <p>As the insulin resistance increases the person cannot metabolize glucose. Insulin is needed at the cellular level to permit the glucose to pass into the cell. The insulin resistance decreases the effect of insulin to permit this passage.</p>  <p>The person’s cells are starved of energy producing glucose. This causes the person to release stored glucose from the liver in order to overcome the insulin resistance. The very high glucose causes increased urination and increased thirst. The lack of glucose metabolism causes weakness.</p>  <p>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus, the result of obesity causing increasing insulin resistance, can be asymptomatic for an average of 8 years.</p>  <p>The resulting high circulating blood sugar denatures proteins in the body. It causes blood vessels to decrease in diameter. Many people present with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus at the time of a heart attack. Over the eight years of asymptomatic Diabetes Mellitus the blood vessels have been slowly constricting. This can result is a heart attack or stroke. </p>  <p>The hemoglobin molecule is a protein within red blood cells (RBC). RBC’s carries oxygen to the tissues. Hemoglobin molecule with the RBC also gets deformed. It is converted to HbA1c. The measurement of the percentage of HbA1c in the circulation is an estimate of the average blood sugar over a three month period of time. </p>  <p>Each red blood cell lives for 3 months. New RBC’s are born every second. If they are born and live in a high blood sugar they become deformed. The higher the blood sugar the higher the percentage of HbA1c.</p>  <p>Normal Hba1c is up to 6%. The lower the level the less the chance there is for blood vessel narrowing and the lower the risk of complications such as heart attacks and strokes. </p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2006/06/do_complication.html">The cost of Diabetes Mellitus to the healthcare system is $217 billion dollars a year</a>. The challenge is to decrease the incidence of Obesity. Decreasing obesity will decrease the incidence of insulin resistance. In turn the incidence of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus and its complications will decrease. </p>  <p>The only way to decrease obesity is through public education program and advertisement, changes in the fast food industry’s economic incentives, and providing economic incentives to consumers to lose weight.</p>  <p>Consumers must be made to be responsible for themselves.</p>  <p>Decreasing obesity will decrease healthcare costs dramatically. </p>  <p>President Obama should be spending taxpayers’ dollars on this goal and not on pilot studies and bureaucracies destined to fail. </p>  <p>The second comment received illustrates that weight loss can be accomplished. A long time reader responded with the following note to my last blog.</p>  <p>I previously sensed he doubted consumers’ ability to control their own health and healthcare dollars.</p>  <p><em>Dear Dr. Feld</em></p>  <p><em>There is hope.  Yesterday I was at a client’s office when I met an old friend who serves as a security officer for the company. </em></p>  <p><em>I said, “John you look great” and he told me he had lost 85 lbs.  I said “wow that’s awesome”.  When we were away from other folks there I quietly asked him if something had precipitated the change and he said “yes, I was diagnosed as a type II diabetic and when I was diagnosed I had an A1c of 11.0%”.  </em></p>  <p><em>He said “the Dr. wanted to start me on Meds immediately but I said no meds, I want to try diet and exercise first”.  The Dr. was skeptical but let him have 3 months to try diet and exercise.  In the 3 months, John lost 70 lbs and his A1c was 5.5% when he next saw the Dr.  He has since lost 15 more lbs and he is now accountable for his health.</em></p>  <p><em>With no accountability, people will not modify their behavior.  Death is inevitable, the questions that we must answer are:</em></p>  <p><em>1. How much money am I willing to spend on delaying the inevitable?</em></p>  <p><em>2. Whose money is it going to be, mine or someone else’s?</em></p>  <p><em>3. Depending on the answer to question number 2, what’s the effect on the answer to question number 1?</em></p>  <p><em>Cheers,</em></p>  <p><b>It can be done with proper motivation. It is difficult to lose weight. Obesity does not cause symptoms. Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus can be asymptomatic for a long time. This patient did lose weight for his own health. Many people can be helped to lose weight. </b></p>  <p><b /></p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/war-on-obesity-part-15.html">As Ross Carlson said it is a matter of eating less and doing more</a>. <b /></p>  <p>Consumers are bombarded with the stress of daily life. Americans are constantly exposed to anxiety by the popular media. Local murders, national oil spills, two wars, auto accidents, other disasters, the threat of unemployment and increased taxes all heighten our anxiety. </p>  <p>Salty and fatty foods taste good and are cheap. These fast foods help relieve stress. Fast food temporarily ameliorates the epinephrine surge caused by stress.</p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=war+on+obesity&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">If President Obama wanted to solve the rising cost of healthcare he should concentrate on changing the culture of food production and attitudes about eating and exercise.</a></p>  <p>He is giving this essential initiative lip service and little expenditure of money. </p>  <p>He should empower consumers to reverse this impending disaster. </p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p>  <p><b /></p>  <p><a name="fb_share"><b /></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/U6rfAmhYDM0" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/war-on-obesity-part-16.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>War on Obesity: Part 15</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/3-jaXkOgLOA/war-on-obesity-part-15.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/war-on-obesity-part-15.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e2013483a2537b970c</id>
        <published>2010-06-09T06:44:46-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-06-09T06:44:46-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE Cecelia and I went to flea market in North Central Texas on Memorial Day. There was a large crowd. I would estimate that more than 60% of the people were grossly obese and 30% were moderately obese....</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="War on Obesity" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</p>  <p>Cecelia and I went to flea market in North Central Texas on Memorial Day. There was a large crowd. I would estimate that more than 60% of the people were grossly obese and 30% were moderately obese. </p>  <p>There was a long line at the fast food restaurant. </p>  <p><i><a href="http://http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2010/05/06/health-insurance-companies-invest-billions-in-fast-food-chains.aspx">Companies providing life and health insurance own nearly $2 billion worth of stock in the fast-food industry</a>. The investments are in Jack in the Box, McDonald's, Burger King, Wendy’s/Arby’s, and Yum! Brands, which includes KFC, Taco Bell, and Pizza Hut.</i></p>  <p>The life and healthcare insurance industries are not exhibiting the social responsibility they claim. They are in business to make a profit. The fast food industry is a profitable business. Why not invest in it? </p>  <p>President Obama ought to be investing taxpayers’ dollars for healthcare reform in convincing the public to not support the fast food industry.</p>  <p>The appeal of fast food is it is cheaper and more filing than fresh food such as fruits vegetables and chicken and requires no food preparation. The food also contains lots of salt and sugar which appeals to the tastes buds. Excess salt is a contributor to the onset of hypertension and sugar is empty calories.   <table cellpadding="0" border="0"><tbody>       <tr>         <td> </td>       </tr>        <tr>         <td>           <p><i><a href="http://http://www.diabetesincontrol.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=9283&amp;catid=1&amp;Itemid=17">Nearly half of all adults in the US have Type 2 diabetes, hypertension or hypercholesterolemia</a> associated with an increased risk of cardiovascular disease, according to data from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES). </i></p>         </td>       </tr>     </tbody></table> </p>  <p>Obesity is the underlying disorder precipitating these chronic diseases. If the U.S controls obesity it will decrease the incidence of these diseases and its complications. <a href="http://http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/129886.php">The cost of these diseases to the healthcare system is enormous</a>.</p>  <p><i>“<a href="http://http://www.cdc.gov/obesity/causes/economics.html">Obesity and diet-related diseases are in fact far costlier than smoking, and they are just as preventable.</a> </i></p>  <p><i><a href="http://www.cdc.gov/Features/TobaccoControlData/">According to the latest statistics from the CDC</a>, smokers incur health care costs of $96 billion a year in direct medical expenses.</i></p>  <p><i>Meanwhile, the annual <a href="http://www.cdc.gov/media/pressrel/2009/r090727.htm">health care cost of obesity in the US</a> has reached $147 billion, and the <a href="http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/129886.php">medical bills for diabetes</a> are at an estimated $217.5 billion a year! </i></p>  <p><i>Truly, the health care cost of smoking is dwarfed by the medical expenses caused by unhealthy food.</i></p>  <p><i><a href="http://http://www.cdc.gov/media/pressrel/2009/r090727.htm">If you are obese, you will spend an average of 42 percent more on health care than someone of normal weight.</a> This is just one of the reasons why I keep reiterating that someone needs to spend some time in the kitchen to prepare meals.</i></p>  <p><a href="http://http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/healthcare-reform-should-be-about-motivating-self-responsibility-not-dependence.html">In response to my last post on consumer driven healthcare a fellow physician wrote;</a> </p>  <p><i>Hi Stan,</i>    <br /><i>You are assuming that patients, especially, will be willing to admit they might get sick and take steps to prevent it. I can't even get overweight male diabetics to lose weight. All cigarette smokers know that smoking is bad for them. </i></p>  <p>I replied by asking<b> “how much he was paying his overweight male diabetic patient to lose weight.”</b></p>  <p>When will President Obama listen? If he is listening he is not hearing. <a href="http://http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/accountable-care-centers-continued.html">He is spending tons of money on bureaucratic infra structure that will not solve our healthcare problems or the costs incurred by those problems</a> </p>  <p>The problem of obesity can be solved. It will take a societal change of cultural and attitude toward food and exercise. It will take innovative incentives. The ideal medical saving accounts provides that incentive. </p>  <p>The government has to develop incentives, and not penalties for the farm and food industry to reverse the production of obesity producing foodstuffs.</p>  <p>To some of us the incentive to stay healthy is enough. However, it is very difficult to eat healthy with all the advertising and food stimuli coming at us all the time.</p>  <p><a href="http://http://www.foundrygroup.com/">My son Brad’s</a> <a href="http://http://www.foundrygroup.com/">Foundry Group’s</a> chief of technology officer, <a href="http://http://www.jasbone.com/wp/">Ross Carlson, had an epiphany</a>.</p>  <p>I saw Ross Carlson before he started his fitness program (see photo). He told me about his fitness program. </p>  <p><i>“ I’ve been hesitant to write this post for quite a while as it feels rather self-serving.  But as I’m ending phase two of my training program and now entering what I’m calling phase three I figured it was time for a little reflection.</i></p>  <p><strong><i>Phase 1 </i></strong><b><i>       <br /></i></b><i>If you’ve known me for more than 3 years you know I used to be fat.  <b>Hey, let’s not dance around it, I was fat. </b></i></p>  <p><i>Fortunately for me I’d finally had enough and decided to finally get healthy.  This is what I call phase one of my fitness program or really fitness progression.</i></p>  <p><i>  I tend to be fairly obsessive with things I care about and fitness has been no difference.  My first goal was to lose weight – and a lot of weight. </i></p>  <p><i>I did two very simple things to accomplish this: <b><u>I ate significantly less and exercised significantly more</u></b> (that is to say I finally started exercising regularly).  I cut my daily caloric intake to around 1000 calories and added in cardio work, mostly cycling.  I continued on this program for roughly 10 months to reach my first goal.  </i></p>  <p><i>I guess it’s time for some numbers huh?  Wow, these are pretty scary: (I’m 5’11” by the way…)</i></p>  <p><strong><i>Beginning: 235lbs | 40” Waist | 32% body fat | 32.8 BMI </i></strong><b><i>       <br /><strong>Ending: 145lbs | 30” Waist | 8% body fat | 20.2 BMI</strong></i></b><i /></p>  <p><i>So in those first 10 months I lost roughly 90lbs total, 10” off my waist, 65lbs of fat (and 22lbs of muscle).  It was that last stat that made me begin phase 2 about 3 months ago.</i></p>  <p>Phase 2 and 3 are combinations of dynamic fitness training to increase muscle mass and cardiovascular fitness. </p>  <p>The key to exercise is to make fitness a way of life. </p>  <p>The key to decreasing caloric intake is to make eating less a way of life.</p>  <p>The key to weight loss is to exercise and burn more calories than you eat. </p>  <p>Nothing is new in the laws of thermodynamics. The patient must be responsible to and for themselves. </p>  <p><strong><i>Final Thoughts </i></strong><b><i>       <br /></i></b><i>I plan on blogging more regularly about this subject now that I’ve finally published this post.  I hope to write about thoughts on eating, exercising, and my journey through all this.  If you’ve got questions or comments please let me know, they can be very motivating.  And if you’re considering doing something similar to this START NOW.  There is no better day than today to be healthy.</i></p>  <p><i>Oh, and now to leave you with a picture that I’m still scared by.  Left is old, Fat Ross.  Middle is thin Ross from about 3 years ago.  Finally on the right is me a few days ago.  Just wait until you see me in 90 more days.</i></p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e20133f078d6fe970b-pi"><img title="clip_image002[4]" style="border-right: 0px; border-top: 0px; display: inline; border-left: 0px; border-bottom: 0px" height="402" alt="clip_image002[4]" src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013483a25370970c-pi" width="536" border="0" /></a></p>  <p>Hooray for Ross. Nice job. I am very proud of you.</p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p>  <p><b /></p>  <p><a name="fb_share"><b /></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/3-jaXkOgLOA" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/war-on-obesity-part-15.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Healthcare Reform Should Be About Motivating Self-Responsibility Not Dependence</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/xembZ6dwoMs/healthcare-reform-should-be-about-motivating-self-responsibility-not-dependence.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/healthcare-reform-should-be-about-motivating-self-responsibility-not-dependence.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133f03a3b9f970b</id>
        <published>2010-06-06T08:14:05-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-06-06T08:14:05-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D,FACP,MACE Last week I heard a lecture about Accountable Care Organizations by a physician leader working for one of the major hospital systems. His discussion made me realize that large physician organizations and hospitals are spending lots of...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicaid" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicare" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Summary Blogs" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Universal Healthcare" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> Stanley Feld M.D,FACP,MACE</p>  <p>Last week I heard a lecture about <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=accountable+care+organizations&amp;x=19&amp;y=10">Accountable Care Organizations</a> by a physician leader working for one of the major hospital systems.</p>  <p>His discussion made me realize that large physician organizations and hospitals are spending lots of time solving problems of <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=accountable+care+organizations&amp;x=19&amp;y=10">quality medical care. In my opinion quality medical care has not been adequately defined.</a> </p>  <p>A working definition right now is to decrease hospital stays, efficient medical care for a disease at lower cost, avoidance of medical errors in the hospital, and avoidance of hospital acquired infections. </p>  <p>These are important goals. They must be attached to monetary incentives. Many of these problems can be solved now. The solution demands the development of processes of care. An important question is how much money will process improvement save? I estimate that this process improvement could save an estimated 7 to 10% of the healthcare dollar. </p>  <p>The real question should be focused on how to repair the healthcare system by decreasing costs while improving the health of Americans.</p>  <p>This problem is not only about hospitals and medical practices reimbursement. It is about problems created by all the stakeholders. It is about aligning all the stakeholders’ incentives. The solutions to the healthcare system’s dysfunction must be initiated at the same time. You cannot try to fix one problem because it will result in a problem getting worse in another area. </p>  <p>The key to the solutions is to <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=consumer+driven+healthcare&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">incentivize consumers of healthcare to control their health and be in charge of their healthcare dollars</a>. Consumers can force secondary stakeholders to adjust swiftly to their demands and make them compete for consumers’ healthcare dollars.</p>  <p>Consumers must have incentive. They should be able to keep anything they do not spend of the first $7500 dollars of healthcare coverage. In our present healthcare system consumers do not control their healthcare dollars. They get first dollar coverage with variable deductible expenses. If the deductible is too high they will avoid necessary care and medications. </p>  <p>Society should not want that to happen because patients will get sicker and cost more to treat. Third party payers control the healthcare dollar. This control has contributed to increase the cost of healthcare. . </p>  <p>Some claim the only incentive consumers (patients) should need is to maintain their health. This claim has turned out not to be true. </p>  <p>Where do all the healthcare dollars go? </p>  <p>1. 65% of each healthcare dollar goes to the healthcare insurance industry for overhead for administrative services and insurance reserves whether it is private or government insurance.</p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e20133f03a3b72970b-pi"><img title="image" style="border-right: 0px; border-top: 0px; display: inline; border-left: 0px; border-bottom: 0px" height="223" alt="image" src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013483640c84970c-pi" width="350" border="0" /></a> </p>  <p>2. Only 35% of the healthcare dollar is actually spent on medical care.</p>  <p>3. 80% of the healthcare dollars spent for medical care is spent by 20% of the people.</p>  <p>4. Most of those 20% have chronic diseases.</p>  <p>5. <a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2006/06/do_complication.html">80% of those dollars are spent on the complications of their chronic diseases.</a> </p>  <p>6. Some claim there is 40% waste in the healthcare system due to uncoordinated care and duplication of care. </p>  <p>7. <a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2009/04/president-obama-if-you-really-want-to-reduce-healthcare-costs-effectively-reform-the-medical-malpractice-tort-system-part-1.html">Much of the excess testing is due to the fear of malpractice claims and the practice of defensive medicine</a>. </p>  <p>Let us follow the healthcare dollars with consumers being in control of their healthcare dollar. </p>  <p>If a moderate size company of 67 employees were willing to pay $15,000 dollars per employee for healthcare insurance it would cost $1,000,000 dollars. If the employer did not provide healthcare insurance the government penalty ($2,000 per employee) would be $134,000 dollars. This would represent a savings to this moderate sized company of $866,000 dollars per year. It would be the logical path to take. The formula I propose will work for the individual buying insurance.</p>  <p>Assume employers were willing to buy healthcare insurance for their employees. They would put $7,500 per year in a trust for each employee. The employee would be responsible for his healthcare dollars. The fees would be pre-negotiated fees by the government as the healthcare insurance industry does presently with physicians and hospitals. Hospitals and physicians might even want to compete among each other for the consumers’ dollars. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=ideal+medical+savings+account&amp;x=14&amp;y=12">If the employee did not spend all the healthcare dollars in a year the remaining dollars would go into his retirement fund. It would not be used for future medical care.</a> </p>  <p>A new equation for driving healthcare costs would be born. </p>  <p>There would not be a 65% overhead for administrative services for the first $7500 dollars because the healthcare insurance industry would not be administering the first $7500 dollars. The savings would be $4875 dollars. </p>  <p>Patients and physicians would have an additional $4875 dollars working toward direct medical care. The 65% overhead for administrative services for the remaining $7,500 of high deductible coverage could remain the same. The high deductible insurance would provide first dollar coverage after $7,500. The risk to the healthcare insurance industry would be less and so its insurance reserves could be less. </p>  <p>The government pays the same amount for administrative services to the healthcare insurance industry. The government could use the same formula for Medicare and Medicaid. </p>  <p>Consumers would have a monetary incentive to decrease their risk of getting sick (preventing obesity and increasing exercise). If consumers drove the healthcare system the consumption of snack foods and fast foods would decrease with proper education. Those fast food companies would be forced to sell healthy food to stay in business. Consumer would be driven by monetary incentives to stay healthy. </p>  <p>The onset of chronic disease would decrease. The complications of chronic disease would also decrease.</p>  <p>If a patient had a chronic disease at the onset of this new system and controlled their disease well in order to avoid acute and chronic complications of the chronic disease the healthcare system could reward them with a bonus at the end of the year. They would avoid costly hospitalizations. </p>  <p>Consumers would demand and pay to be properly educated to avoid complications of their chronic disease</p>  <p>An added benefit is that there would be less doctor visits and hospitalizations. This would increase healthcare capacity. It would enable the country to provide care for the entire population rather that force the healthcare system to absorb additional patients and create shortages resulting in rationing and decreasing access to care. </p>  <p>When people are motive by monetary incentives they are innovative. Innovation stimulates efficiency and decreases costs. It is important to have consumers be responsible for themselves and not dependent on the government. </p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/xembZ6dwoMs" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/healthcare-reform-should-be-about-motivating-self-responsibility-not-dependence.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Small Business Associations And Individuals Joins State Lawsuit Against President Obamas Healthcare Reform Bill</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/1L5f6bKdYqQ/small-business-associations-and-individuals-joins-state-lawsuit-against-president-obamas-healthcare-reform-bill.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/small-business-associations-and-individuals-joins-state-lawsuit-against-president-obamas-healthcare-reform-bill.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e2013482cb6377970c</id>
        <published>2010-06-02T08:04:59-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-06-02T08:04:59-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE President Obama has tried to marginalize the law suits filed by 20 states concerning the constitutionality of his healthcare reform bill. President Obama has the power of the pulpit. He also has the traditional media helping him....</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><b>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</b></p>  <p> </p>  <p>President Obama has tried to marginalize the law suits filed by 20 states concerning the constitutionality of his healthcare reform bill. President Obama has the power of the pulpit. He also has the traditional media helping him.</p>  <p>There are two main issues with these legal challenges:</p>  <ol>   <li>Is the mandate to force citizens to buy healthcare insurance constitutional?</li>    <li>Is the nationalization of healthcare a constitutional infringement on States rights?</li> </ol>  <p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/05/15/health/policy/15lawsuit.html?emc=tnt&amp;tntemail1=y">The lawsuits against the Obama administration have come from 20 State Attorney Generals, plus physicians’ groups and constitutional legal centers.</a> An attempt has been made by the administration marginalize each lawsuit without much explanation.</p>  <p>It is difficult for the average citizens to understand the merits of the challenge. President Obama and his staff keep telling us the bill will reduce the cost of healthcare. It will be good for everyone. President Obama says he has been assured by legal counsel that the bill is constitutional. </p>  <p>Two weeks ago the National Federation of Independent Businesses filed an amended complaint to the lawsuit originally filed by 13 states. </p>  <p>“<em>In addition <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/05/15/health/policy/15lawsuit.html?emc=tnt&amp;tntemail1=y">two individuals also joined the litigation.</a> One is the uninsured owner of an automobile repair shop in Panama City, Fla. The other is a man from Washington State who prefers to pay his medical bills out of pocket rather than being compelled to obtain insurance, as will be the case starting in 2014.”</em></p>  <p>President Obama’s administration claims the lawsuits are a political ploy by Republicans. The administration has stated it will challenge the law suits on their legal standings and authority. </p>  <p>Dan Danner, president and CEO of the National Federation of Independent Business (NFIB), a nonprofit, nonpartisan organization that works to promote and protect the rights of small businesses to own, operate and grow their businesses wrote;</p>  <p>“<em><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704113504575264802756326086.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h">We also believe the health-care law is unconstitutional.</a></em> </p>  <p><em>The centerpiece of this law is an individual mandate requiring virtually all Americans to purchase health insurance or pay a fine. </em></p>  <p><em>We strongly believe that the Commerce Clause of the Constitution does not give Congress the power to force individuals to purchase a private product or face a fine. </em></p>  <p><b><em>Requiring individuals to purchase something simply because they are alive is unprecedented.”</em></b></p>  <p>President Obama’s lawyers’ response to the constitutional challenge is it is a political ploy to tarnish the healthcare reform bill. </p>  <p>In court filings the administration has claimed that an individual decision to not purchase insurance is, in effect, a decision about how to pay for future medical care. Taken in the aggregate, those decisions substantially affect interstate commerce by shifting the cost of covering the uninsured to policy-holders, health care providers and taxpayers. </p>  <p>This is a lame argument. </p>  <p>Individual businesses have realized that President Obama’s healthcare bill will dramatically raise health-care costs rather than lower costs. This will increase the overall cost of doing business. There is a built in bias against small businesses.</p>  <p>What's more, the federal mandate requiring that nearly all U.S. residents carry health insurance by 2014 seriously threatens our basic constitutional rights and individual freedoms.</p>  <p>The government cost estimates are already rising. </p>  <p><em>“<a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704113504575264802756326086.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h">According to the Congressional Budget Office (CBO), the overhaul will cost about $115 billion more</a> than first projected, bringing the total to more than $1 trillion.” </em></p>  <p>One trillion dollars does not even come close to the real and hidden costs of President Obama’s healthcare reform bill. The bill is not a healthcare reform bill. It is a way of centralizing federal power over individual rights. </p>  <p><a name="U30860807981uyD" />President Obama has said the law will significantly help small businesses. He continually focuses on the small business tax credit. In reality the tax credit is not real.</p>  <p><em>“<a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704113504575264802756326086.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h">The reality is that the tax credit is complex and very limited</a> because firms qualify based on number of employees and average wages.</em></p>  <p><em>The credit, which is only available for a maximum of six years, puts small business owners through a series of complicated "tests" to determine if they qualify and how much they will receive. </em></p>  <p><em>Fewer than one-third of small businesses even pass the first three (of four) tests to qualify: have 25 employees or less, provide health insurance, and pay 50% of the cost of that insurance.” </em></p>  <p><em>“More importantly, the credit is temporary, but health-care cost increases are permanent. When the credit ends, small businesses will be left paying full price. They'll also be forced to deal with all sorts of new taxes, fees and mandates buried in this 2,000-page law.”</em></p>  <p>One hidden tax is the healthcare insurance industry fee of $8 billion (that escalates to $14.3 billion by 2018) on insurance companies based on its market share. The fee will be passed on to employers in high premiums. </p>  <p><b>This tax will be paid almost exclusively by small businesses and individuals. The law specifically excludes self-insured plans. Most large corporations and labor union are self insured and will avoid this tax. </b></p>  <p>President Obama said his healthcare reform bill is going to “go after” the healthcare insurance industry’s grotesque profits. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/05/16/health/policy/16health.html?ref=health">The healthcare insurance industry is lining up to help the government write the new rules and regulations.</a> </p>  <p>The rules they are helping write will permit the healthcare insurance industry to <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/05/16/health/policy/16health.html?ref=health">load its expenses as it has done previously</a>.</p>  <p>With the business association and individual plaintiffs joining the lawsuit public perception might shift from the lawsuit being primarily a political device as President Obama has tried to emphasize to this lawsuit being a serious constitutional and states’ rights issue.</p>  <p><strong>America wake up!</strong> </p>  <p>President Obama’s healthcare reform bill is a very expensive law. It will not decrease the cost of healthcare or increase the quality of healthcare.</p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/1L5f6bKdYqQ" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/06/small-business-associations-and-individuals-joins-state-lawsuit-against-president-obamas-healthcare-reform-bill.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Medical Care Must Not Be A Commodity</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/0obtSPBdQUk/medical-care-must-not-be-a-commodity.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/medical-care-must-not-be-a-commodity.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e2013482859e63970c</id>
        <published>2010-05-30T09:46:02-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-05-30T09:46:02-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE President Obama is creating a new bureaucratic agency. It is called the Independent Payment Advisory Board. The Independent Payment Advisory Board will not be measuring clinical judgment or patient compliance when judging the effectiveness of treatment. Its...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Pay for Performance (P4P)" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</p>  <p>President Obama is creating a new bureaucratic agency. It is called the Independent Payment Advisory Board. The Independent Payment Advisory Board will not be measuring clinical judgment or patient compliance when judging the effectiveness of treatment. Its measurement will be physician compliance with evidence based medicine. <a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/president-obama-please-re-examine-your-premises.html">President Obama, please reexamine your premises.</a></p>  <p> </p>  <p>I am in favor of clinical practice guidelines and evidence based medicine. However, both should be used as an educational tool for physicians and not as a punitive tool to judge payment.</p>  <p>The USPHTF will determine the evidence based medicine to be used. <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=USPHTF&amp;x=12&amp;y=7">I have pointed out the deficiencies in the USPHTF in the past.</a> </p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/president-obama-please-re-examine-your-premises.html">This bureaucracy is an attempt by the government to commoditize medical care.</a> Once medical care is commoditized the cost for medical care is suppose to decrease. </p>  <p>Intensive control of the blood sugar for Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus can be expensive in the short run. If intensive control decreases the complications of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus it can decrease costs in the long term. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.diabetesincontrol.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=9287&amp;catid=1&amp;Itemid=17">The conclusion of the ACCORD study was intensive control was not worth the cost of medical care in the short term or long term. After the data was reexamined it turned out that the ACCORD conclusions were incorrect.</a></p>  <p><i>“It was not hypoglycemia from intensive control or intensive control itself that caused the increased deaths in the ACCORD study.”</i></p>  <p><b><i /></b><b>Unfortunately, this information was not being reported on every TV station as the original study results were. </b>The original study results set back universal use of intensive control of Type 2 Diabetes at least a decade.</p>  <p><i>“ It was important to say that in the intensive group it really was not the people with lower A<sub>1c</sub> who had problems, it actually was those who had the higher A<sub>1c</sub> who, despite intense efforts, we couldn't get under control."</i></p>  <p>This means patients did not comply with their responsibility to intensively control their chronic disease or their physicians did not teach them to control their blood sugar adequately. </p>  <p>"<i>This reexamination gives a stronger momentum to the idea that we need to be thinking that one size doesn't fit all, we need to have different targets for different groups of people and perhaps different treatment strategies to reach those different targets as well. That's troubling both clinically and to the trialist.”</i></p>  <p><i /><i>"This is something of a new idea, because previously there has been a strong impetus to having standardized guidelines for doctors and people with diabetes, but it's probably not the right thing to do.”</i></p>  <p>The reader can sense the discomfort of the academic physicians. They are realizing they cannot commoditize medical treatment. Ask any experienced practicing physician about their patients. Patients have different attitudes about their disease and treatment.</p>  <p>Each patient has to be related to differently. This is clinical judgment. Physicians communicating with their patients is called the physician patient relationships. Patients should be responsible for their outcomes along with physicians. This is the art of medicine. Neither patient nor physician can be treated as a commodity. </p>  <p>President Obama, I hope you are listening. Medical care is difficult to commoditize. </p>  <p>The ACCORD study originally suggested that the goal to normalize the HbA1c resulted in an increase in cardiovascular deaths. It turned out not to be true.</p>  <p>On the other hand an observational study was just published concluding that the lower the HbA1c the lower the complication risk.</p>  <p><i>“<a href="http://www.diabetesincontrol.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=9285&amp;catid=1&amp;Itemid=17">The Atherosclerosis Risk in Communities (ARIC) study is a community-based assessment of 11,092 middle-aged adults</a> in four US communities with normal HbA1c were followed for up to 15 years (4 visits at about 3-year intervals) for onset of new diabetes, new CVD, stroke, and all-cause mortality.” </i></p>  <p>The higher the HbA1c the higher the average blood sugar and the greater the risk for chronic complications of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus. HbA1c is a measure of the average blood sugar over the previous three months.</p>  <h3 />  <h3 />  <h3 />  <p><b>Table. HbA1c Levels and Corresponding Multivariate Hazard Ratios</b>    <table cellspacing="1" cellpadding="0" border="1"><tbody>       <tr>         <td valign="bottom">           <p><b>HbA1c Level</b></p>         </td>          <td valign="bottom">           <p><b>Multivariate-Adjusted Hazard Ratio</b></p>         </td>       </tr>        <tr>         <td valign="top">           <p>&lt; 5%</p>         </td>          <td valign="top">           <p>0.52 (0.40-0.69)</p>         </td>       </tr>        <tr>         <td valign="top">           <p>5% to &lt; 5.5%</p>         </td>          <td valign="top">           <p>1.00 (reference)</p>         </td>       </tr>        <tr>         <td valign="top">           <p>5.5% to &lt; 6%</p>         </td>          <td valign="top">           <p>1.86 (1.67-2.08)</p>         </td>       </tr>        <tr>         <td valign="top">           <p>6% to &lt; 6.5%</p>         </td>          <td valign="top">           <p>4.48 (3.92-5.13)</p>         </td>       </tr>        <tr>         <td valign="top">           <p>≥ 6.5%</p>         </td>          <td valign="top">           <p>16.47 (14.22-19.08)</p>         </td>       </tr>     </tbody></table> </p>  <p><em>HbA1c = hemoglobin A1c</em><em /></p>  <p><i>“The hazard ratios for stroke were similar, but for all-cause mortality, HbA1c displayed a J-shaped association curve. All associations remained significant after adjustment for the baseline FPG.”</i></p>  <p>The study found HbA1c values predicted Cardiovascular Disease (CVD) or death, whereas fasting plasma glucose (FPG) levels were not significant after adjustment for other risk factors.</p>  <p><i>“The recent ADVANCE [Action in Diabetes and Vascular Disease: Preterax and Diamicron MR Controlled Evaluation], ACCORD [Action to Control Cardiovascular Risk in Diabetes], and VADT [Veterans Affairs Diabetes Trial] trials <b>left us wondering about the value of tight glycemic control in reducing CVD risk.</b>” </i></p>  <p><i>“One of the many shortcoming of each of these trials was that most participants had had diabetes for many years, and the designs could not account for the long-term accumulation of glycemic burden.”</i></p>  <p>The authors claim that the vascular damage from high HbA1c may have already occurred. Tight control during the trials might have had relatively little effect. This is probably not true.</p>  <p>There is evidence that normalizing the blood glucose can lead to regression of the vascular lesions that cause the complications of Diabetes. </p>  <p><i>The current ARIC analysis demonstrates that higher HbA1c levels, even in the normal range, increase CVD risk.</i></p>  <p>These results are not conclusive because it is an observational study as opposed to a double blind placebo controlled study. The USPHTF and President Obama’s Independent Payment Advisory Board would not give this study as much credit as the ACCORD study. </p>  <p>The ACCORD study was a placebo controlled double blind study. Its conclusions have more power than an observational study (ARIC). The problem is ACCORD measured the wrong endpoint. ACCORD has resulted in a great disservice to the standard of medical care of diabetes. </p>  <p><a href="N Engl J Med.  2010; 362(9):800-11 ">The results of The Atherosclerosis Risk in Communities (ARIC) study suggest</a> that maintaining a HbA1c as near normal as possible even before the onset of diabetes may help prevent CVD. </p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/is-evidence-based-medicine-based-medicine-the-holy-grail.html">As President Obama tries to quantify the standard of care he could be picking the wrong standard of care in order to reduce the cost of medical care.</a> All medicine is local. Standards of care are always evolving. The standard of medical care should be determined by local medical leaders respected as teachers by local practitioners. It can also be enforced by local peer review with no monetary interest in the outcome. </p>  <p>President Obama’s effort to improve medical care at a reduced price will not succeed if it is interpreted as a punitive measure by a national bureaucra</p>  <p><em /></p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/0obtSPBdQUk" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/medical-care-must-not-be-a-commodity.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Father Son Weekend</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/sNhglUAXCPo/father-son-weekend.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/father-son-weekend.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133eee37cda970b</id>
        <published>2010-05-26T18:58:32-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-05-26T19:02:20-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE In 2006 Brad suggested I write a blog since I had so many ideas about Repairing the Healthcare System. In the course of writing the blog Brad and I decided to write about each other occasionally. We...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Life's Experiences" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> </p>  <p>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</p>  <p>In 2006 <a href="www.feld.com">Brad</a> suggested I write a blog since I had so many ideas about Repairing the Healthcare System.</p>  <p>In the course of writing the blog Brad and I decided to write about each other occasionally. We have done a <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=father+and+son&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">Father and Son Weekend</a> for a number of years. </p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013482138d8a970c-pi"><img title="Brad in NYT" style="border-right: 0px; border-top: 0px; display: inline; border-left: 0px; border-bottom: 0px" height="331" alt="Brad in NYT" src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013482138da1970c-pi" width="234" border="0" /></a> </p>  <p>This year we spent our Father Son Weekend in San Diego. We have no goal. We simply hang out. Every year I come home invigorated. </p>  <p>We went to Coronado because Coronado is the “World Headquarters” of <a href="http://howardlindzon.com/">Howard Lindzon’s</a> Stockwits.com. </p>  <p>Last year <a href="www.studio7310.com">Cecelia</a> and I meet Howard in Phoenix two years. Brad has invested in a few of Howard’s companies. Howard is a guy who has an idea a minute. He is a vibrant personality. He never stops churning. <a href="www.stockwits.com">His vibrancy can be seen on  video feeds</a>. Stockwits tag line is Real Investors, Real Ideas, Real Time. </p>  <p>This year is the year of Howard’s first annual LindzonPaloza. He invited 45 venture capitalist, investors, and entrepreneurs from all over the country and me to the LindzonPaloza. Forty four people showed up. </p>  <p>I was invited because I am Brad Feld’s Dad.</p>  <p>What is a LindzonPaloza? It is a Meet and Greet sponsored by Social Leverage one of Howard’s companies. “Social Leverage’s” tagline is Invest, Syndicate. And Grow.</p>  <p>I was hanging out with some of the brightest people in the world. All were under the age of 45. I learned about their views of the world, their attitudes and impressions of the future.</p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013482138a07970c-pi"><img title="Brad vigulucii 2010" style="border-right: 0px; border-top: 0px; display: inline; border-left: 0px; border-bottom: 0px" height="262" alt="Brad vigulucii 2010" src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e20133eee37cc3970b-pi" width="307" border="0" /></a> </p>  <p>Let me tell you folks, their view is a very optimistic view of the world.</p>  <p>Everyone had at least two smart phones. During lunch on Friday part of the discussion was which was the best smart phone. Brad had just been on a couple of panels at the <a href=" http://code.google.com/events/io/2010/sessions.html">I/O Google conference</a>. Google sent him a Droid with an Android OS 2.1 before the conference and gave him an EVO Android 2.1 at the conference. One guy had Incredible Android 2.1. Everyone had an IPhone. </p>  <p>I concluded from the smart phone discussions that Apple had better watch out. Steve Jobs’ party is almost over. He will not be able to play catch up. It had Sprint since 1982. I quit Sprint 2 years ago because they did not have an adequate smart phone. </p>  <p>I think I am going back to Sprint as soon as the EVO with Android 2.2 is released. This is just one of the many things I learned over the weekend. </p>  <p>Most fascinating was the many philosophies of venture capitalist investing. These guys have big ideas. They are all smart and articulate. They are going to revolutionize our existence. The different philosophies were directly related to the differences in personality. </p>  <p>After lunch we wandered over to Howard’s Stockwits Headquarters. <a href="http://www.stocktwits.tv/stocktwits-with-brad-feld-052510/ ">Howard interviewed Brad on Stockwits for 30 minutes</a>. </p>  <p>Howard talked us into spending some time     shooting the breeze on the patio at the del Coronado. I stuck close to Brad all weekend learned a lot from him. </p>  <p>Howard continued the Meet Up with hors d’ouerves and wine on the patio. My brother, <a href="http://www.feldgroup.com/">Charlie Feld</a>, and I were concerned that healthy people between the ages of 40-55 were not interested in President Obama’s healthcare proposals.</p>  <p>I had a chance to pitch my views. Brad and Howard made the introduction about healthcare to get me started. I was pleased that most of these guys were very concerned. . </p>  <p>At 6pm PDT it was either eating with the group or on your own. It was time for the famous Feld Men’s nap. The timing was just right. I was 4 pm Dallas time. A fifteen minute snooze and we were all set for dinner. </p>  <p>Neither Brad nor I remembered that we were scheduled to eat at <a href="http://www.vigiluccis.com/">Vigilucci’s</a> on Saturday night. We had Friday dinner together at Vigilucci’s. </p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013482138a1e970c-pi"><img title="stan in california" style="border-right: 0px; border-top: 0px; display: inline; border-left: 0px; border-bottom: 0px" height="307" alt="stan in california" src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e20133eee37cd2970b-pi" width="195" border="0" /></a> If you’re in Coronado for dinner go to Vigilucci’s. Brad and I spoke about life, the past and the future for two and a half hours. <b>Love that boy!</b></p>  <p>At nine o’clock we split to go to our separate rooms. I think I was asleep by nine fifteen. Saturday morning I jogged at 7 am along the bayside. Brad and I were going to meet for breakfast at 9 a.m. It was cold in San Diego. I had a windbreaker and hat on and was shivering. Brad didn’t show up at nine. He was swimming in the pool. He didn’t wake up until 9. I tried to get his attention while he was swimming but he was in a zone. </p>  <p>We finally went to breakfast at 10.30 a.m. <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/claytons-coffee-shop-coronado">Clayton’s Diner was packed</a>. We had at least a 25 minute wait. We decided to have chocolate ice cream at <a href=" http://www.yelp.com/biz/moo-time-creamery---hotel-del-coronado-coronado">Moo Time Creamery</a> before breakfast. Chocolate ice cream before breakfast is not a bad idea.</p>  <p>We finished breakfast at noon and hurried back to the “del” to meet up with anyone that wanted to go to Iron Man 2 with us. <a href="http://www.techstars.org/mentors/dcohen/">David Cohen</a>  and <a href=" http://learntoduck.com/ ">Micah Baldwin</a> were the only people interested. </p>  <p>The taxi took us somewhere in San Diego. Iron Man 2 is a campy movie. It must be seen with the right attitude. The movie held my attention. I slept only for ten minutes.</p>  <p>LindzonPaloza is a Meet-Up. We went back to the “del” patio to continue discussions after the movies.</p>  <p>Next event was a group dinner at Vigilucci’s. I thought I met and spoke to everyone. I was wrong. I kept meeting additional intelligent, critical thinkers. They were all 25 to 35 years my junior. I think America will be in good hands. They all know what’s going on. </p>  <p>Howard threw a spectacular Meet Up. I thank him for letting me participate. Many people were leaving on Sunday morning. Howard told us to meet him at 9 am in the Coffee Shop on Orange. Neither Brad nor I had the vaguest idea where the Coffee Shop was located but we figured we would be smart enough to find it. We got lost because we were talking so much. </p>  <p>I had a great weekend. </p>  <p>Everyone should spend at least one weekend a year alone with their kid. I guarantee it will be invigorating.</p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/sNhglUAXCPo" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/father-son-weekend.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Is Evidence Based Medicine Based Medicine The Holy Grail?</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/rh5-ylnsmYs/is-evidence-based-medicine-based-medicine-the-holy-grail.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/is-evidence-based-medicine-based-medicine-the-holy-grail.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ee4baea4970b</id>
        <published>2010-05-23T06:27:39-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-05-23T06:27:39-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP, MACE “Reanalysis of an ACCORD study refutes link between intensive therapy, higher death risk from Cardiovascular Disease” Most of my readers know I am a retired Clinical Endocrinologist. I practiced Clinical Endocrinology for 30 years. I do...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><b>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP, MACE</b></p>  <p><i><a href="http://www.diabetesincontrol.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=9287&amp;catid=1&amp;Itemid=17">“Reanalysis of an ACCORD study refutes link between intensive therapy, higher death risk from Cardiovascular Disease”</a></i></p>  <p>Most of my readers know I am a retired Clinical Endocrinologist. I practiced Clinical Endocrinology for 30 years. I do not have a billfold interest in the healthcare system. My goal is to influence policy makers to develop a healthcare system that will work and decrease costs. </p>  <p>During my practice of Clinical Endocrinology I became involved in Clinical Research. My involvement forced me to understand the nuances of clinical statistics. I gained an appreciation of the defects of statistical analysis in clinical research.</p>  <p>When I was Vice President, President elect and then President of the American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists I was Chairman of AACE’s Diabetes Guidelines. I also co-chaired the guidelines for Thyroid Disease, Thyroid Nodules, and Thyroid Cancer. </p>  <p>The process of writing the guidelines increased my appreciation for both excellent and shabby clinical research.</p>  <p>T<a href="http://www.aace.com/pub/pdf/guidelines/DMGuidelines2002.pdf">he AACE Diabetes Guidelines are a “System of Intensive Diabetes Self-Management for Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus.”</a> Clinical endocrinologist knew that in order to avoid the complications of diabetes mellitus, patients had to be taught how to manage their disease. It was a team approach. Patients had to be taught by physicians and their healthcare teams to be responsible for their day to day blood sugar control. </p>  <p>The AACE Diabetes guidelines were an outline of a process of care. Over the last 15 years many new oral drugs have been introduced to control blood sugar in Type 2 Diabetes. The concept of patients’ responsibility for the self management of their disease must not be de-emphasized. </p>  <p><strong>Patient responsibility has not been included in President Obama’s healthcare reform bill.</strong> </p>  <p>In the last few years there have been studies that have discredited the concept that normalizing the blood sugar would decrease diabetes complications. <a href="http://www.diabetesincontrol.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=9287&amp;catid=1&amp;Itemid=17">One such study was a study call ACCORD “The Action to Control Cardiovascular Risk in Diabetes”. The study found patients in the intensive control of blood sugar group had a higher mortality from Coronary Artery Disease than patients in the control group.</a> </p>  <p>This conclusion was counterintuitive to previous evidence, evidence I believed to be statistically significant. However, I understood the defects in Accord’s statistical analysis at publication. The journal referees did not pick up the defects</p>  <p>The media publicized the findings undermining the significance of the progress in the culture change toward tight blood sugar control in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus. Patients were confused. They decreased their effort to normalize their blood sugar. </p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2007/06/womens_health_i.html">I wrote extensively about the defects in the statistical analysis of the Women’s Health Initiative (WHI). My critique fell on deaf ears. None of the finding in the WHI were statistically significant.</a></p>  <p>The conclusion that estrogen therapy was dangerous to women’s health was misguided. The costly NIH study was poorly designed and did not prove there is an increased incidence of complications statistically.</p>  <p>It might be that estrogen therapy is dangerous to the health of women. This study did not prove it in a statistically significant way. </p>  <p>The study did change the course of women’s health in this country forever. None of the academic leaders spoke out to refute the study statistically. </p>  <p>The WHI is the Holy Grail for evidence based medicine in women’s health. I think the WHI has been a setback in treatment for post menopausal women 50 years and older. </p>  <p>The Accord study has been a setback for the concept of intensive self management and tight blood sugar control for Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus.</p>  <p>President Obama’s healthcare reform bill is in the process of creating bureaucratic review boards that determine the standards of evidence based medicine. </p>  <p>Some clinical studies are excellent and should set the standard for evidence based medicine. It should be the way physicians practice. President Obama’s boards should be educational boards for physicians. Instead they will be punitive boards focused on reducing reimbursement.</p>  <p>Some evidence based medicine is shabby, poorly designed, and not statistically significant. Those studies conclusions should not be forced on the practicing medical community.</p>  <p><i>“<a href="http://www.diabetesincontrol.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=9287&amp;catid=1&amp;Itemid=17">The Action to Control Cardiovascular Risk in Diabetes (ACCORD) study was abruptly halted in 2008</a> when researchers noticed an increase in deaths in the group of Type 2 diabetics being intensively treated to bring their blood sugar levels down to near-normal levels.”</i></p>  <p><strong>Termination of the study received wide coverage by the traditional media. No one critiqued the design of the study or the reasons for its statistical outcome. </strong></p>  <p>Two years later the investigators have realized the errors in the study.</p>  <p><em>“ <a href="http://www.diabetesincontrol.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=9287&amp;catid=1&amp;Itemid=17">A new analysis of data from that study has concluded</a> that a rapid lowering of blood sugar (glucose) levels was not the cause of the increased risk of mortality.</em></p>  <p><em>However, even though the researchers were able to exclude intensive diabetes management from their list of suspects, they still aren't clear what factors may have played a role.”</em></p>  <p>I applaud study author Dr. Matthew Riddle, a professor of medicine at Oregon Health and Science University in Portland, for further analyzing the data.</p>  <p><em>"The original question underlying the study was, </em></p> <a href="http://www.diabetesincontrol.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=9287&amp;catid=1&amp;Itemid=17"><em>would rapid lowering of blood glucose be an explanation for the excess mortality rates?"      <br />"The answer was no.</em></a>   <p><em>People who rapidly lowered their A1c didn't have excess deaths," Riddle said. In fact, "it was the ones who couldn't bring their A1c's down that had increased mortality."</em></p>  <p>This is the way errors in clinical research findings have been discovered in the past. </p>  <p>President Obama’s quest to reduce government spending will result in decisions about evidence based medicine made by bureaucratic panels before the data is tested and retested. My fear is the standards of care will be changed to reflect new evidence too swiftly. The change will be to the detriment of advances in patient care.</p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/rh5-ylnsmYs" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/is-evidence-based-medicine-based-medicine-the-holy-grail.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What Is A Medical Home?</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/HBqAYSxVykE/what-is-a-medical-home.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/what-is-a-medical-home.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e2013481204486970c</id>
        <published>2010-05-19T06:16:34-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-05-19T06:16:34-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE In the 1980’s primary care physicians thought they were king. In reality, they were pawns for the managed care companies. Their job was to be the gatekeeper and manage costs not care. Patients could not see a...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><b>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</b></p>  <p>In the 1980’s primary care physicians thought they were king. In reality, they were pawns for the managed care companies. Their job was to be the gatekeeper and manage costs not care. Patients could not see a specialist unless referred by a primary care physician. The managed care system did not decrease medical care cost. It restricted access to care. Patients rebelled. </p>  <p>In 2002, seven U.S. national <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Family_medicine">family medicine</a> organizations created the <a href="http://www.annfammed.org/cgi/reprint/2/suppl_1/s3">“Future of Family Medicine Project” to "transform and renew” the specialty of family medicine.</a></p>  <p>The specialty of family medicine has been devalued in the last 20 years. Primary care physicians practice cognitive medicine. Reimbursement for cognitive medicine is low and has been decreasing while overhead has been increasing. </p>  <p>Primary care organizations have proposed a<b> </b>Medical Home Model to increase their value. Medical Home is a strange name for this model of medical care.<b> </b></p>  <p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medical_home">The definition of a Medical Home is a patient-centered approach to providing</a> comprehensive <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Primary_care">primary care</a>. Patients should understand that their care would be coordinated by their personal primary care physician and his/her team of physician extenders. </p>  <p>The model emphasizes a partnership between <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patient">patients</a> and their physicians. In recent years physicians have been called healthcare providers. I have insisted they be called physicians because they provide medical care; healthcare care providers should provide assistance to physicians’ medical care.</p>  <p>The term healthcare provider devalues physicians’ contribution to patient care. In turn it is used to decreases reimbursement. </p>  <p>Medical Homes might deliver better access to health care, increase satisfaction with care, and improve health. Primary care physicians should have been doing this all along. </p>  <p>However, economic conditions have forced primary care physicians to see a greater number of patients in a shorter time. Many primary care physicians have not related well to patients because of the time limitations. </p>  <p>Primary care physicians have to incorporate systems of chronic disease management into their practice of medicine. These systems of chronic disease management must teach patients how to be professors of their chronic disease so they can avoid the costly complications of chronic disease.</p>  <p>Eighty percent of the healthcare dollar is spent on the complications of chronic disease. In order to avoid these complications patients need to be taught to self-manage their chronic disease. </p>  <p>If primary care “Medical Home” could teach patients to be responsible for the control of their disease and increase compliance with medical treatment recommendations a cost savings would occur. </p>  <p>It remains to be seen if the “Medical Home Model” will achieve its goal. President Obama is setting up pilot studies to see if “Medical Homes” work. I fear the physician incentives are too small. Also patient incentives are not included but are critical to the models success. </p>  <p>There is a shortage of primary care physicians. With 30 million more people insured the shortage of primary care physicians will intensify. The result will be long delays in seeing a primary care physician. Long delays have occurred with Romney care in Massachusetts.</p>  <p>President Obama’s pilot studies will increase primary care physicians’ reimbursement 5.6%. I do not believe this is enough. He plans to get the money by decreasing specialist compensation. </p>  <p><i><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704471504574443472658898710.html?mod=mostpop">“In President Obama's Washington, medical specialists are slightly more popular than the H1N1 virus</a>. Compared to bread-and-butter primary care doctors, specialists cost more to train and make more use of expensive procedures and technology—and therefore cost the government more money. .”</i></p>  <p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704471504574443472658898710.html?mod=mostpop">President Obama has declared war on medical and surgical specialists</a>. </p>  <p>Future of Family Medicine Project has recommended;</p>  <p><i>“</i><i><a href="http://www.annfammed.org/cgi/reprint/2/suppl_1/s3">that every American should have a "personal medical home"</a> through which to receive his or her <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acute_%28medicine%29">acute</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronic_%28medical%29">chronic</a>, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Preventive_medicine">preventive</a> services. The services should be "accessible, accountable, comprehensive, integrated, patient-centered, safe, scientifically valid, and satisfying to both patients and their physicians."</i></p>  <p>. </p>  <p>Execution by primary care practices will be the problem. Articles supporting the concept Medical Home are not scientific studies. They are at best survey estimates and consensus documents declaring that a medical cost savings will result.</p>  <p>I believe it would be very difficult for Medical Homes to be accessible 24/7, comprehensive, scientifically valid and satisfying to both patients and physicians.    <table cellpadding="0" border="0"><tbody>       <tr>         <td> </td>       </tr>     </tbody></table> “<a href="http://www.annfammed.org/cgi/reprint/2/suppl_3/s1"><em>If the Future of Family Medicine recommendations were followed (including implementation of personal medical homes), "health care costs would likely decrease by 5.6%, resulting in national savings of 67 billion dollars per year, with an improvement in the quality of the health care provided."</em></a><em> </em></p>  <p>In 2007, the leading primary care physician organizations in the United States released the <a href="http://www.acponline.org/advocacy/where_we_stand/medical_home/approve_jp.pdf">"Joint Principles of the Patient-Centered Medical Home."</a> </p>  <p><i>The principles are:</i></p>  <ul>   <li><b><i>Personal physician</i></b><i>: "each patient has an ongoing relationship with a personal physician trained to provide first contact, continuous and comprehensive care."</i></li>    <li><b><i>Physician directed medical practice</i></b><i>: "the personal physician leads a team of individuals at the practice level who collectively take responsibility for the ongoing care of patients."</i></li>    <li><b><i>Whole person orientation</i></b><i>: "the personal physician is responsible for providing for all the patient’s health care needs or taking responsibility for appropriately arranging care with other qualified professionals."</i></li>    <li><b><i>Care is coordinated and/or integrated</i></b><i>, for example across specialists, hospitals, home health agencies, and nursing homes.</i></li>    <li><b><i>Quality and safety</i></b><i> are assured by a care planning process, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evidence-based_medicine">evidence-based medicine</a>, clinical decision-support tools, performance measurement, active participation of patients in decision-making, information technology, a voluntary recognition process, quality improvement activities, and other measures.</i></li>    <li><b><i>Enhanced access</i></b><i> to care is available (e.g., via "open scheduling, expanded hours and new options for communication").</i></li>    <li><b><i>Payment</i></b><i> must "appropriately recognize[s] the added value provided to patients who have a patient-centered medical home." For instance, payment should reflect the value of "work that falls outside of the face-to-face visit," should "support adoption and use of health information technology for quality improvement," and should "recognize case mix differences in the patient population being treated within the practice."</i></li> </ul>  <p>These are all important principles.</p>  <p>The last principle deals with increasing reimbursement. Candidate Obama pledged to support Medical Homes when elected President. Multiple accrediting agencies are being formed to oversee the practice in Medical Homes. Increased bureaucracy leads to increased inefficiency and increased costs. It also leads to the increased possibility of failure of the pilot. </p>  <p>The concept of Medical Homes is a step in the right direction. If successful it can help the important specialty of primary care flourish. It will require teaching primary care physicians how to set up systems of intensive self management for chronic disease as well as adequate reimbursement for these services. </p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/HBqAYSxVykE" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/what-is-a-medical-home.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Here Comes The Public Option. Next: Single Party Payer.</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/PPbjtiVEoXg/here-comes-the-public-option-next-single-party-payer.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/here-comes-the-public-option-next-single-party-payer.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133edb6450e970b</id>
        <published>2010-05-16T06:17:39-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-05-16T06:17:39-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE Barney Frank declared during the healthcare reform bill debate, if we do not have a public option healthcare reform will fail. Senator Kerry felt we must have a single party payer system. He stated the Democratic Party...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/">
&lt;div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f3BS4C9el98"&gt;Barney Frank declared during the healthcare reform bill debate, if we do not have a public option healthcare reform will fail.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;div class="wlWriterEditableSmartContent" id="scid:5737277B-5D6D-4f48-ABFC-DD9C333F4C5D:a5d2a63e-943c-4dee-85b9-24608dfd3439" style="padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-left: 0px; float: none; padding-bottom: 0px; margin: 0px; padding-top: 0px"&gt;&lt;div id="b9b76b13-e2c4-424f-9f09-246cbd8702c3" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline;"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f3BS4C9el98&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;" target="_new"&gt;&lt;img src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013480e89805970c-pi" style="border-style: none" galleryimg="no" onload="var downlevelDiv = document.getElementById('b9b76b13-e2c4-424f-9f09-246cbd8702c3'); downlevelDiv.innerHTML = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;object width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;param name=\&amp;quot;movie\&amp;quot; value=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/f3BS4C9el98&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/param&amp;gt;&amp;lt;embed src=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/f3BS4C9el98&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash\&amp;quot; width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/embed&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/object&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/div&amp;gt;&amp;quot;;" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Senator Kerry felt we must have a single party payer system. He stated the Democratic Party did not have the votes to put it in the bill. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama and the Democrat figured out how to sneak a single party payer system into the healthcare system in America by default. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;div class="wlWriterEditableSmartContent" id="scid:5737277B-5D6D-4f48-ABFC-DD9C333F4C5D:ee7cc3ca-2b25-4271-9092-15c822829e70" style="padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-left: 0px; float: none; padding-bottom: 0px; margin: 0px; padding-top: 0px"&gt;&lt;div id="07e613d2-5b5c-49ff-af42-4c48ac83e0c7" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline;"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-522hcm3woA&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;" target="_new"&gt;&lt;img src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e2013480e89812970c-pi" style="border-style: none" galleryimg="no" onload="var downlevelDiv = document.getElementById('07e613d2-5b5c-49ff-af42-4c48ac83e0c7'); downlevelDiv.innerHTML = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;object width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;param name=\&amp;quot;movie\&amp;quot; value=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/-522hcm3woA&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/param&amp;gt;&amp;lt;embed src=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/-522hcm3woA&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash\&amp;quot; width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/embed&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/object&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/div&amp;gt;&amp;quot;;" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama’s signature promise about the healthcare reform bill was &amp;quot;If you like your health care plan, you can keep your health care plan. If you like your doctor you can keep your doctor.”&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;div class="wlWriterEditableSmartContent" id="scid:5737277B-5D6D-4f48-ABFC-DD9C333F4C5D:5f37914a-d26b-4206-b035-830803c906c2" style="padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-left: 0px; float: none; padding-bottom: 0px; margin: 0px; padding-top: 0px"&gt;&lt;div id="f1475003-357a-48ba-8c1f-0e40db083dc0" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline;"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DXqKp5B0ZLE&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;" target="_new"&gt;&lt;img src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e20133edb6450a970b-pi" style="border-style: none" galleryimg="no" onload="var downlevelDiv = document.getElementById('f1475003-357a-48ba-8c1f-0e40db083dc0'); downlevelDiv.innerHTML = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;object width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;param name=\&amp;quot;movie\&amp;quot; value=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/DXqKp5B0ZLE&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/param&amp;gt;&amp;lt;embed src=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/DXqKp5B0ZLE&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash\&amp;quot; width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/embed&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/object&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/div&amp;gt;&amp;quot;;" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;p&gt;What President Obama left out of his promise was that if your employer stops your healthcare insurance coverage there will be no choice but to use the subsidized government healthcare plan from the healthcare insurance exchange “Public Option”.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama uses this move a lot. It is called misdirection.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“&lt;a href="http://www.dallasnews.com/sharedcontent/dws/bus/stories/DN-healthcare_08bus.ART0.State.Edition1.38ce1f3.html"&gt;As companies crunch numbers on what the new law means for their bottom line, some have concluded they might be financially better off canceling&lt;/a&gt; their health care coverage and moving their workers to government-subsidized &amp;quot;exchanges&amp;quot; that will be created in four years. “&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Corporate action to drop healthcare insurance will make Barney Frank, Nancy Pelosi, John Kerry and President Obama happy. I do not think the Democrats have thought about the unintended consequences. Just think what the influx of consumers to the government subsidized plan will do to the CBO’s estimate of the healthcare reform bill reducing the deficit by $115 billion dollars in ten years and 1 trillion dollars over the next 10 years. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The CBO revised its estimate this week. It stated that the bill will increase the deficit by that amount in the tenth year instead of decreasing it. I believe this is an underestimate.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://topics.dallasnews.com/topic/AT%26T_Inc."&gt;AT&amp;amp;T Inc&lt;/a&gt; has concluded that eliminating employees' healthcare insurance could mean a $1.8 billion dollar saving per year. It is much cheaper to pay an estimated penalty $2,000 per employee than $15,000 to 18,000 in non deductible dollars for employee healthcare insurance coverage.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="http://www.dallasnews.com/sharedcontent/dws/bus/stories/DN-healthcare_08bus.ART0.State.Edition1.38ce1f3.html"&gt;The documents, obtained by Fortune magazine and posted online this week, reveal that four companies&lt;/a&gt; – AT&amp;amp;T, &lt;a href="http://topics.dallasnews.com/topic/Verizon_Communications_Inc."&gt;Verizon Communications Inc&lt;/a&gt;., &lt;a href="http://topics.dallasnews.com/topic/Caterpillar_Inc."&gt;Caterpillar Inc&lt;/a&gt;. and &lt;a href="http://topics.dallasnews.com/topic/Deere_%26_Co"&gt;Deere &amp;amp; Co&lt;/a&gt;. – had investigated to varying degrees the impact of dropping health care coverage and pushing their workers onto the new exchanges, where they will be able to buy their own insurance.” &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This year AT&amp;amp;T spent about $2.4 billion to cover medical costs of its 283,000 active workers. Next year they are scheduled to pay more. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T instantly denied that it has a plan in place to drop healthcare insurance for employees. AT&amp;amp;T would only have to pay an annual penalty of $600 million, or $2,000 a worker if the company dropped the healthcare insurance. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The burden would be on the employee and the government. President Obama promised us all affordable healthcare insurance.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Large companies are sick of dealing with increasing insurance premiums, insurance paperwork and regulatory compliance. These large companies would pocket huge savings by eliminating healthcare insurance for employees.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://www.dallasnews.com/sharedcontent/dws/bus/stories/DN-healthcare_08bus.ART0.State.Edition1.38ce1f3.html"&gt;Even though the proposed [penalties] are material, they are modest when compared to the average cost of health care,&amp;quot; Hewitt Resources said in its report. &amp;quot;To avoid additional costs and regulations, employers may consider exiting the employer health market and send employees to the exchanges.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;All the large corporations are denying they have plans to drop healthcare insurance. However it is obvious this is just what they should do to protect their vested interests.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Just as bad an unintended consequence is firms fewer than 50 full time employees do not have to pay a penalty for dropping insurance. A firm at the 50 employee threshold could fire workers to get below the 50 mark. They could then hire them back as part time employees. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;If al these people lose healthcare insurance they will be forced to go into Medicare, Medicaid or the government subsided “Public Option” through the healthcare insurance exchange. Either option will increase government spending. The estimate increases are low at $160 to 300 billion dollars per year. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama’s little trick will work. The losers will be consumers. Everyone will be forced into the “Public Option” by default. The single party payer (the government) will automatically take over the healthcare system in America (socialized medicine).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The federal deficit will increase without Repairing the Healthcare System. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Taxes on everyone will have to be increased . Does President Obama understand all of this? &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Americans must wake up. The 2010 midterm elections are near. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“It is t&lt;a href="http://loyaltoliberty.blogspot.com/2009/04/time-to-throw-da-bums-out.html"&gt;ime to trow da bums out&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="OLE_LINK1"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/PPbjtiVEoXg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/here-comes-the-public-option-next-single-party-payer.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Accountable Care Centers Continued</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/ARCRlmtlekI/accountable-care-centers-continued.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/accountable-care-centers-continued.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e2013480b6bcd8970c</id>
        <published>2010-05-12T05:24:41-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-05-12T05:24:41-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE I received the following note from Dale Fuller M.D. a retired Radiation Oncologist. Like me Dr. Fuller does not have a billfold agenda for Repairing The Healthcare System. I will add my comments to his extensive critique...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> </p>  <p>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</p>  <p>I received the following note from Dale Fuller M.D. a retired Radiation Oncologist. Like me Dr. Fuller does not have a billfold agenda for Repairing The Healthcare System. I will add my comments to his extensive critique of Accountable Care Organizations (ACO). </p>  <p><i><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/accountable-care-organizations.html">“I read your piece this morning,</a> and a number of thoughts come to mind; One is a quote from Richard Nixon, who when he was "vamping for time", would say.”Let me say this about that!"  In this case the "that" is the issue of ACO's. It stimulated some general ideas about how medicine is structured, and how care is or could be paid for.”</i></p>  <p><i /></p>  <p>Dr. Fuller has expressed some of the same concerns that I have about ACO. He nailed it with his concern for the hospital systems taking advantage of physicians’ intellectual property. </p>  <p><i>It concerns me that the lead in the formation of ACO's is generally a hospital, and most often, a large one, with multiple sites of service.  My fifty years in medicine have caused me to recognize that the management of hospital organizations and the leadership of doctor groups of any size, small or large, do not have interests that are congruent. </i></p>  <p><i /></p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=align+interests&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">When hospital systems realize its vested interests must be aligned with physicians’ vested interests</a> systems such as ACO might be effective.</p>  <p><i>I have no reason to believe that the administrators of hospitals understand the business side of medicine very well. Hospital administrator may be able to learn the business of medicine over time. <b><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=healthcare+insurance+industry+overhead&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">The doctors would be well advised to "watch their hats and coats" while the learning is taking place.</a></b></i></p>  <p><i /></p>  <p><i>Moreover hospital administrators tend to come and go, sometimes with great frequency, and each change brings new managers with new management strategies. Doctors, changing as they do with much less frequency, will have to learn to adapt to constantly to new management strategies. </i></p>  <p>Hospital administrations usually change because the hospital is not making enough money. Hospital systems might not make enough money when administrators treat staff physicians poorly. Physicians can undermine hospital systems’ built in profit leverage. Physicians’ may have also negotiated too good a deal. </p>  <p><i>Some of those changes will in one way or other impact physicians’ earnings. That is to say nothing about recognizing the difference in the earning expectations and compensation strategies among the various specialties likely to be swept up together in an ACO. </i></p>  <p><i>The division of the "pie" of dollars will be a daunting exercise, just as it is now, but with the added complexity of hospital administrators adding their own expectations to the process, and claiming their own piece of the pie. </i></p>  <p><i /></p>  <p><i>The transition will mark the end of the era of the practice of medicine as a "cottage industry" as it is transformed into an assembly line approach to the delivery of  the care of patients.</i></p>  <p><i /></p>  <p>You can bet the process of dividing reimbursement will be contested. It is difficult enough when deciding compensation among physicians in multi specialty groups.</p>  <p><i>“In your piece you mention that the dollars paid to the ACO will still be procedures based, and I believe that same process, probably with RVU's, could easily be translated into an algorithm to facilitate the division of the revenue to those delivering the services, <b>with, of course, that healthy slice off the top, for the administration of the ACO, provided by you-know-who.(hospital administrators). </b></i></p>  <p><b><i /></b></p>  <p>Physicians are beginning to understand that the healthcare insurance industry loads its overhead. As physicians enter into partnerships with hospital systems they are starting to realize that the hospital systems administrators overload physicians overhead. Hospital systems pay all the overhead for employees, rents and equipment maintenance many times at an inflated fee. </p>  <p>Physicians are not stupid. They are starting to wake up. <i /></p>  <p><i>“I have the sense that not only of the adage "he who has the gold makes the rules “will apply, but in addition, "he who has the data controls the flow of payments".  And, more often than not, the data is controlled by the insurance companies and by the CMS (aka the government)”</i></p>  <p><i /></p>  <p><i>  Generally the doctors are pretty clueless about the existence and the potential usefulness of the data, prevented as they have been from negotiation with the payers with both sides having equal access to that information. </i></p>  <p>I have been told by healthcare insurance executives that physicians will remain clueless. I replied that physicians are a sleeping tiger. When they awake the party for secondary stakeholders will be over.</p>  <p>Physicians are reluctant to purchase and install expensive electronic medical records. <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=claims+data&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">Data such as claims data have been used against them. Claims data are inaccurate</a>. Physicians are starting to learn how to collect data to be used for their advantage.</p>  <p><em>“The data is all there and could readily be used to develop case rates for individual diagnoses, or, given the characteristics of a given patient population, a capitation rate could be set quite easily based on the experience and the risk factors inherent in the makeup of the population.” </em></p>  <p>Useful data presupposes a large data base. Most of the physicians are solo or in small groups. It had been impossible to calculate capitation rates with data available in the past.</p>  <p>A large margin of error must be built into the cost of care. Patients are becoming sicker because of the <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=Obesity+epidemic&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">obesity epidemic</a> and poor lifestyle choices. Patients over utilize the healthcare system because they have first dollar coverage. </p>  <p><i>“ Once the ACO is paid, the division of the income could be made in a variety of ways, the easiest being by the Relative Value Units (RVU's) for the services provided to the patient by the physicians.  The physicians in the ACO over time should be able to monitor the actual RVU's reported by individual physicians.”</i></p>  <p>From the physician side if the RVU’s were fair and primary care was valued appropriately. ACO might work. ACO would not control patient utilization of the healthcare system. Patients must be motivated and incentivized to control utilization.</p>  <p><i>“When "outliers" are identified, those physicians can be re-educated about the wisdom of practicing medicine with some greater level of restraint where the provision of services is concerned.  Some of the larger organizations are already using such an approach with the evolution of clinical pathways.” </i></p>  <p>Data could be used and should be used constructively to control outliers. Groups of physicians must control the data and discipline to outliers. A peer group must have incentive to control “outliers”. It must be done in a non punitive way. </p>  <p><i>“It isn't all that easy.” </i></p>  <p>ACO will not decrease costs. </p>  <p><i>“An ACO will change forever the business side of medical practice, but that may be the way the ball will be made to bounce”. </i></p>  <p>An ACO might wake up physicians and patients. It might stimulate secondary stakeholders not to take advantage of primary stakeholders (physicians and patients). I believe the chances are slim. </p>  <p><i><b>All in all, it is a good time for the docs to be very careful, and not to rush into something they may later have cause to regret.    DEF </b></i></p>  <p>The idea of ACO is a good one if it could be priced fairly. The patient incentive component is missing. Consumers of healthcare with first dollar coverage drive increasing utilization and costs. </p>  <p>Prevention of the onset of disease and the complications of chronic disease will drive the cost down. This can only be accomplished by <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=consumer+driven+healthcare&amp;x=20&amp;y=7">consumer driven healthcare</a> utilizing the <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=ideal+medical+saving+account&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">ideal medical savings account</a>. </p>  <p> </p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/ARCRlmtlekI" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/accountable-care-centers-continued.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Accountable Care Organizations</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/NML59kVKH-M/accountable-care-organizations.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/accountable-care-organizations.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ed6da409970b</id>
        <published>2010-05-09T16:11:04-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-05-09T16:11:04-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP, MACE Accountable Care Organizations (ACO) are supposed to manage Medicare cost. Policymakers are desperate to control costs. Proponents of ACO want to test it along with such alternatives as patient-centered medical homes, pay-for-performance and payment bundling. President...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP, MACE</p>  <p><a href="http://www.ama-assn.org/amednews/2009/08/31/gvsa0831.htm">Accountable Care Organizations (ACO) are supposed to manage Medicare cost</a>. Policymakers are desperate to control costs. Proponents of ACO want to test it along with such alternatives as patient-centered medical homes, pay-for-performance and payment bundling.</p>  <p>President Obama’s practice models pilots are going to be a great waste of money. Each model has major defects.</p>  <p>None of the models offer patients the ability to control of healthcare dollars. None of the models provide incentives to patients to be responsible for their own health.</p>  <p>The models replace individualism with collectivism. They replace individual self-responsibility with community governance. Bureaucracy stifles initiatives and innovation, two characteristics that have been the engine of progress in medical advances. </p>  <p>The models subject medical care to the deadening hand of bureaucracy. The net result is a more costly healthcare system and increasing federal deficits. Bureaucracy always has loopholes. The advantaged vested interests always game the system to the disadvantage of consumers. </p>  <p><b>What are Accountable Care Organizations (ACO)? </b></p>  <p><b /></p>  <p><em><a href="http://www.ama-assn.org/amednews/2009/08/31/gvsa0831.htm">“The goal of ACO is to encourage physicians and hospitals to integrate care</a> by holding them jointly responsible for Medicare quality and costs.”</em></p>  <p> </p>  <p>A typical Medicare ACO would include a hospital, primary care physicians, specialists and potentially other medical professionals. Services would still be billed under fee-for-service. The ACO’s members would coordinate care for their shared Medicare patients. </p>  <p>I do not know when hospital systems have not tried to profit from its physicians’ intellectual property. What will suddenly get them to not take advantage of physicians intellectual property? </p>  <p><em>“Because ACO members are held jointly accountable for this care, they would share in any cost savings that stem from the quality gains.”</em></p>  <p>Cost overruns would be deducted from the fees billed. Realistically surgeons have always dominated the primary care physicians. It is unrealistic to believe surgeons would relinquish this position passively. Surgeons would not agree to increase compensation to primary care cognitive physicians at their expense</p>  <p><em>“<a href="http://healthcare-economist.com/2010/01/26/what-are-accountable-care-organizations/">The goal of ACOs is to pay providers in a way that encourages them to work together, to pay providers in a way that does not encourage supplier induced demand, and to create an organization that is rewarded for providing high quality care.”</a></em></p>  <p>The Medicare Advantage program pays a lump sum to private insurers. The government holds the healthcare insurance industry accountable for all medical care. The healthcare insurance industry is in control of the healthcare dollars. </p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2009/06/republican-healthcare-proposal-executive-summary-part-2.html">Medicare pays the healthcare insurance industry a $3000 premium per patient above and beyond the average cost of $6600 per patient.</a> Patients pay on average 33% of the total $9600 premium. The healthcare insurance industry decreases physician reimbursement to increase its profitability.</p>  <p> Medicare Advantage looks good to the patients because premiums are low. Patients do not realize restriction to access to care exists. Patients are happy. </p>  <p>The government was happy despite the large subsidy because it had a fixed cost. The insurance industry was happy because its profit increased. </p>  <p>The problems with ACO are:</p>  <p><em>“<a href="http://healthcare-economist.com/2010/01/26/what-are-accountable-care-organizations/">Accountability rests with the providers.</a>  Providers or provider groups, rather than insurance companies, are evaluated on the quality and efficiency of care.”</em></p>  <p>Physicians are unhappy. They are being judged on utilization without concern for medical risk their patients present or the need for defensive medicine to avoid malpractice liability. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=patient+resonsibility&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">Patients’ responsibility for their health and medical care is not considered</a>. Obesity, substance abuse, or noncompliance are not considered as a patient responsibility in this or any other model considered by President Obama’s healthcare team.</p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=80%25+of+the+healthcare+dollar+spent+on+chronic+disease+comlications&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">Eighty percent of healthcare dollars are spent on treating the complications of chronic diseases</a>. When the risk of disease and complications of disease is high the risk management is the responsibility of physicians and not patients.</p>  <p><em>“ACO allow for flexibility in the type of organization.  Some regions may prefer independent practice associations (IPAs) while others may prefer a physician-hospital organization (PHO).”</em></p>  <p>The ACO is a fixed reimbursement system. Cost overruns will occur at the expense of physicians. Physicians and hospital systems will not know how to price reimbursement in advance. Utilization of medical care services is dependent on both patient and physician behavior. If patients were healthy there would be great cost savings. There are no incentives in ACO for patients to remain healthy.</p>  <p><em>“The physician-centered organization makes much sense to many policymakers because “the resources that flow from the decisions physicians make with patients account for a major portion of overall health care costs, regardless of where the care actually takes place.”</em></p>  <p>Physicians are good at treating illness. They are not good at risk management. Patients must be incentivized and taught to manage the risk of complications. </p>  <p>Many physicians will get stuck with high-risk patients. Medicare will have to increase payments to those physicians or risk losing them as providers. ACO will become insolvent. This will increase the deficit. </p>  <p> <em>” <a href="http://healthcare-economist.com/2010/01/26/what-are-accountable-care-organizations/">If participant believe that ACOs are essentially tightly managed ‘HMOs in drag’</a> that are going to restrict their choices, undermine the doctor-patient relationship, and result in cheaper but lower-quality care, the concept will be met with skepticism, if not overt opposition.”</em></p>  <p><em>P</em>hysicians and patients should view ACO for what they are. ACO are HMO in disguise. They represent a fixed reimbursement for variable amounts of necessary service. </p>  <p>Physician groups and hospital systems are allergic to HMO because they did not know how to price the reimbursement adequately. They also do not know how to price risk and manage risk. </p>  <p>Neither the healthcare insurance industry nor the government knows how to manage or price risk. The healthcare insurance industry compensates for overuse by increasing the premium next year.</p>  <p>How can they expect physician groups to price risk? Many physicians’ practices and hospital systems lost money on HMO. This resulted in non participation in HMO. </p>  <p>Many patients hated HMO because medical care became commoditized, choice was restricted and the doctor-patient relationship was undermined. The resulting cost was not lower.</p>  <p>The HMO were a failure. ACO will be a failure. The result will be opposite of the intent with increasing cost, increasing deficits and decreasing quality of care. </p>  <p>The only way to manage risk is to motivate consumers to manage risk. This is the definition of <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=consumer+driven+healthcare&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">consumer driven healthcare</a> using the <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=ideal+medical+savings+account&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">ideal medical savings account.</a> </p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/NML59kVKH-M" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/accountable-care-organizations.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>President Obamas Legislative Strategy</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/OkpRSrqifHI/president-obamas-legislative-strategy.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/president-obamas-legislative-strategy.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ed4ac5c1970b</id>
        <published>2010-05-05T14:24:07-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-05-05T14:40:04-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE President Obama’s healthcare reform bill was rammed through congress over a month ago. He has been first to point out that the world has not fallen apart yet. He is being disingenuous since he healthcare reform plan...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><b>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</b></p>  <p>President Obama’s healthcare reform bill was rammed through congress over a month ago. He has been first to point out that the world has not fallen apart yet. He is being disingenuous since he healthcare reform plan does not influence medical care until 2014. </p>  <p>The strategy is to not do anything drastic until after he wins the November 2010 elections for the Democratic Party and the Presidential election in November 2012. </p>  <p>He is disregarding American’s anger toward him for ignoring their wishes. He is hoping they forget their anger. </p>  <p>The traditional media is helping America forget the tactics used to pass the healthcare reform bill. They are not evaluating the long term consequences on medical care and the budget deficit. It is not economically feasible to enlarge failed entitlement programs.</p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=Wellpoint&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">The public opposes the healthcare bill yet Wellpoint, who has been making billions of dollars a year, raises insurance premiums by 39%</a>.</p>  <p>Immediately, President Obama, Harry Reid and Nancy Pelosi demonized the healthcare insurance industry. The choice given the public was to keep the present system along with healthcare insurance company abuse or adopt President Obama’s healthcare reform plan. The Republican Party did not present an alternative loud enough. </p>  <p>President Obama’s healthcare reform plan won the day by a partisan vote and a frustrated electorate. <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=Wellpoint&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">It led to Nancy Pelosi’s comment that Americans will understand the bill after it is passed.</a> </p>  <p>The reality is the healthcare reform bill will lead to a single party payer system with increasing deficits, increased taxes and decreased access to care. </p>  <p>The healthcare insurance industry and Big Pharma are supporting President Obama’s healthcare reform plan because they will continue to control the healthcare dollars. Now the government will subsidize their business. </p>  <p>After passage of the healthcare reform plan, President Obama went on to his financial reform bill. There was much opposition to his plan. The plan does not go far enough to repair structural defects in the financial system. It also increases government control of the financial system without preventing abuse. Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac are not restructured. </p>  <p>In the midst of the financial system reform debate the Democrats started a congressional hearing on alleged abuses by Goldman Sachs. Congress has demonized Goldman Sachs. The public has another choice. America can either support President Obama’s financial reform or the old structure. </p>  <p>President Obama’s environment and energy bill was going nowhere. Cap and trade looked dead. President Obama agreed to permit offshore drilling for oil as a compromise. </p>  <p>The catastrophic oil spill occurred. The traditional media obsessed over the leak. In order to be a “good guy” President Obama announced that off shore drilling is too risky and discontinues his plan to let federal leases for off shore drilling. </p>  <p>We now have an environment and energy bill without off shore drilling. There is no consideration about this decision’s effect on a fragile economy. </p>  <p>The immigration bill is going nowhere also. It has large structural defects. The federal government is not enforcing laws that already exist. Arizona passed a law duplicating the federal laws. Arizona gets demonized by the White House and the traditional media. </p>  <p>President Obama has condemned Arizona. Arizona is only doing what the federal government should be doing. There is now public sympathy for President Obama’s defective immigration bill.</p>  <p>I suspect President Obama will use this opportunity to push through his immigration bill rather than do it right. Where are the Republicans? </p>  <p>President Obama wants illegal immigrants to be legalized citizens. He wants them to have the right to vote. His plan is to get enough new voters to neutralize the independent voter who have defected since he was elected President. </p>  <p>The pattern is clear. You demonize the opposition and then pass your alternative as if it is the only alternative. President Obama’s method has legs with the traditional media. Experts in each area will tell you most of this legislation will not solve any of our problems. It will be ineffective legislation. It will increase the federal deficit and lead to more taxation. It will decrease economic growth by decreasing incentives. It will increase government power over States and suppress individual freedoms. Many unintended negative consequences will occur after government has operational control. </p>  <p>I am afraid the public is growing weary of protest. They will forget the tricks used to produce terrible legislation. We will have many costly unintended consequences for many years to come.</p>  <p>The most frightening consequence is government control over our lives and freedom and a never ending need to raise taxes. It will suppress America innovative spirit.</p>  <p>President Obama is moving ahead with his healthcare pilot studies. In my view all of the approved pilot studies have little chance of success. </p>  <p>A potential pilot study with the biggest chance of success is not being considered. The five models to be studied are Accountable Care Organizations, Primary Care Medical Homes, Bundled Payments, Partial Capitation, and Full Capitation. </p>  <p>All five have problems. The chance of succeeding to reduce cost is marginal. <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=ideal+medical+savings+accounts&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">The Ideal Medical Savings Account</a> is ignored as an option. The MSA should be compared to each model tested. The Ideal Medical Savings Account model is the only model with a chance for success. The MSA is a consumer driven model. It puts patients in control of their healthcare dollars. It rewards consumer when they use their healthcare dollars wisely and maintain their health. It promotes self responsibility and self respect. </p>  <p>I will evaluate each model and point out the problems in each model.</p>  <p> </p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/OkpRSrqifHI" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/president-obamas-legislative-strategy.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The American Taxpayer Should Wake Up!</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/kwvIZJI1644/the-american-taxpayer-should-wake-up.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/the-american-taxpayer-should-wake-up.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ed2086a1970b</id>
        <published>2010-05-02T10:49:37-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-05-02T10:49:37-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid’s support for reelection to the Senate has been stagnating at less than 40%. Each potential opponent for the Republican nomination vs. Senator Reid has support of over 50% of the probable voters....</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><b /><b /></p>  <p> </p>  <p><b>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</b></p>  <p><a href="http://www.rasmussenreports.com/public_content/politics/elections2/election_2010/election_2010_senate_elections/nevada/election_2010_nevada_senate">Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid’s support for reelection to the Senate has been stagnating at less than 40%</a>. Each potential opponent for the Republican nomination vs. Senator Reid has support of over 50% of the probable voters. </p>  <p>Senator Reid needs a costly, well choreographed campaign to overcome his poll deficit. </p>  <p>Who do you think is doing it for him?</p>  <p><strong>Big Pharma is paying for his big push.</strong> </p>  <p>How come?</p>  <p>Big Pharma is supposed to have been slaughtered by President Obama’s healthcare reform plan. Harry Reid jammed President Obama’s healthcare reform plan through the Senate. Senator Reid is supposed to be Public Enemy Number 1 to Big Pharma and the healthcare insurance industry. </p>  <p><em><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703871904575216444241140032.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h&amp;mg=com-wsj#articleTabs%3Darticle">“A new TV ad is up in Mr. Reid's home state praising the Democrat for creating "good Nevada jobs," expanding "clean energy" and providing "tax credits for small business."</a> Moreover, "thanks to Harry Reid's leadership, if you change or lose your job, you can keep your health care coverage."</em></p>  <p>Big Pharma is paying for Harry Reid’s campaign. The reasons are complicated but are becoming obvious. It is another one of President Obama’s trick plays. </p>  <p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703871904575216444241140032.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h&amp;mg=com-wsj#articleTabs%3Darticle"><em>“All this is courtesy of the Pharmaceutical Research and Manufacturers of America,</em></a><em> in league with the liberal health-advocacy group Families USA.” </em><a href="http://www.familiesusa.org/"><em>http://www.familiesusa.org/</em></a></p>  <p>Isn’t that strange?What is going on? </p>  <p>Big Pharma should be overjoyed that Harry Reid will lose his election. The healthcare insurance industry is now teaming up with Families U.S.A. to promote Obamacare.</p>  <p>President Obama has promised to provide affordable insurance. If he does provide affordable insurance it will be at the expense of all taxpayers because the government will be subsidizing healthcare insurance and drug costs. It will not be at the expense of the healthcare insurance industry or Big Pharma. Both industries will have a mandated increased customer base with guaranteed payment yielding a larger net profit. </p>  <p><em>“<a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703871904575216444241140032.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h&amp;mg=com-wsj#articleTabs%3Darticle">Big Pharma and health insurance companies are betting on short-term rent-seeking from legislation that subsidizes Americans to use more of their products</a>”</em></p>  <p>President Obama is not protecting the American taxpayer. He is protecting big business in a different way than big business has been protected in the past. </p>  <p>President Obama is protecting big business because big business provides the money that gets candidates elected. They are providing the money to get Harry Reid reelected. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.mmm-online.com/headliner-harvard-medical-schools-tom-stossel/article/147778/">Thomas P. Stossel M.D. Director, Translational Medicine Division at Brigham &amp; Women’s Hospital Harvard Medical School</a> cofounded the <a href="http://www.acreonline.org/">Association of Clinical Researchers and Educators (ACRE),</a>an advocacy group for doctor/drug company partnerships. He believes there is no statistical objective evidence for a conflict of interest in such partnerships. The partnerships are a valuable addition to physician education and clinical research as government funding for both decreases. The partnerships help translate advances in bench science into clinical practice.</p>  <p><strong>Big Pharma might be delighted to decrease its support of physician education.</strong> It will decrease its overhead and increase its short term profit. It will also decrease its drive to develop new drugs. </p>  <p>Big Pharma’s ad is partly a thank you to Democrats for new customers. But it's also political protection. With their business model in the hands of government, the drug makers have to make sure the government doesn't squeeze them in the bottom line. </p>  <p>Politics does not change. Only the guys running the government change. Someone is going to come along some day and do something to benefit the people. President Obama is just pretending to be doing things to benefit the people.</p>  <p><em><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703871904575216444241140032.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h&amp;mg=com-wsj#articleTabs%3Darticle">“Thus do sweeping government programs produce their own special-interest advocates?</a> Lost in this palm-greasing are the customers who ultimately will pay for ObamaCare in higher prices and politically rationed medical care.” </em></p>  <p>President Obama’s healthcare reform plan is another unsustainable entitlement for the benefit of Big Pharma and the healthcare insurance industry. </p>  <p>“<em><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703871904575216444241140032.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h&amp;mg=com-wsj#articleTabs%3Darticle">Another reminder, if another reminder is needed, that powerful government serves the powerful.”</a></em></p>  <p>As government entitlements grow, government’s percentage of the GDP grows. Taxes must increase for all. Black market trading will start. Before America knows it America will be another Greece. </p>  <p>Patients and physicians do not realize how much power they have. They are the primary stakeholders in the healthcare system. Consumers must become vocal. They must force their elected government officials to pay attention to their needs. President Obama and the Democrats are only pretending to pay attention to taxpayers needs. </p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/kwvIZJI1644" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/05/the-american-taxpayer-should-wake-up.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Medicare Actuary Weighs In</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/d61kHZ6sbHQ/the-medicare-actuary-weighs-in.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/the-medicare-actuary-weighs-in.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ed04ff88970b</id>
        <published>2010-04-28T08:12:48-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-04-28T08:12:48-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE On April 22, 2010 Richard S. Foster CMS Chief Actuary issued a report entitled “On the Estimated Financial Effects of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act as Amended. “ Mr. Foster’s disclaimer introduces the report. “Office...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> </p>  <p>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</p>  <p> </p>  <p>On April 22, 2010 Richard S. Foster CMS Chief Actuary issued a report entitled “On the Estimated Financial Effects of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act as Amended. “</p>  <p><a href="http://republicans.waysandmeans.house.gov/UploadedFiles/OACT_Memorandum_on_Financial_Impact_of_PPACA_as_Enacted.pdf">Mr. Foster’s disclaimer introduces the report</a>.</p>  <p><i>“Office of the Actuary has prepared this memorandum in our long standing capacity as an independent technical advisor to both the administration and the Congress. The statement, estimates, and other information provided in the memorandum are those of the office of the Actuary and do not represent an official position of the Department of Health &amp; Human Services or the administration.”</i></p>  <p><i />The report is an independent assessment of the fiscal reality of President Obama healthcare reform plan. The report contradicts President Obama’s fantasy that a new entitlement will lower health costs. President Obama used a series of trick plays to feed the Congressional Budget Office unrealistic assumptions in order for the CBO to conclude his healthcare bill will reduce the deficit. The only way there can be a deficit reduction is greater tax increases for all Americans. </p>  <p>President Obama’s Healthcare Reform plan does not solve the healthcare systems problems. The present healthcare reform bill will make the problems worse and increase the deficit further. </p>  <p><a href="http://republicans.waysandmeans.house.gov/UploadedFiles/OACT_Memorandum_on_Financial_Impact_of_PPACA_as_Enacted.pdf">Here are some of the Actuary Report findings:</a></p>  <ol>   <li>President Obama claims health care costs will go down but the actuary says they will go up<strong>.</strong> National health expenditures will increase from 17 percent of GDP now to 21 percent under the new law. Healthcare costs will be higher than they would have been without the legislation. [Page 4] Net federal spending on health care will also increase by $311 billion dollars. </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>The healthcare reform bill will result in the loss of employer coverage by 14 million employees. Employees of small firms are especially at risk despite small employer tax credit subsidies. It is cheaper to pay the penalty than pay for the insurance[Page 7] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>Two million employees who lose coverage will have to enroll in Medicaid. [Page 3] Medicaid enrollment will increase by 20 Million new beneficiaries. [pages 3-4]</li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>Qualifying for a Medicaid insurance card is not a guarantee of medical care. There is no corresponding increase in the supply of physicians. Other health professionals will try to care for the additional Medicaid patients. The quality of medical care must be questioned. </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>A significant portion of the increased demand for Medicaid care would be difficult to service. [Page 20]. Physicians are not participating in Medicaid presently because of the low reimbursement. Further reductions in reimbursement will lead to further non participation. The government could try to force physicians to participate in Medicaid. </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>There are more than one-half trillion dollars in Medicare cuts scheduled<strong>.</strong> The new health law cuts “$575 billion” from Medicare. [Page 4]. The result will be lower reimbursement and rationing of care. President Obama did not address this comment when the bill was being passed. </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>Medicare Part A cuts would threaten the viability of 15% of hospitals. These<strong> </strong>Part A Medicare providers would become unprofitable within the 10-year projection period.” [Page 10] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>Health care shortages are “plausible and even probable.” Because of the increased demand for health care, “supply constraints might initially interfere with providing the services desired by the additional 34 million insured persons.” [Page 20] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li><strong />By 2019, more than 10% of insured workers will “be in employer plans with benefit values in excess of the thresholds (before changes to reduce benefits) and will be taxed. The percentage of workers taxed would increase rapidly thereafter.” [Page 13] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>The new taxes on medical devices, prescription drugs, and insurance plans “would generally be passed on through to health consumers in the form of higher drug and device prices and higher insurance premiums.” [Page 17] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>The reimbursement decreases will challenge Medicare providers to continue to take Medicare patients. Medicare providers will find it difficult to remain profitable and might decide not to participate in the program. [Page 10] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>Enrollment in Medicare Advantage is planned to be cut in half (from its projected level of 14.8 million under the current law to 7.4 million under the new law). [Page 11] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>The new “Medicare Tax” doesn’t go to Medicare. Despite the Medicare tax title, the revenues generated by this tax on unearned income are not allocated to the Medicare trust funds. [Page 9] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>Budgetary double-counting does not improve Medicare’s solvency. Medicare cuts “cannot be simultaneously used to finance other federal outlays (such as the coverage expansions) and to extend the [life of the Medicare] trust fund, despite the appearance of extending the trust using present accounting conventions.” [Page 9] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>The new long-term care insurance plan (CLASS Act)<strong> </strong>faces “a significant risk of failure” because the high costs will attract sicker people and lead to low participation. [Page 15] </li> </ol>  <ol start="start">   <li>The promise to those with pre-existing conditions is unfunded. “By 2011 and 2012 the initial $5 billion in Federal funding for [high risk pools] would be exhausted, resulting in substantial premium increases to sustain the program.” [Page 16]. The healthcare insurance industry is still in control of the healthcare dollars. </li> </ol>  <p>These are just some of the Actuary Report finding </p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=terrible+bill&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">Despite President Obama’s repeated promises to curb healthcare costs and allow people to keep their current coverage, the President and Congress have enacted a healthcare law that will escalate healthcare costs, raise taxes, and decrease patient choice</a>. President Obama’s political agenda ignores the will of the people.</p>  <p>The government takeover of healthcare heralds a financial disaster. There will be unsustainable spending and ballooning budget deficits. The financial disaster will not occur overnight. President Obama’s healthcare reform bill is spread out over many years. The increased taxes will be collected for four years before significant benefits will start.</p>  <p>This healthcare reform bill is fatally-flawed. It must be replaced with common-sense healthcare reforms that will solve the problems in a dysfunctional healthcare system. Instead we have a bill that will increase the systemic dysfunction. </p>  <p><strong /></p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/d61kHZ6sbHQ" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/the-medicare-actuary-weighs-in.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>President Obama Please Re-examine Your Premises</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/KBHzvW40uvE/president-obama-please-re-examine-your-premises.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/president-obama-please-re-examine-your-premises.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ecef6a19970b</id>
        <published>2010-04-25T05:08:30-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-04-25T05:08:30-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE President Obama’s goal might be for his healthcare reform plan to fail. Once it fails the default plan will be a public option with a single party payer system. Everyone will be forced to opt into the...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><b /></p>  <p><b>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</b></p>  <p>President Obama’s goal might be for his healthcare reform plan to fail. Once it fails the default plan will be a public option with a single party payer system. </p>  <p>Everyone will be forced to opt into the public option. There will not be a private option. </p>  <p>The cost of healthcare will not decrease. The government will be paying the private healthcare insurance industry to administer the public option. Hospitals and physicians will figure out how to game the new system. The increasing costs will force a restriction to access to care.</p>  <p><strong>President Obama must re-examine his premises.</strong> The medical care crisis is neither a Democratic nor Republican problem. It is an American problem. Americans need to be motivated to live a healthier existence. Only then will the cost of care diminish.</p>  <p>Consumers must be provided with education to live a healthier existence. The culture must be changed to emphasize better nuitrition and exercise. </p>  <p><a href=" www.feldthoughts.com">Brad Feld</a> pointed me to a fascinating paper by Carliss Y. Baldwin (Harvard) and (Brad’s mentor) Eric von Hippel (MIT). The paper suggests that some of the <a href="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1502864">most basic theories on which the patent system is based are wrong</a>. The thesis is our present patent system might hinder innovation. </p>  <p>The same logic can apply to the premises President Obama and his healthcare policy wonks apply to medical care. President Obama’s healthcare reform plan is punitive to both patients and physicians. It does not promote patient responsibility. It penalizes physicians for poor patient care outcomes. </p>  <p>Effective healthcare reform should promote patient responsibility and physician innovation. Inappropriate patient incentives and punitive regulations for physicians encourage patients and physicians to get around the healthcare reform system. President Obama’s healthcare reform plan does not achieve its goal of saving money and building efficient medical care systems.</p>  <p>A way to develop efficient medical care systems is through a consumer driven healthcare system with patients being in control of their healthcare dollars.</p>  <p>Nevertheless, President Obama’s healthcare plan is law. He won the election and forced through a partisan vote for a healthcare reform plan the overwhelming majority of the public and the physician community oppose. Only time will demonstrate the impending disaster in the healthcare system.</p>  <p><i><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/health/policy/18cost.html?emc=tnt&amp;tntemail1=y">“Mindful that the new health care law’s ability to slow rising medical costs will depend to a great extent on how it is put in effect</a>, <a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/people/o/barack_obama/index.html?inline=nyt-per">President Obama</a> is assembling a high-level team to carry out key elements of the overhaul and is considering moving faster than the law requires to put them into action. “</i></p>  <p>Kathleen Sebelius, the secretary of health and human services is reorganizing the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services. She is developing an innovation center whose goal is to test ways to reduce reimbursing providers.</p>  <p>She can enforce ideas she deems important nationwide without Congressional approval. The power of the secretary of health and human services has been expanded greatly without checks and balances.</p>  <p>She has started working on new regulations in an attempt control <a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/news/health/diseasesconditionsandhealthtopics/medicare/index.html?inline=nyt-classifier">Medicare</a>, <a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/news/health/diseasesconditionsandhealthtopics/medicaid/index.html?inline=nyt-classifier">Medicaid</a> costs. She is also working on regulations to control independent private health care providers. President Obama wants an <strong>Independent Payment Advisory</strong> Board for controlling Medicare spending before 2014.</p>  <p>The problem with the Independent Payment Advisory Board is its total independence of congressional oversight. In the past Congress has ignored the Medicare Trustees’ recommendations to reduce costs. President Obama’s healthcare reform bill eliminates congressional oversight. Congress has not exercised its responsibility. However congress is accountable to the public and the Independent Payment Advisory Board is not.</p>  <p>The new board’s responsibilities will be in the hands of a 15 member board nominated by President Obama and confirmed by the Senate for the six-year term. The memberships will be full-time positions.</p>  <p><i><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/health/policy/18cost.html?emc=tnt&amp;tntemail1=y">“Each year that Medicare spending exceeds annual targets</a>, as most analysts expect it will, the board must propose ways to reduce payments to care providers.” </i></p>  <p>The Independent Payment Advisory Board provides Congress with an excellent opportunity to shirk its responsibility. The executive branch will have a firm grasp on control of the healthcare system. </p>  <p><em>“With the federal debt projected to rise to levels that many economists consider unsustainable, mainly due to growing health costs and an aging population, Congress might have little choice in coming years but to accede to unpopular limits on payments for doctors, </em><a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/news/health/diseasesconditionsandhealthtopics/hospitals/index.html?inline=nyt-classifier"><em>hospitals</em></a><em> and other health care providers of the kind that lawmakers have ignored in the past. <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/health/policy/18cost.html?emc=tnt&amp;tntemail1=y">The board would give them political cover to do so. “</a></em></p>  <p><em>“It’s a very promising structure,” said </em><a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/people/o/peter_orszag/index.html?inline=nyt-per"><em>Peter R. Orszag</em></a><em>, Mr. </em><a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/subjects/f/federal_budget_us/index.html?inline=nyt-classifier"><em>Obama’s budget</em></a><em> director. “But like anything else in life, it’s what you make of it. So whether it realizes its potential depends on how it’s implemented.” </em></p>  <p><a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/people/d/tom_daschle/index.html?inline=nyt-per">Tom Daschle</a>, wants the board to be expanded to deal with not only Medicare but also all healthcare insurance.</p>  <p><i>“ <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/health/policy/18cost.html?emc=tnt&amp;tntemail1=y">Otherwise, he said, doctors will shift their costs that Medicare does not fully reimburse to patients with private insurance, “which really exacerbates the problem.</a>” </i></p>  <p>Tom Daschle said it. It is all about the government takeover of the healthcare system. It is about government regulating the healthcare system at the expense of all the stakeholders including patients. It is not about healthcare reform to produce efficient and safe systems of care through patients influencing physicians to develop innovative systems of medical care. </p>  <p>When was the last time a government controlled system was efficient and cost effective? Government should make the rules and then get out of the way. </p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/KBHzvW40uvE" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/president-obama-please-re-examine-your-premises.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Family Travel</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/WZFYUkTPJ9I/family-travel.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/family-travel.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ecd2fdbb970b</id>
        <published>2010-04-20T15:14:14-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-04-20T15:14:14-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE Cecelia and I believed it was important to expose our children to as much of the world as possible as they were growing up. The belief was not from our travels as children with our families. My...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Life's Experiences" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</p>  <p><a href="http://www.studio7310.com/">Cecelia</a> and I believed it was important to expose our children to as much of the world as possible as they were growing up. The belief was not from our travels as children with our families. My longest trip was an occasional summer trip to the Catskill mountains with my parents and brother. </p>  <p>I did not travel in college and medical school but yearned to explore foreign countries. I worked in the Catskill mountains as a waiter for seven years including my senior year in high school to help pay for tuition. </p>  <p>College opened my eyes to the potential of world travel. When I met Cecelia I met a woman that had the same goals about world travel. We promised each other when we had enough money we were going to take at least one vacation trip overseas a year to experience other cultures</p>  <p>My philosophy is, “if you do not have goals you cannot score baskets.” </p>  <p>When <a href="http://www.feld.com/wp/">Brad</a> was 11 years old and <a href="http://www.sliceoflime.com/about/">Daniel</a> was 8, Cecelia and I decided to take the kids to England during Spring break. We would start in London, go to Scotland and then drive back to London. The goal was to experience average British life. </p>  <p>We flew to London. We stayed at a Bed and Breakfast in Knightsbridge. Cecelia did a magnificent job planning the itinerary for both the daily activities and living accommodations. The Feld family was the only American group in this Bed and Breakfast that accommodated eight other families of similar size from all over Europe. The stay was an interesting cultural experience. </p>  <p>We walked all over London. We took the tube or bus to everything we wanted to see. </p>  <p>Our goal was to expose Brad and Dan to all the fine art London had to offer. Cecelia and I had been to London a few times before and knew where to go.</p>  <p>I did not realize how much pain we inflicted on the boys schlepping them though all the museums and galleries. It turned out that <i>if there is no pain there is no gain</i>. <a href="http://www.feld.com/wp/">Brad</a> and his wife <a href="http://anchorpoint.blogs.com/amythoughts/">Amy</a> and <a href="http://www.sliceoflime.com/about/">Daniel</a> and his wife <a href="http://bucklebuttonzip.wordpress.com/about/">Laura</a> have a deep appreciation of fine art.</p>  <p>There were many memorable experiences during that trip. Harrods’ food court enchanted the boys. </p>  <p>One night, dinner ran late. The scheduled visit was the Tower of London. The trip on the tube was long. We arrived at the tube stop 30 minutes before closing. The Tower closed at 9 pm. We didn’t realize how long it would take to get there. Tension mounted on the tube ride. </p>  <p>I saw the excitement rising in Brad and Daniel. We ran through the dark streets and were the last people to go on the last tour. We got lost in the tube on the way home. All of this delighted of the boys. </p>  <p>On our last day we were scheduled to take a sleeper train to Scotland at 11 pm at Kings Crossing. I had arranged to have dinner at a medical school roommate’s cousin’s house outside of London. This cousin was a Family Doctor with four kids. They lived in a modest apartment. The doctor had a lot of negative things to say about America. </p>  <p>He compared Americans’ attitude to the British attitude. He said; if there was a black kid in the back of the bus in London and a man in a Rolls Royce the black kid would be thinking about how that guy ripped off the country and how he could be destroyed. In America the black kid would be thinking how he could achieve enough to own that Rolls Royce. </p>  <p>I thought this was very constrictive thinking. Our family discussed it in Scotland.</p>  <p>The doctor drove us to King’s Crossing. It was the first sleeper train for all of us. None of us slept a wink. We arrived in Edinburg at 5.45 am. Our rental car was a Ford Escort equivalent. It was not the most comfortable vehicle for the four of us but we managed. </p>  <p>We stayed at a farm in Tweed after having our share of lamb chops. It was beautiful but cold. The farmer gave us hot water bottle to keep our feet warm in lieu of heat. There was an overnight frost and not enough blankets. </p>  <p>I could not find the farm. I stopped at a house and ask a guy where it was. He jumped on his BMW motorcycle and said follow him.</p>  <p>We showed the boys more old castles and churches than one could imagine existed. In a bed in breakfast in one village a woman charged us the equivalent of a quarter to take a bath. </p>  <p>To an American boy this was certainly old world. </p>  <p>Lake Windermere was a great experience. We stayed in an old mansion. The structure was beautiful but again no heat. Cecelia and I had a date night to the best restaurant in England by the most famous chef in England. I found a pizza joint in town and bought a very large pizza for Brad and Daniel to share with the owner of the house. They sat in the living room before the fireplace wrapped in blankets watching the telie and eating pizza. </p>  <p>They were happy and we were off to have one of the best meals of our life.</p>  <p>The trip was wonderful. Brad and Daniel were great sports. I hope the warm memories of that trip linger in their minds as is does in mine. This is what family travel is about. </p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/WZFYUkTPJ9I" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/family-travel.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Will Obamacare Fail?</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/mlGl9iqYa9U/will-obamacare-fail.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/will-obamacare-fail.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ecc471f2970b</id>
        <published>2010-04-18T05:56:19-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-04-18T05:56:19-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE Unfortunately, the answer is yes. President Obama’s healthcare reform plan will fail because of its poor construction. The majority of Americans agree with President Obama’s goals. Americans want affordable universal high quality healthcare. President Obama’s healthcare reform...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> </p>  <p>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</p>  <p>Unfortunately, the answer is yes.</p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=terrible+bill&amp;x=24&amp;y=9">President Obama’s healthcare reform plan will fail because of its poor construction</a>.</p>  <p>The majority of Americans agree with President Obama’s goals. Americans want affordable universal high quality healthcare. President Obama’s healthcare reform bill will not accomplish these goals.</p>  <p>President Obama’s healthcare reform bill will <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=ration+care+&amp;x=12&amp;y=11">waste 2 trillion dollars, restrict access to care, raise taxes, ration care and destroy infrastructure of a healthcare system that provides excellent medical care to the sick</a>.</p>  <p>Our healthcare system is broken because prices are out of control. President Obama’s healthcare reform bill with a mushrooming government bureaucracy will not control prices by competition. It will try to control prices by regulations and force. Price controls never work. </p>  <p>Previous behavior is a predictor of future behavior. It follows that previous healthcare system reform failures are a predictor of future healthcare reform failure.</p>  <p>President Obama’s healthcare reform plan is similar to the failed <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=Massachusetts+healthcare+plan&amp;x=27&amp;y=10">Massachusetts healthcare reform plan (Romneycare). Romneycare was destined to fail from the onset.</a> <b /></p>  <p><b /></p>  <p> </p>  <p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703625304575115691871093652.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h#articleTabs%3Darticle">The similarities between Obamacare and Romneycare are glaring</a>;</p>  <ol>   <li>Both the Massachusetts healthcare reform plan and Obamacare mandate individual healthcare insurance.</li>    <li>If individuals do not have insurance they must pay a penalty. </li>    <li>Most businesses are required to participate or pay a fine. </li>    <li>Both healthcare reform plans rely on government-designed purchasing exchanges (healthcare insurance exchanges)</li>    <li>The healthcare insurance exchanges are supposed to provide a vehicle to control private health insurance. </li>    <li>The uninsured are covered by the expansion of Medicaid and with Obamacare the expansion of Medicare.</li>    <li>Qualified citizens receive healthcare insurance subsidies to help pay for their mandated healthcare insurance policies. </li>    <li>The state of Massachusetts has set up many new boards and committees to oversee and administer the healthcare reform plan. The added bureaucracy has failed to control costs.</li> </ol>  <p><strong>I predicted the Massachusetts plan would fail at its onset.</strong> It has been plagued with cost overruns from the start. I cannot image President Obama’s plan can be budget neutral after ten years. I suspect many Americans can’t image it either. I think the Scott Brown election has given America the notion that the citizens of Massachusetts don’t think Obamacare can be successful. </p>  <p>Why did the Massachusetts Healthcare Reform Plan fail?</p>  <ol>   <li>The healthcare reform plan is administered by the healthcare insurance industry. It controls the healthcare dollar and determines the premiums based on defective accounting rules. These rules permit the healthcare insurance industry to overestimate expenses and underestimate reserves. The result is increased premiums. </li>    <li>No one has the political will to challenge or change these rules. The rules permit the healthcare insurance industry to declare a loss while it is removing sixty five cents out of every healthcare dollar from the healthcare dollar pool. </li>    <li>There are 410,000 people who are newly insured in Massachusetts. Of those 200,000 are fully subsidized by Massachusetts state insurance exchange. </li> </ol>  <p>Policy makers underestimated the number of people that would qualify for subsidy.</p>  <ol start="start">   <li>3% of the population remains uninsured. The total 140,000 uninsured are required to pay a penalty. Half (70,000) uninsured cannot afford the premiums or penalty and receive a waiver.</li>    <li>The state’s premiums have increased every year since the onset of healthcare reform. A typical family of four’s annual premium costs almost $13,788, the highest in the country. This is twice the cost of premiums in Texas. The premiums are 27% higher than the national average.</li>    <li>This cost does not include out of pocket expenses.</li>    <li>Massachusetts regulations serve to eliminate competition in the healthcare insurance market.</li>    <li>Mandates dictate the services needed to be covered. </li>    <li>Healthcare insurance vendors are required to sell "just-in-time" policies even if people wait until they are sick to buy coverage.</li>    <li>Patients game the system by purchasing health insurance when they need it. Patients then drop insurance a few months later and pay the less expensive penalty. The same will apply to President Obama’s plan.</li>    <li>Massachusetts’ safety-net hospitals are treating a disproportionate number of lower-income and uninsured patients. State compensation of these safety-net hospitals has been reduced under the new healthcare plan. It is only a matter of time before the safety net hospitals will declare bankruptcy. The alternative is to increase state taxes further. The result is people will move out of Massachusetts lowering the tax base </li>    <li>There is a "critical shortage" of primary-care physicians as a result of increasing the number of people covered and an increase in demand for medical services.</li>    <li>Physician compensation is decreasing. Physicians are fleeing the state. Patients cannot get doctor appointments.</li>    <li>New patients wait 44 days to get an appointment with a primary-care doctor. A secondary market for primary-care doctor appointments is developing. People are selling their appointment times to patients.</li>    <li>Appointment time shortages have led to an increasingly expensive emergency room visit for basic medical services. Emergency room visits increased 7%. More than half need emergency room attention. ER visits are very costly.</li>    <li>President Obama gave the state of Massachusetts an 8 billion dollar bailout to help cover healthcare reform expenses. The healthcare insurance industry benefited by the stimulus bailout.</li> </ol>  <p>The state has refused to permit the insurance industry to raise rates. The insurance industry will leave the state or decrease reimbursement for services. The results are obvious. </p>  <p>If you do not fix the defects in the healthcare system you will not fix the financial difficulties. People must own their healthcare dollar, be responsible for their own care and have the freedom to choose. All this adds up to <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=consumer+driven+healthcare&amp;x=19&amp;y=13">consumer driven healthcare</a> using the <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=ideal+medical+savings+accounts&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">ideal medical saving accounts</a>. </p>  <p><a name="U20596922004KFD" /></p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/mlGl9iqYa9U" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/will-obamacare-fail.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Who Doesnt Get It?</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/lymrqojdnrM/who-doesnt-get-it.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/who-doesnt-get-it.html" thr:count="2" thr:updated="2010-05-12T11:17:29-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ecaf3e39970b</id>
        <published>2010-04-14T08:56:26-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-04-14T08:57:48-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D., FACP, MACE California Senator Diane Feinstein speaking on health care on Monday April 12, 2010 said; “I've gotten 90,000 emails and faxes on the health care bill and over 85,000 of them are against it. After all...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> </p>  <p><strong /></p>  <p><strong>Stanley Feld M.D., FACP, MACE</strong></p>  <p>California Senator Diane Feinstein speaking on health care on Monday April 12, 2010 said;<strong> </strong></p>  <p><strong><i /></strong></p>  <p><strong><i>“I've gotten 90,000 emails and faxes on the health care bill and over 85,000 of them are against it. <u> After all the debate we've had, I can't believe so many people still don't get it!"</u></i></strong></p>  <p><strong><i /></strong></p>  <p><b>What debate?</b></p>  <p>President Obama’s healthcare reform debate was one sided and not bipartisan. </p>  <p>Didn’t Nancy Pelosi say; <i>“Americans will understand the bill once it is passed.”</i></p>  <p><b>Maybe Diane Feinstein doesn’t get it? </b></p>  <p>If 94.4% of her constituents are against the bill, maybe 94.4% of her constituents will vote against her in the upcoming election. </p>  <p>The will of the people is being ignored by President Obama and the Democrats. </p>  <p><strong>Why?</strong></p>  <p>The Democrats believe:</p>  <ol>   <li>Americans need to be guided by big government in order to survive in our complex society.</li>    <li>Big government is superior to free enterprise.</li>    <li>Bureaucrats are more important than entrepreneurs.</li>    <li>Planning is more effective than innovation.</li>    <li>Redistribution of wealth and services are more important and much fairer than individual success.</li> </ol>  <p>Americans know that big government does not work. The government’s role should be to make the rules and then get out of the way. If the rules do not provide a level playing field the rules should be modified.</p>  <p>There are many examples of big government failure. One notable example is the U.S. Postal Service. It is going bankrupt while Fed Ex and UPS are successful. </p>  <p>I am sure President Obama wants to do the right thing. </p>  <p>However, he is going about it in wrong way. He is piling new healthcare reform on top of a failed healthcare system. (Medicare and Medicaid). His healthcare reform law cannot work. It can only waste more money</p>  <p><a href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/the-impending-physician-shortage.html">President Obama’s advisors have not been in the pits practicing medicine.</a> If he really wanted to do something effective he should try to understand the real problems in the healthcare system and repair them. </p>  <p>Republicans have done no better. They have expressed their opinions within a framework established by President Obama and the Democrats rather than presenting a bold and new approach to healthcare reform. </p>  <p>The American people know President Obama’s healthcare reform law will fail at a high cost to the economy and the nation’s welfare. The Tea Party might represent the peoples’ rebellion. The movement is frightening both the Democrats and Republicans. Republican like to think the Tea Party is an arm of the Republican Party. I think both parties will be in for a surprise.</p>  <p>President Obama cannot throw money after a failed system and expect the system to improve. The healthcare system will not improve until the primary stakeholders (consumers and physicians) are provided with incentives and the ability to be innovative.</p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=Primary+stakeholders&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">The primary stakeholders are the engine of the healthcare system.</a> Bureaucrats and “non partisan experts” cannot make the healthcare reform system more efficient and operate at decreased cost.</p>  <p>The incentives should be directed to the patients and not the healthcare insurance industry or hospital systems. In a healthcare system Patients are First. In President Obama’s healthcare law big government and the secondary stakeholders are first. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=mandates&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">Government should not require people to buy insurance</a>. People must be responsible for themselves even if government gives them the money. I believe it is fine to provide for people who cannot afford healthcare insurance. However, the incentive must be financial. Healthcare reform will work only if it is consumer driven. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=healthcare+insurance+industry+must+be+reformed&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">The healthcare insurance industry must be reformed.</a> President Obama’s healthcare bill does not reform the healthcare insurance industry. The law does not revise the healthcare industry’s accounting rules. The healthcare industry will continue to take sixty five cents out of every healthcare dollar. </p>  <p>President Obama must provide incentives for to buy healthcare insurance. Instead the law imposes penalties if consumers do not buy healthcare insurance. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=The+ideal+medical+savings+account&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">The ideal medical saving accounts provide consumers with the control of the first dollar coverage</a>. It encourages consumers to use their money wisely. What they do not spend they keep for retirement. If a consumer has a chronic disease and uses his money wisely he receives a bonus.</p>  <p>President Obama must change American’s eating habits using public service announcements. He must change the way the farm industry is subsidized. The obesity epidemic is devastating the healthcare system. </p>  <p>President Obama must deal with the expense of defensive medicine. The only way to decrease defensive medicine is through effective malpractice reform. </p>  <p>Forcing Americans to be dependent on big government does not work. It creates all sorts of unintended consequences. President Obama should encourage an environment of self-reliance, innovation and independence. </p>  <p>None of the important issues needed to have effect a positive impact on the healthcare system are addressed in President Obama’s healthcare reform bill.</p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/lymrqojdnrM" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/who-doesnt-get-it.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Fourteen States Sue Federal Government On Constitutionality Of The Healthcare Reform Law</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/tHCtColuhgk/fourteen-states-sue-federal-government-on-constitutionality-of-the-healthcare-reform-law.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/fourteen-states-sue-federal-government-on-constitutionality-of-the-healthcare-reform-law.html" thr:count="1" thr:updated="2010-04-19T09:09:23-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e201347fcca4d9970c</id>
        <published>2010-04-11T09:31:17-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-04-11T09:54:55-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACP Fourteen states are suing the U.S. Government in order to block the healthcare reform bill. The participating plaintiff states are Florida, South Carolina, Nebraska, Texas, Utah, Louisiana, Alabama, Michigan, Colorado, Pennsylvania, Washington State, Idaho, and South Dakota....</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><h3>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACP</h3>  <p>Fourteen states are suing the U.S. Government in order to block the healthcare reform bill. The participating plaintiff states are Florida, South Carolina, Nebraska, Texas, Utah, Louisiana, Alabama, Michigan, Colorado, Pennsylvania, Washington State, Idaho, and South Dakota.</p>  <p>Virginia has filed a separate lawsuit. It is anticipated that other states will join the lawsuit. </p>  <p><i>“State attorneys general wasted no time filing legal challenges to President Obama’s healthcare reform law, swinging into action with legal filings in Florida and Virginia within minutes of the White House signing ceremony on Tuesday.”</i></p>  <p>The state attorneys general charged that the new healthcare reform package exceeds Congress’ power to regulate commerce, violates 10th Amendment protection of state sovereignty and imposes an unconstitutional direct tax.</p>  <p><i>“This lawsuit should put the federal government on notice that Florida will not permit the constitutional rights of our citizens and the sovereignty of our state to be ignored or disregarded,”</i></p>  <p>President Obama’s administration has dismissed the lawsuits. Robert Gibbs said White House lawyers have advised them that the administration would win the lawsuits. Mr. Gibbs’ contention received more traditional media coverage than the reasons for the lawsuits. </p>  <p>A Democratic Party spokesman has turned the table on reality and said the lawsuits are a waste of state funds that will create large state deficits.</p>  <p><b>Who is paying for the federal government’s defense expenses?</b></p>  <p>Virginia filed a separate law suit in federal court in Richmond. The suit focuses on the mandate issue. A state law protects Virginia residents freedom to refuse unwanted health insurance. President Obama’s healthcare reform bill imposes penalties on anyone who avoids buying healthcare insurance.</p>  <p>“<em>It has never been held that the Commerce Clause [of the Constitution] … can be used to require citizens to buy goods and services,” the suit says. “To depart from that history to permit the national government to require the purchase of goods and services would deprive the Commerce Clause of any effective limits.”</em></p>  <p>The goal of the multi-state lawsuit is to move through the court system to the U.S. Supreme Court. The states are confident the U.S. Supreme court will declare the new healthcare law unconstitutional.</p>  <p><i>“The multi-state lawsuit maintains that new law infringes the liberty of individual state residents to choose for them whether to have health insurance. It also says the states themselves are victims of a federal power grab by leaders in Washington.”</i></p>  <p>During the writing of the U.S. Constitution, our founding fathers worked hard to preserve individual freedoms and states’ rights. The fear was that a federal system of government would attempt to control those rights and freedoms. These debates are beautifully outlined in <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Plain-Honest-Men-American-Constitution/dp/0812976843/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1271002788&amp;sr=1-1">Richard Deeman’s book”Plain Honest Men”</a> </p>  <p><a href="http://michaelconnelly.viviti.com/">Michael Connelly is a constitutional lawyer who explains the constitutional issues in President Obama’s healthcare reform bill.</a> His explanation of the issues are clearly stated on his blog.</p>  <p><i>“The entire bill is a blatant attempt to hide what is really going on when it comes to the Constitutional implications for individual Americans and the states that we live in.” </i></p>  <p><i>“Instead, this is a summary of the most important parts of the bill that will deal a severe and possibly fatal blow to the Constitution of the United States of America.” </i></p>  <p>Michael Connelly permitted me to print his first analysis of the unconstitutionality of the HR 3200. <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=trick+plays&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">President Obama, Harry Reid, and Nancy Pelosi used a number of tricks to get the bill passed by a partisan congress.</a> </p>  <p>Many of the tricks are unconstitutional. The methodology and results were not the intention of the founding fathers’.</p>  <p>It is essential that the American people understand the specifics of the constitutional issues. The Public should not accept the administrations sleight of hand comments about the lawsuits.</p>  <p>I salute the state governments who are taking a stand. I hope many other states will join the lawsuits. </p>  <p>I<a href="http://michaelconnelly.viviti.com/entries/general/the-nightmare-of-the-health-care-bill">t is important to present Michael Connelly’s comments as a source reference to the constitutional issues of President Obama’s healthcare reform law.</a> </p>  <p> </p>  <p><i /></p>  <p><i> “ I won’t even attempt to deal with all of the items covered in the bill because that would probably require a book.         </i></p>  <p><i>1. the passage of this bill far exceeds the powers granted to Congress under the provisions of Article 1, Section 8 of the Constitution which specifically states what Congress can do.</i></p>  <p><i>2. The bill grants powers to President Obama and the Executive Branch of government that are not authorized under the Constitution. </i></p>  <p><i>3. The new law requires every American, simply by virtue of the fact that they are alive, to purchase health insurance from private companies that will be heavily regulated by the Federal government. This is not authorized under the commerce clause of the Constitution and the Supreme Court has never rendered a decision saying that such power exists. </i></p>  <p><i>4. The legislation not only requires people to purchase health insurance, but establishes the terms and conditions that such insurance plans will have. In other words, Americans will be forced to enter into contracts for coverage that they may not want or need. </i></p>  <p><i>5. Failure to comply with the requirements to buy health insurance or even health insurance approved by the Federal Government will result in punitive action against American citizens. People will be fined for this failure although the bill calls it a tax. This is an effort to bypass the provisions of the 5<sup>th</sup> Amendment to the Constitution which provides protection against the taking of our property without “due process”. </i></p>  <p><i>6. This tax will be collected by the Internal Revenue Service that will have an additional 16,500 agents and auditors hired to enforce it. This opens the door for people who fail to pay the “tax” being subjected to criminal penalties. </i></p>  <p><i>7. In order to facilitate the actions by the IRS the Federal government will have real time access to the formerly private information of Americans including medical records and financial information. This is a violation of our right to privacy and the 4<sup>th</sup> Amendment protection against illegal searches and seizures.</i></p>  <p><i>8. The imposition of this so called “tax” also violates Article 1, Section 9 of the Constitution that limits the type of taxes that Congress can levy. </i></p>  <p><i>9. The bill also takes away from the states their historic right to regulate the health care industry, including health care insurance, within their own borders. Everything will now be regulated by the Federal government. This is a clear violation of the 10<sup>th</sup> Amendment to the Constitution. </i></p>  <p><i>10. In addition, the legislation will force State Governments to add millions of people to Medicaid, yet the Federal government will not be funding most of this. In other words, the bill will force the states to impose massive tax increases on their citizens in order to pay for this coverage. Congress has no authority to do this and it is another clear violation of the 10<sup>th</sup> Amendment. </i></p>  <p><i>11. The impact on senior citizens in the United States will be immediate and devastating and will entail a breach of contract between Americans and their own government. We are required to pay taxes for Medicare coverage and have a right to expect that they will have adequate health care coverage when we reach age 65. However, enormous cuts in the funding of Medicare under the provisions of the new law will deny us the coverage we have paid for and inevitably lead to the rationing of health care for senior citizens. </i></p>  <p><i>12. There are also numerous new taxes imposed under this law ranging from taxes on so called “Cadillac” policies that provide a high level of coverage, to taxes on medical devices, and even taxes on tanning booths. I consider all of these to be questionable under the powers granted to Congress in the Constitution. </i></p>  <p><i>            These are just some of the important Constitutional issues about this bill, yet there are other disturbing aspects that Americans need to consider.</i></p>  <p><i>For example, the bill does not prohibit Federal Funding of abortions and that is something many Americans want. Yet, the votes of some members of Congress who opposed this provision were purchased by the President’s promise to sign an Executive Order prohibiting such Federal funding. </i></p>  <p><i>In fact, he did sign such an order shortly after he signed the health care bill. This was a ruse. The President has no authority under the Constitution to issue an Executive order changing the provisions of a law passed by Congress that he has just signed. The Executive Order is meaningless. </i></p>  <p><i>            Finally, there is another section of the legislation that has nothing to do with health care. It is an authorization for the Federal Government to take complete control of the granting of student loans for our children to further their education.</i></p>  <p><i>If you are preparing to send your son or daughter to college you will no longer be able to go to your local bank to take out a student loan. Instead, federal bureaucrats will decide who gets student loans and under what terms and conditions. What will be owed to the Federal government besides the repayment of loans? Will some type of Federal service will be required and will your child have to attend a university approved by the Government. The potential implications are staggering.”</i></p>  <p>As the bill was unfolding the trick plays and unconstitutional aspects of the healthcare reform bill were obvious. Besides ignoring the constitution President Obama’s healthcare reform bill ignores the will of the people.</p>  <p> <a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/tHCtColuhgk" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/fourteen-states-sue-federal-government-on-constitutionality-of-the-healthcare-reform-law.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Impending Physician Shortage.</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/o0AIWe2pn3A/the-impending-physician-shortage.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/the-impending-physician-shortage.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e201347fb694de970c</id>
        <published>2010-04-07T10:48:30-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-04-07T10:48:30-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE Sixty three percent of physicians are unhappy with the implications of President Obama’s healthcare reform plan. The government has reduced reimbursements arbitrarily over the last decade. Physicians have had an underlying mistrust of government healthcare policy. Congress...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> </p>  <p><b>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</b></p>  <p><b /></p>  <p> </p>  <p>Sixty three percent of physicians are unhappy with the implications of President Obama’s healthcare reform plan. The government has reduced reimbursements arbitrarily over the last decade. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=mistrust&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">Physicians have had an underlying mistrust of government healthcare policy</a>. Congress and especially Pete Stark mistrust physicians. Pete Stark feels all physicians game the healthcare system.</p>  <p>I believe there is some abuse of the healthcare system by a small percentage of physicians. I also believe congress has a lack of understanding of medical practice expenses, the value of physicians’ intellectual property and skill sets. </p>  <p>In September 2009 an Investor Business Daily Survey was criticized for its findings in a physician opinion survey.</p>  <p><i><a href="http://www.investors.com/NewsAndAnalysis/Article.aspx?id=527698">“We were harshly criticized last September for an IBD/TIPP Poll that showed 45% of doctors would consider leaving medicine if a health care takeover passed.”</a></i><i> </i></p>  <p>The liberal media refused to believe the survey. It is a pity the media is so polarized. The liberal media is blind to information that could affect liberal healthcare policy adversely.</p>  <p><i>"IBD/TIPP Doctors Poll Is Not Trustworthy," ran the headline of one much-read piece on the FiveThirtyEight: Politics Done Right blog. </i></p>  <p><i>The Huffington Post attacked the very integrity of our poll: "Investor's Business Daily Publishes Ludicrous Poll Claiming 45% Of Doctors Would Quit Over Reform."</i></p>  <p>While the Democratic caucus in the Senate and the House were crafting the healthcare reform bill, no one asked practicing physicians how they felt about a government takeover of the healthcare system. The implementation of healthcare reform is dependent on physician support.</p>  <p>The government villainized the healthcare insurance industry. It is hard to tell who is the bigger villain the healthcare insurance industry or the government. </p>  <p>The government will hire the healthcare insurance industry to provide administrative services for the healthcare reform bill. </p>  <p>The healthcare insurance industry will continue to receive 65 cents of every healthcare dollar. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.investors.com/NewsAndAnalysis/Article.aspx?id=527698">The Medicus Firm, a physician search firm, conducted a survey published in the Investor's Business Journal, March 18, 2010.</a> </p>  <p><a href="http://www.themedicusfirm.com/pages/medicus-media-survey-reveals-impact-health-reform">For text:</a> </p>  <p><a href="http://www.themedicusfirm.com/pages/medicus-media-survey-reveals-impact-health-reform">http://www.themedicusfirm.com/pages/medicus-media-survey-reveals-impact-health-reform</a></p>  <p> </p>  <p><a href="http://www.themedicusfirm.com/pages/medicus-media-survey-reveals-impact-health-reform">The Medicus Firm survey was emailed to a random sample of 2,250 physicians from their physician database</a>. Of the 2,250 emailed, 1,195 responded. Of the 1,195 responses, 36.4% were primary care physicians (family practice, internal medicine, or pediatrics), and 63.6% were specialists.</p>  <p>This survey response was impressive. </p>  <ul>   <li>45% said they'd consider closing their practice or retiring early if the healthcare reform bill being considered was enacted. </li>    <li>65% said they opposed the government's attempts at taking over the health care system.</li>    <li>33% supported President Obama’s healthcare reform bill. </li> </ul>  <p><i>“Given that the White House and Congress both promised then -- as they do now -- to provide health care coverage for 31 million new patients while at the same time cutting costs from the $2.4 trillion a year we spend on medical care.”</i></p>  <p><i>“The poll reveals that doctors won't go along with it, says IBD:” </i></p>  <ul>   <li>If the sampling is valid of the 800,000 physicians practicing in the United States in 2006, as many as 360,000 might leave the profession. </li>    <li>President Obama will be trying to cover 31 million more patients with up to 45 percent fewer doctors.  </li> </ul>  <p><i>“Impossible.  It can't be done, says Investor Business Digest.” </i></p>  <p>· 29.2 percent of the 1,200 doctors said they would quit or retire early if a health reform bill was passed. </p>  <ul>   <li>That number jumped to 45.7 percent -- the same Investor Business Digest‘s original survey -- if a public option were included.  </li> </ul>  <p><em>"Many physicians feel that they cannot continue to practice if patient loads increase while pay decreases," wrote Kevin Perpetua, managing partner of the Medicus Firm, summing up his findings. </em></p>  <p><a href="http://www.investors.com/NewsAndAnalysis/Article.aspx?id=527698">“So for the record, we still stand by our findings said IBD. Our poll wasn't "ludicrous" or "untrustworthy." It was dead-on. And it's still relevant.”</a></p>  <p>It is interesting to look at some of the survey questions and answers. The questions were asked without or with a public option. </p>  <p>Only 24% of the physicians were in practice for more than 20 years.</p>  <p><b>Without a Public Option</b></p>  <p><b>Your Career Satisfaction:</b></p>  <ul>   <li>1.2%= improve Dramatically</li>    <li>13% = Improve Somewhat </li>    <li><i>40% = No Impact / Remain Same</i></li>    <li><b><i>33% = Decline/Worsen Somewhat</i></b></li>    <li><b><i>13.2% = Decline/Worsen Dramatically</i></b></li> </ul>  <p><b>With a Public Option</b></p>  <p><strong>Your Career Satisfaction:</strong></p>  <ul>   <li>5.5% = Improve Dramatically </li>    <li>16.5% = Improve Somewhat </li>    <li><i>14% = No Impact / Remain Same</i></li>    <li><b><i>25% = Decline/Worsen Somewhat</i></b></li>    <li><b><i>39% = Decline/Worsen Dramatically</i></b></li> </ul>  <p><b>Without a Public Option</b></p>  <p><strong>Physician Supply in General:</strong></p>  <ul>   <li>2% = Improve Dramatically </li>    <li>9% = Improve Somewhat </li>    <li><i>33% = No Impact/Remain the Same</i></li>    <li><b><i>42% = Decline/Worsen Somewhat</i></b></li>    <li><b><i>14% = Decline / Worsen Dramatically</i></b></li> </ul>  <p><b>With a Public Option</b></p>  <p><strong>Physician Supply in General:</strong></p>  <ul>   <li>3% = Improve Dramatically </li>    <li>11% = Improve Somewhat </li>    <li><i>14% = No Impact/Remain the Same</i></li>    <li><b><i>27% = Decline/Worsen Somewhat</i></b></li>    <li><b><i>45% = Decline / Worsen Dramatically</i></b></li> </ul>  <p><b>Without a Public Option</b></p>  <p><strong>Quality of Medical Care in General:</strong></p>  <ul>   <li>1% - Improve Dramatically </li>    <li>11% = Improve Somewhat </li>    <li><i>34% = No Impact/Remain Same</i></li>    <li><b><i>40% = Decline/Worsen Somewhat</i></b></li>    <li><b><i>14% = Decline/Worsen Dramatically</i></b></li> </ul>  <p><b>With a Public Option</b></p>  <p><strong>Quality of Medical Care in General:</strong></p>  <ul>   <li>9% - Improve Dramatically </li>    <li>17% = Improve Somewhat </li>    <li><i>6% = No Impact/Remain Same</i></li>    <li><b><i>30% = Decline/Worsen Somewhat</i></b></li>    <li><b><i>40% = Decline/Worsen Dramatically</i></b></li> </ul>  <p><strong>Which of the following best describes your overall opinion / support for health reform?</strong></p>  <ul>   <li>I support the current proposed legislation – 28.5% </li>    <li>I support the current proposed legislation minus the public option* – 5.0% </li>    <li><b><i>I support reform but would prefer a different, more incremental approach - 63.0%</i></b></li>    <li>I prefer the status quo – the healthcare system is fine the way it is – 3.6% </li> </ul>  <p><strong><i>*at the time of the survey, public option was still a possibility. </i></strong><strong>It still is by default.</strong><strong><i> </i></strong></p>  <p>President Obama ought to pay attention to physician opinion. If he doesn’t there are going to be severe shortages in physician manpower.</p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/o0AIWe2pn3A" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/the-impending-physician-shortage.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Unintended Consequence: The Law Suits Begin</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/87uRXfUcnlE/unintended-consequence-the-law-suits-begin.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/unintended-consequence-the-law-suits-begin.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e201347fa3427f970c</id>
        <published>2010-04-04T07:40:13-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-04-04T07:40:13-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE President Obama and the Democratic Party controlled congress have used multiple procedural tricks to pass a terrible healthcare reform bill. In the opinion of many constitutional lawyers they have passed legislations that are unconstitutional. The majority of...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/">
&lt;div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama and the Democratic Party controlled congress have used multiple procedural tricks to pass a terrible healthcare reform bill. In the opinion of many constitutional lawyers they have passed legislations that are unconstitutional.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The majority of the public has felt President Obama and the Democrats have ignored the will of the people. President Obama does not think so. He has stated Americans will decide in his favor in the November midterm elections. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama has been disingenuous and arrogant in his selling his healthcare reform bill. His attitude was made clear during his speech in Maine on April 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;. (Go to you tube below and start at 7.47 minutes). &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;div class="wlWriterEditableSmartContent" id="scid:5737277B-5D6D-4f48-ABFC-DD9C333F4C5D:d5b76d01-1c87-4a4f-adeb-2825f1817ab1" style="padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-left: 0px; float: none; padding-bottom: 0px; margin: 0px; padding-top: 0px"&gt;&lt;div id="9d6ef3f1-d890-431a-a373-49934a7493cf" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline;"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HSC9hJXR9Oo&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;rel=0" target="_new"&gt;&lt;img src="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83451876469e201347fa34276970c-pi" style="border-style: none" galleryimg="no" onload="var downlevelDiv = document.getElementById('9d6ef3f1-d890-431a-a373-49934a7493cf'); downlevelDiv.innerHTML = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;object width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;param name=\&amp;quot;movie\&amp;quot; value=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/HSC9hJXR9Oo&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/param&amp;gt;&amp;lt;embed src=\&amp;quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/HSC9hJXR9Oo&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;hl=en\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;application/x-shockwave-flash\&amp;quot; width=\&amp;quot;425\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;355\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/embed&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/object&amp;gt;&amp;lt;\/div&amp;gt;&amp;quot;;" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama’s goal is default to the public option. The public will have no other choice. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;amp;start_time=&amp;amp;p=g&amp;amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;amp;blog_platform=&amp;amp;view_id=&amp;amp;link_id=7386&amp;amp;flavor=&amp;amp;q=terrible+bill&amp;amp;x=0&amp;amp;y=0"&gt;The public option will socialize medicine,&lt;/a&gt; increase taxes, increase healthcare insurance premiums (subsidized by the government, ration care, decrease access to care, eliminate freedom of choice, decrease the quality of care and bankrupt the nation.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Federal deficit spending has increased to over 2 trillion dollars this past year. The federal deficit ceiling has been increased from $11 trillion to almost $14 trillion dollars. Despite all the deficit spending unemployment is almost 10% and not falling. The only new jobs are government jobs or government related jobs.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The legislative and executive branches of government have totally disregarded the will of the American people. The only option left for the public is to appeal to the judicial branch of government.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Legal action does not add value to the healthcare system. However, when people feel abused they take legal action. The winners are always the lawyers. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The losers will be the taxpayers. Taxpayers will be paying both the plaintiff and defendant fees to lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;There is no question the healthcare system is dysfunctional. President Obama’s healthcare reform bill will make the healthcare system worse. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I have demonstrated that the healthcare reform bill can only increase the deficit. The bill might appear to have the potential to reduce the deficit because of the disinformation the administration feeds to the traditional media. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;There has been much criticism of the AMA and its President because of the position they have taken to support the healthcare reform bill. The AMA is losing membership. Other physician organizations such as Sermo and the Association of American Physicians and Surgeons have an equal number of members&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.aapsonline.org/newsoftheday/00974"&gt;The Association of American Physicians and Surgeons (AAPS) became the first medical organization to sue the government to overturn the newly enacted health care bill, the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA).&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;AAPS v. Sebelius et al.&lt;/i&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“&lt;i&gt;If the PPACA goes unchallenged, then it spells the end of freedom in medicine as we know it,” observed Jane Orient, M.D., the Executive Director of AAPS. “Courts should not allow this massive intrusion into the practice of medicine and the rights of patients.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The law suit makes many compelling arguments. These arguments represent the vested interest of patients first. Physician leadership and input is required to educate the public and the courts. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ol&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;“There will be a dire shortage of physicians if the PPACA becomes effective and is not overturned by the courts.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;The PPACA requires most Americans to buy government-approved insurance starting in 2014, or face stiff penalties.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;This violates the Fifth Amendment protection against the government forcing one person to pay cash to another. AAPS is the first to assert this important constitutional claim.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Insurance company executives will be enriched by this requirement. Federal and State government will be forced to subsidize the unaffordable healthcare insurance premiums. Ultimately taxes will be increased. The result will be a slowing of the economic recovery.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ol start="start"&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;The PPACA also violates the Tenth Amendment, the Commerce Clause, and the provisions authorizing taxation. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Taxing and spending power are unconstitutional when payments go to private healthcare insurance companies. President Obama and Congress recognized that PPACA cannot be funded without the insurance mandates. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;5. The traditional sovereignty of the States over the practice of medicine is destroyed by the PPACA.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;6. AAPS asks the Court to enjoin the government from promulgating or enforcing insurance mandates.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;7. &lt;i&gt;AAPS asks HHS Secretary Kathleen Sebelius and Social Security Commissioner Michael Astrue to provide the Court with an accounting of Medicare and Social Security solvency.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;8. Court action is necessary “to preserve individual liberty” and “to prevent PPACA from bankrupting the United States generally and Medicare and Social Security specifically,” &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;AAPS contends Congress imposed assumptions on the Congressional Budget Office resulting in the PPACA reducing the budget deficit. These include assumptions leading to a $500 billion savings in Medicare. The savings was accomplished by moving the Doctor Fix out of the Healthcare Reform Bill budget. Moving the Doctor Fix out of the healthcare budget still increases the federal deficit. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;AAPS contends that Congress and President Obama know the opposite to be true. They know the CBO’s assumptions are unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.aapsonline.org/hhslawsuit"&gt;This law suit is the first of a long list of law suits to come.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The states are lining up to defend their state sovereignty and protect their state budgets.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;President Obama’s view is that everyone is playing into his hands. He has many legal tricks up his sleeves. The public is sick of his trick plays.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;A fear is the American public will get tired of the healthcare debate before it is too late to repeal. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The education of the public must continue.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="OLE_LINK1"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/87uRXfUcnlE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/04/unintended-consequence-the-law-suits-begin.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Unintended Consequences Are Rolling In</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~3/8a1aGNM12D0/unintended-consequences-are-rolling-in.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/03/unintended-consequences-are-rolling-in.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a00d83451876469e20133ec5b52fe970b</id>
        <published>2010-03-31T05:49:41-07:00</published>
        <updated>2010-03-31T05:55:17-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE Over the years congress has made many deals with the secondary stakeholders. The new rules were made to correct previous rules. They did not work and made the healthcare system worse. Americans are information junkies. Information is...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>stanleyfeldmdmace</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Medicine: Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Politicians,Healthcare and Vested Interests" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Abuse of the Healthcare System" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Stakeholder Mistrust" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p> </p>  <p><b>Stanley Feld M.D.,FACP,MACE</b></p>  <p> </p>  <p>Over the years congress has made many deals with the secondary stakeholders. The new rules were made to correct previous rules. They did not work and made the healthcare system worse. </p>  <p>Americans are information junkies. Information is important to decision making. The wrong information leads to making wrong decisions</p>  <p>The traditional media is usually fed the wrong information by vested interests. It, in turn, feeds the public a short version of the wrong information. The result is faulty decisions. </p>  <p>President Obama’s healthcare bill was finalized last Thursday. On Friday AT&amp;T and several other corporations took required tax write downs as a result of the bill’s passage</p>  <p><em>“</em><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704100604575146002445136066.html?mod=djemEditorialPage_h"><em>The returns for the healthcare reform bill are already rolling in</em></a><em>. AT&amp;T announced that it will be forced to make a $1 billion tax write down due solely to the health bill, in what has become a wave of such corporate losses.”</em></p>  <p>The tax write downs have been announced by Deere &amp; Co., $150 million; Caterpillar, $100 million; AK Steel, $31 million; 3M, $90 million; and Valero Energy, $20 million. </p>  <p>Other write downs have not been announced in the media. Corporations must declare the increase in healthcare related tax liabilities to the SEC immediately.</p>  <p>President Obama has used every tax trick in the book to make the new healthcare entitlement look affordable and deficit neutral. </p>  <p>An Increased tax liability to these corporations occurred when congress placed the new rule on top of the rule providing a tax subsidy.</p>  <p>The government provides a 28% subsidy to corporate America for continuing the drug benefit for their retirees as incentive to continue retirees’ drug coverage plans.</p>  <p>The twist of the tax law permitted these companies to deduct 100% of its drug benefit expense. In effect corporations were getting 28% free money while retaining the ability to deduct the 28% as an expense. </p>  <p>This is called double counting. It is difficult to follow the tax accounting. It represents a large tax benefit. The tax rule saved AT&amp;T $100 billion dollars a year. It also saved most corporations large amounts of money. The savings went directly to its bottom line. </p>  <p>With the passage of the healthcare reform bill, corporations will not be allowed to deduct the subsidy. </p>  <p><em>“Black-letter financial accounting rules require that corporations immediately restate their earnings to reflect the present value of their long-term health liabilities, including a higher tax burden. Should these companies have played chicken with the Securities and Exchange Commission to avoid this politically inconvenient reality?”</em></p>  <p>It appears Henry Waxman and other House Democrats were unaware of this unintended consequence. If they were, the healthcare reform bill is more sinister than it looks.</p>  <p><em>“ Mr .Waxman announced his committee will call for a hearing demanding these companies explain their action because their judgment <b>"appears to conflict with independent analyses, which show that the new law will expand coverage and bring down costs."</b></em></p>  <p>Media coverage and analysis of these write downs have been minimal. Why? </p>  <p>I do not think the media understands the consequences.</p>  <p>President Obama has said repeatedly, <em>“if you like your insurance you can keep it. If you like your doctor you can stay with him.”</em></p>  <p>Nancy Pelosi said; <em>“After the bill is passed we will understand it.”</em> </p>  <p><strong>You bet we will.</strong> </p>  <p>This rule will precipitate several consequences. Corporations have been trying to eliminate healthcare benefits for employees and retirees for years. </p>  <p>The new rule provides an excuse to drop the healthcare insurance benefits. The government will also eliminate the pretax benefit of private healthcare insurance. </p>  <p>If corporations eliminate the healthcare insurance benefit for employees, employees will be forced to buy individual insurance policies. The individual healthcare insurance plans will be unaffordable. </p>  <p>The government public option will be affordable because the government will subsidize the premiums. The healthcare insurance mandate will increase an entitlement burden to the states who presently have deficits. It means increased state taxes. </p>  <p>Corporations will be happy to pay the penalty for not insuring employees. The penalty is less than the insurance premium.</p>  <p>If a corporation chooses not to eliminate the healthcare benefit it will increase prices. The result is inflation. Corporations will also decrease its work force resulting in increased unemployment. </p>  <p>The public option as a sole source of healthcare insurance is only a matter of time. Then the government will fully control the healthcare system. </p>  <p>Regulations such as these will be President Obama’s back door approach to government control of the healthcare system. </p>  <p>However, <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304252704575155522246442654.html?mod=djemalertNEWS&amp;mg=com-wsj">President Obama overlooked the increase in unemployment and a decrease in people insured</a>. Few people would be able to keep their own doctor, individual insurance premiums will be unaffordable and the deficit will escalate. </p>  <p>A prominent physician, who understands all this, sent me a copy of a letter he wrote to the President of the AMA opposing the AMA’s position on President Obama’s healthcare reform bill. He said;</p>  <p><i>“Surely, you didn't arrive on a load of turnips yesterday.</i></p>  <p><i>Doc, the congress is the same wonderful group that gave us Medicare and Medicaid in the first place and then endlessly tinkered with it for nearly 50 years, and also gave us the SGF, and a host of other ill-considered acronyms that did our patients and the physicians (</i><em>not</em><i> the <u>providers</u>) of our country no good at all.” </i></p>  <p>He then wrote;</p>  <p><i>“It is a sad situation, not just for the docs but for their patients. </i></p>  <p><i>So, now what?  Until cast of characters in the congress, assorted criminals, tax dodgers, and others of ill repute, is changed, I am afraid we are all screwed.  That includes the patients, more is the pity. </i></p>  <p><i>My own suggestion is that the AMA seize the moral high ground and take on the role of being </i><em>the</em><i> advocate for the patient (</i><em>not</em><i> the <u>consumer</u></i><em>) </em><i>and view any effort to reform the reform  through the lens of what is best for <u>all</u> of our patients. </i></p>  <p><i>If the AMA were to do that, physicians would find that they will come out well, I am certain. While we are it, it would be a good thing to advocate for a reasonable and sane system of pricing so that what is done for people is simply costed at acquisition plus a reasonable margin of profit and the retail price is then the same for all patients.”  </i></p>  <p>This physician has said it all. Consumers owning their healthcare dollar and driving the healthcare system is the only way to accomplish affordable universal care with <a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;start_time=&amp;p=g&amp;blog_uri=http%3A%2F%2Fstanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com%2F&amp;blog_platform=&amp;view_id=&amp;link_id=7386&amp;flavor=&amp;q=ideal+medical+saving+accounts&amp;x=0&amp;y=0"><strong>the government subsidizing or paying for the uninsured with the ideal medical savings account.</strong></a>  It will be less costly and give consumer incentive to be responsible for their health and healthcare dollars. </p>  <p><a href="http://www.lijit.com/search?uri=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.lijit.com%2Fusers%2Fstanleyfeld&amp;type=blog&amp;q=trerrible+bill&amp;x=0&amp;y=0">Both physicians and patients must wake up and protest this folly</a> at the polls and to their congresspersons immediately during the Easter recess.</p>  <p><a name="OLE_LINK1"><i>The opinions expressed in the blog “Repairing The Healthcare System” are, mine and mine alone.</i></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RepairingTheHealthcareSystem/~4/8a1aGNM12D0" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://stanleyfeldmdmace.typepad.com/repairing_the_healthcare_/2010/03/unintended-consequences-are-rolling-in.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
 
</feed><!-- ph=1 --><!-- nhm:dynamic-ssi -->
